<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Escaping Sloth</title>
    <description>...very slowly</description>
    <link>http://escapingsloth.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://escapingsloth.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Tbilisi II - Visa-troubles and David Gareja</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The articles here are still almost a month behind my actual itinerary. Normally I would deal with the mounting feeling of guilt by taking a nap and then using the boost of energy to clean the kitchen or look up cat videos on Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the nap is out of the question: It’s impossible to find a sleeping position in which my lobstered skin doesn’t cause me to suffer dreams of hellfire, father-of-the-year King Stannis or the Vietnam war. Turns out, the colour of your skin can cause lots of problems. Who knew?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the absence of decent excuses I’m now sitting in the living room, not-sipping my not-coffee (because Ramadan). As its rich, smokey flavour not-fills my mouth, I’m thinking that I might as well get on with the writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Tbilisi I ended up spending little time on sightseeing, but rather more on socializing. My theory is that any person troubled by shyness or lack of friends should grab a bag, book a ticket and find themselves some nice hostels to stay in. Hostels are full of people with the strangest background and experiences! Most of them tend to actively look for other people to hang out with. That relative abundance of social interaction also puts any fears of blunders or awkwardness in perspective: So what, you’ll never see those people again - unless you want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, that’s what the choice between hotels and hostels comes down to: Would you rather talk to waiters and room service or other travelers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_001046.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_001046_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;airport-no&quot;&gt;Airport? No.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between the meals and nights out, I managed to clarify the situation regarding my visa for Iran. Clarify that I wasn’t going to get one, that is. My initial plan had been to fly into Teheran, spend two weeks roaming around Iran and then flying out to Bahrain. This actually sounded like a really good plan because of Iran’s Visa-on-arrival service, which allows citizens of some countries to just pick up a visa at the airport. Being lazy but cautious I decided to ask about that at the embass before booking my flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first attempt, I walked to the embassy (for about 90 minutes). Unfortunately, the place had closed down 10 minutes before I reached it. The opening hours listed on the website were out of date, apparently. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150526_123904.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150526_123904_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Vake Park, which I found along the way&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second attempt, I reached the embassy early and was admitted in, together with a couple from Poland. It was their second visit to the embassy, and the looks on their faces didn’t exactly inspire confidence. Sure enough, we were met by a almost-certainly-competent embassy official. I could elaborate on the specifics, but I fear that it might jeopardize my chances of getting a visa in the future. Suffice to say that he eloquently answered our initial question in one sentence: “… … … …airport? … … … no.” He really stuck to his guns and used the same sentence to answer all of our follow-up questions, too. 
Instead, he helpfully directed us towards a visa service agency, which would apply for a regular visa on our behalf, for around 200 USD. That would take around 2 weeks. For me, this meant I simply was not going to go to Iran: If I had to wait for two weeks to get a visa, I would only have around 5 days to spend in Iran before meeting my friend in Bahrain. 200 USD (visa) + ~200 USD (flight) / 5 days = 80 USD/day just to get into the country. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I had met other travelers (tourists!) who had gotten into Iran on those airport visas very recently, no problem. Plus, all Iranian government websites stated the Visa-on-Arrival was still an option. So technically, I could have just booked my ticket and hoped for the best. However, this meant running the risk of being rejected at the airport and then being forced to book a pricy flight out on the spot. I decided to trust the charming man from the embassy and leave my Iran visit for another journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;david-gareja&quot;&gt;David Gareja&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that sorted, I decided to explore the Tbilisi area some more. Luckily, I had met some interesting people at the hostel before (Hi, Rene!) and we decided to do a day-trip to the David Gareja monastery right on the Georgian-Azerbaijani border. The orthodox monastery was founded in the 6th century and consists of dozens of chapels, caves and buildings. Today, the area is the object of a border dispute between Georgia and Azerbaijan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We picked a tour operator near Liberty Square and were directed to a waiting car. It must have been a slow day, because it was only the two of us, an Italian guy and an Austrian lady, and the driver. He would drive us to the monastery, we would complete a short hike there and then be driven back. Luckily, our driver was very accommodating of our tourist-y desire to take pictures of…everything and stopped frequently along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_122615.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_122615_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Endless landscapes&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_125258.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_125258_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Endless sheep&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monastery itself turned out to be a fairly low-key affair: It is still operating (monks are still monking) and thus much of it is off-limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_132417.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_132417_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Caves dug into the side of Mount Gareja&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_132625.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_132625_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The chapel&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_133331.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_133331_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Inside the chapel&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the monastery behind, we started our hike up the cliff towards the Azerbaijani border. The temperature must have hovered around 35°C and the path was baked solid by the sun. The path was also quite steep, so after a short while we were all sweat-soaked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_135138.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_135138_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Rene and Marco figuring out the route from an A4 map provided by our driver&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Is that humming in your head the sign of an oncoming headache? You haven’t drunk enough water, clearly. And no aspirin on you. Yep, definitely a headache. One of those pulsing ones. Ka-CHOCK….Ka-CHOCK. Awesome.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few hundred meters of steep ascent we reached the top of the ridge. There, sitting on a huge rock, we found two Azerbaijani soldiers on watch, who called us in on their radio. Interestingly enough, they did not check our passports or require any documents. And thus we sat foot into Azerbaijan. The view from up there was stunning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_141130.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_141130_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The north of Azerbaijan actually looks...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_141250.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_141250_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;...a lot like the south of Georgia&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then followed a footpath along the ridge and found several small caves with wallpaintings and inscriptions. All of these were outlying parts of the monastery and still used as places of worship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_142018.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_142018_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Caves along the south slope of Mount Gareja&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_142106.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_142106_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Another cave&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_142528.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_142528_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;And another cave&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we made our way up to the peak of the ridge, where we checked back in with two Georgian soldiers sitting in the shade of a chapel there. We ended up spending half an hour just admiring the landscape and trying to snap a few good shots of the enormous birds of prey that circled around us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_145448.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_145448_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_145910.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_145910_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A bird!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, we climbed down the other side of the ridge, back towards the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_151705.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_151705_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Down the north slope of Mount Gareja&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back, we had a lunch-stop in the town of Udabno. As these things go, the only restaurant there was operated by our driver’s parents. Their entire community had been relocated to this area after their hometown in Svaneti had been devastated by a rockslide. The Soviets had begun building a completely new town for them, when the USSR collapsed and the money ran out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_160822.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_160822_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Udabno&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick lunch there, we all slept through the entire drive back to Tbilisi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1300 words! On a sunday, no less! Next time: Another episode of “Wanna come?” - “Sure, why not?” with mountains, sheep and chacha - nectar of the gods and terror of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/06/tbilisi_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/06/tbilisi_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tbilisi I - Arrival and doing not much</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, yes: the writing. The writing which I promised to do regularly. &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; writing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the above three sentences in an agonizing fifteen minutes, I got up and fetched myself a cup of coffee. Then I groaned to myself a little and pulled my own hair for a bit. But now I’m good. Excited to continue the tale!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left off - I remember distantly - when I took a coach from Batumi to Tbilisi. Metro, the coach company I had used so frequently in Turkey, offered a comfortable 5-hour trip to Tbilisi. Being the lazy sort I had a relaxed breakfast in Batumi first, and then got on the coach in the early afternoon. We drove up north along the coast for about two hours before turning east and driving into the country, towards the capital. I’ll spare you the details, but here is the summary: Georgia is beautiful. Really, really beautiful. That’s about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the outskirts of Tbilisi in the late afternoon. Remember what I wrote about Batumi looking pleasantly post-apocalyptic? The outer districts of Tbilisi looked worse. Within half an hour we went from “Oh, pretty hills!” to “Oh, a rat!” to “Oh, a guy…barbecueing a rat”. This surprised me, since I had heard very positive things about Tbilisi in general. Luckily, my concerns were unfounded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got off the coach near the city centre and found myself standing in the middle of a neat-looking high street (Rustaveli Avenue), which also leads to the parliament and the Georgian National Museum.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_195121.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_195121_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;On Rustaveli Avenue&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived, the entire road was blocked for traffic, as they were preparing for a parade: People were in the process of erecting stages and assembling stands. Bands were practicing and every available space was covered in billboards and posters. Despite the commotion I managed to find a cafe with wifi and find myself a suitable hostel. Then I shouldered my way back through the crowd and towards the southern part of town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_195532.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_195532_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Liberty Square, at the southern end of Rustaveli Avenue&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There, right at the foot of a massive hill and under the remains of Narikala Fortress I found the excellent Envoy Hostel. On top of all other amenities, it had a fantastic roof terrace!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_201831.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_201831_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View from the hostel roof terrace&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dark, I ventured down the hill and found myself something to eat. Next, I followed a bridge into a park on the other side of the river, and spent some time reading there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_203552.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_203552_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The park. That subtle, understated building in the background? The presidential palace.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, I called it an early night and headed back across the river and to bed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_214627.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_214627_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Shiny bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I heard from the hostel staff that I had actually managed to arrive just in time for Georgian independence day (May 26th). Curious, I headed out towards liberty square and had a look at the little military parade organized there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150526_112531.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150526_112531_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150526_112644.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150526_112644_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the whole affair wasn’t as action-packed as I had hoped, I decided to ignore the festivities and get coffee instead. That’s pretty much what I did on my second day in Tbilisi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150527_164627.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150527_164627_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Came up to me, looked at me, sat down on me.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite honestly, I didn’t feel like hardcore sight-seeing when I was in Tbilisi. So I just enjoyed wandering around town and having a look at various districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150528_105524.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150528_105524_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View of Narikala Fortress from the foot of the hill&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my hostel was very close to the fortress, I took a detour up there (using the cable car of course…what am I, a farmer?). While the fortress consisted of nothing more than its walls, I enjoyed climbing up to the parapet and taking in the view of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150528_112215.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150528_112215_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View of the castle from the northern side.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150528_113221.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150528_113221_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View down into town. That brownish thing is a river, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would end up staying in the Tbilisi area for around 5-6 days before heading north with a few new-found friends. All in all, I found the city pretty, but not overly exotic. For my personal productivity that was excellent news, but not necessarily the material for riveting stories. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phew, that’s a whole lot of writing right there! A good day’s work! I’ll take a break now. Next time, I’ll explain why I didn’t end up going to Iran and tell you how we crossed into Azerbaijan without passports!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/05/tbilisi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/05/tbilisi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Batumi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The third country of my trip was Georgia. I crossed the border at Sarpi and took a minibus from there to Batumi. The whole ride lasted about half an hour and cost me a single Lari (about 0.40 Euro). As we drove up the coast, I enjoyed the view of the empty beaches and the hilly countryside. Much of the scenery reminded me of a slightly more summer-y Poland. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun broke through the morning haze eventually and the streets become more and more lively as we reached Batumi. The city is a famous holiday destination and especially popular with tourists from Poland and the Ukraine. As we drove into the city centre, I noticed the fairly typical shape tourism has given Batumi: The outskirts looked pleasantly post-apocalyptic, the way former soviet-territories do. Rusty cars, about-to-collapse buildings and entire neighbourhoods which looked like they were held together only by duct tape and stubborn optimism. Or at least a shared confidence that things were not likely to get &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; worse in the immediate future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as we neared the city’s port, the influence of tourist money became very visible: Newer buildings, well-maintained facades and roads, lots of hotels and restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150523_085951.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150523_085951_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The port&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got off the bus there and grabbed an early coffee at a cafe on the promenade. There, I also tried my first Adjarian Khachapuri. This entire country seems to survive on various kinds of Khachapuri (cheesy dough baked goods). Case in point: Beggars will approach you repeating “Khachapuri, Khachapuri”. The Adjarian is baked dough in an open boat shape and has a raw egg on top of the feta-like cheese. Yes, most dishes here are very hearty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_103128.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_103128_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Main square&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I found myself a decent hostel (for 6 EUR/night) and took a nap which lasted for most of the day. My afternoon exploration was cut short by the onset of torrential rain, so I stayed in. In the evening, another hostel-guest from Poland and I went out to grab dinner, before calling it an early night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_104842.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_104842_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The obligatory seaside shot&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning the rain had stopped and I took a long walk around town and along the promenade. Since tourist season here does not start before July, most places were very empty and I struggled to find a place for breakfast. While I got increasingly frustrated at people telling me they didn’t serve coffee, I really appreciated the fact that most people seemed to speak English willingly. It’s nice to be denied in english!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the promenade you get plenty of hotels and casinos, many of them either new or still in the process of construction. And then you get this thing, which apparently belongs to the university: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_142143.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_142143_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Yeah, that building in the distance has a built-in ferris wheel. Does yours not have that?&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, circling back to the harbor, I came across this fine example of sturdy Cold War engineering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_142451.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_142451_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A semi-submersible...semi-submersed.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Batumi is marked by these strong contrasts: In front of the hotels and casinos you find plenty of Bentleys and Ferraris, other parts of town are just casually rotting to pieces. Besides this absurdity, Batumi did not really hold much of interest. To me, it seemed like a typical tourist town - at that point, minus the tourists - who would come there to swim, drink, eat and gamble. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_193649.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_193649_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The old part of town&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_194249.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_194249_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Another square and a fountain with lots of boobs&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, I decided that I was going to leave Batumi the next day. I ended up going out for dinner with my Polish aquaintance and enjoying a relaxing beer on the promenade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_202456.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_202456_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;I really need to stop posting these...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I got up nice and early and walked to the coach station on the other side of town. There, I got on a coach to Tlbl…Tblbl…the capital.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/02/batumi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/02/batumi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>35 litres of stuff</title>
        <description>&lt;div align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;color:gray&quot;&gt;
  &quot;Oh, is that it?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
  -- She &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several times other travelers asked me where the rest of my stuff is. Many are surprised to find out that I only carry one medium-sized backpack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantages of traveling light have been analyzed in excrutiating detail on a great number of travel sites and forums. Let me save you the time and present the key principle of traveling light: &lt;strong&gt;Things are heavy and you don’t need most of them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most backpackers look like they are moving house for a year. I blame two faulty lines of thought:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) If you travel for longer, you need more everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) Foreign countries do not have shops, ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these hobo-hoarders go out and get themselves a nice 90-litre hiking pack. What goes well with that? Oh yeah, a second, smaller pack they can carry on their chest! That’s useful because it allows them to strap their sleeping bags on there, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, it must be nice to have everything you could possibly need with you. On the other hand, I don’t want to go &lt;em&gt;beep!-beep!-beep!&lt;/em&gt; while awkwardly reversing off a train because all that gear is too bulky for me to turn around. I have carried heavy equipment for extended periods, and I’m not a fan. The prospect of doing that for an entire year is incredibly off-putting to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided against it. After all, I was going to stay in civilization (or whatever passes for it) for most of the time. I knew I would be able to buy additional things as needed. This also meant that I would leave typical hiking-gear, like a hiking boots, tent and sleeping bag. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I understand that travelers of the female persuasion tend to carry more stuff. The social consensus seems to be that the whole smelly-but-somehow-handsome-in-a-rugged-way look is male-only. Lucky me!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would just bring the basics then. When I inspected my gear before leaving Samsun, I took this picture:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150522_112422.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150522_112422_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One pair of shorts, one pair of jeans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel towel and travel blanket&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swimming trunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First-aid kit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laptop and charger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Powerbank (thank you, Alex and Clément!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notebook (thank you, Sisi, Sofia and Martin!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sunglasses (the label says “Ray Bon”)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flashlight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Windbreaker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sweatshirt (wool)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sunscreen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 T-shirts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Belt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 pairs of woolen socks (two pairs hand-knitted by my mom!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Washbag&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 Boxers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assorted cables and adapters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vacuum compression bags (Eagle Creek)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Backpack (Assault pack II)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, of course, the clothes I was wearing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vacuum bags are incredibly useful: They are heavy-duty ziplock-bags with one-way valves on the lower end. You stick your clothes in there and then roll the bag to press out all the air. This way, my clothes shrink to less than half their volume. In addition, the bags keep them dry and protect them from that typical bag-smell. I’m absolutely amazed by these bags and I could kick myself for not getting them earlier. This compactness obviously doesn’t do anything about the weight, so my backpack is a bit heavier then it looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150522_113213.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150522_113213_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;All my clothes put into those two vacuum bags&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is all that stuff packed up nicy and tidy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150522_115332.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150522_115332_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s it: A moving household stuffed into a 35-litre backpack!
If I’m completely honest, even this bag could stand to lose a few items. I might still eliminate one or two t-shirts and the pair of jeans and replace the swimming trunks with a less bulky pair. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/29/traveling-light/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/29/traveling-light/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Samsun</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Outside, in the alley the rain is pouring down hard. Big, heavy drops drum on the pavement and glisten in the yellow light of the street lamps. For most of the afternoon the city smelled of hot dust and ozone.  At sunset the thunderstorm finally broke and I got back to the pension drenched. Now I’m sitting in the small lobby, sunk deep into the worn sofa-cushions. I sit by myself, surrounded by pillows, throws, thick carpets and a huge bookshelf. On top of the shelf, barely visible in the dim glow of the glass lamps, the owner has arranged decorative plates and glasses, and a few family photographs, too. Next to it, the wooden counter is dwarfed by the photographs and flags on the wall behind it. In the half-dark I can’t make out where the old clock is, but its solemn ticking fills the room. When I concentrate on the moments between its ticks, the place feels as if time itself has stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clock’s rythm contrasts with the continous pitter-patter outside, intermingled with the occasional distant rumbling of thunder. I hadn’t really noticed any of that until a few minutes ago, when I put down John Le Carré’s ‘Tinker, Taylor, Soldier, Spy’. Mentally coming back from Cold War espionage to the present, I also realized that the pension’s owner must have gotten up from his paperwork at the counter to attend to one of the rooms upstairs. There isn’t much to do though, since I am the only guest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No doubt that’s part of the reason why I am still in Samsun: The pension is neat and very quiet. The owner is a stately-looking man in his early 50s who uses the phrase “no problem!” almost exclusively and brings me coffee without me asking. That, too, is part of why I’m still in Samsun, a city in which there is nothing to do. A city which I intensely disliked when I arrived here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t slept much on the night bus from Göreme (I’m sure I mentioned that). When I arrived at Samsun coach station at 04:00h, I barely knew where I was. My mouth felt like a hamster had slept on my tongue. The station was devoid of people but I managed to find the metro lounge, which had a TV tuned to a sports channel. So I saw some of the run-up fights to Mayweather vs. Pacquiao.  I also noticed that somebody on the bus must have nicked the cookies I had kept in a plastic bag under my seat. Whoever you are, cookie-thief, I hope those chocolate chips bring you joy, and not diabetes. Just before the big fight started, a shuttle appeared out of the thick fog outside and took us the city centre. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I saw of the city looked dire as hell in the fog and under a light drizzle. I got off at the city centre and wandered around in search of caffeine, wifi and processed carbohydrates for almost an hour. It would only occur to me a few days later that I had arrived on a sunday morning, at 06:00h. This would have explained nicely why nothing was open and there were no people around at all. As it was, I felt very much betrayed by the universe. Finally I managed to find a bakery with wifi (yay!), puff pastries (yay!) and tea (…). From there, I looked up this one pension and then crossed the road to a Metro coach ticket office, on the off-chance that there was a way out of this hellhole on the same day. Since there wasn’t (probably - my Turkish isn’t so good), I marched off in the other direction and found the pension. The room I was offered was a double, for a price which made haggling feel pointless. I lugged my bag up to the fourth floor and collapsed on the bed. Outside, the sun rose behind hazy clouds, stores were opened and cars started. Windows were flung open, tea was brewed. Inside, I drifted off and slept the sleep of the all-but-dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150504_191404.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150504_191404_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The promenade&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150505_142038.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150505_142038_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Fried egg on top of my beef-bacon pizza/pide? Don&#39;t mind if I do!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have been in Samsun for two weeks now, I will spare you all the details. The main points are these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After staying in so many places for relatively short periods (2-5 days), I wanted to take a break and stay somewhere for a bit longer. While hopping from town to town is great fun, it’s also a flood of new impressions which need to be processed at some point. I simply did not want to be one of those travelers who live by their itineraries. The kind that gets off a bus somewhere with glazed-over eyes and trembling hands. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, my other stays had been at hostels. That had turned out great in terms of the people I met and I’m actually amazed how easily groups formed between people from very different backgrounds. Yet, after I while I felt like I needed a break from people. Some time to shut up and think (or precisely not think). This was made all the more pressing, as I kept remembering all the things I had set out to do on this trip: Study, write, read, program. So far, I had done preciously little of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past two weeks, I started doing some of what I had planned, and Samsun turned out to be just the right place for it: Population of 1 million, but not too crowded. Affordable, yet modern. No major attractions meant: no major distractions. In Samsun I didn’t feel the least bit guilty about spending entire afternoons and evenings in cafes, just reading or writing. I knew I wasn’t missing out on anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150504_191736.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150504_191736_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Samsun&#39;s port&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I did things. I read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Joe Haldeman, The Forever War (I loved this one.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Terry Pratchett, The Nightwatch (Deeply philosophical satire, one of his best!)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;John Le Carré, Tinker, Tailor, Soldier, Spy (enjoyable)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kurt Vonnegut, Slaughterhouse 5 (not sure)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Orson Scott Card, Ender’s Game (not convinced)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also finally managed to commit Kipling’s “The Palace” to memory, though I struggled for ages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually I would read in the mornings and at night, and program in the afternoons. That way, I got some Python exercises out of the way and completed a script which manages the photographs included in these articles (more on that later). I also found out how shockingly simple it is to write a script to generate and guess Finnish Social Security Numbers. I started working on some simple pattern recognition for data analysis in Python. I hope to continue that in the coming weeks. Finally, I set up a virtualized Arch Linux system, which is a great thing to do if you ever need a system which feels like it’s been made of broken household appliances. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150506_130454.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150506_130454_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Not quite sure what this is...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between the reading and the programming, I spent an unreasonable amount of money on coffee and don’t regret a thing. For breaks, I took plenty of long walks along the promenade and exercised fairly regularly. All in all, the past two weeks have felt refreshingly productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150509_170844.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150509_170844_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As enjoyable as my stay here has been, I’m beginning to feel restless. Luckily, a coach ticket to Batumi, Georgia (No, not that one. The other one.) is only ~20 EUR. I’ll leave at 23:00h and reach at 07:00h. Hooray for overnight coaches!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/19/samsun/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/19/samsun/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cappadocia, part III - Hiking and climbing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brace for a storm of landscape shots!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-valley&quot;&gt;The valley&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, Marc and I met Michal (from Poland) over breakfast. The three of us decided to go for a casual morning hike in one of the valleys (Kiliclar vadisi). The weather was gorgeous and the three of us picked a route which followed almost none of the suggested paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_103945.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_103945_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_104428.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_104428_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started out by walking past (and through) some of the deserted rock houses. Having inspected them in detail, we then walked up to one of the large ridges lining the valley:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_104710.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_104710_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_104714.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_104714_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_110803.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_110803_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the ridge, we climbed down into one of the smaller valleys, and for once followed a path for a while. Next, we tried to scale one of the opposite ridges, which took us over an hour. The white rock you see in the pictures is tufa, which is soft and porous at the best of times. Often enough, the rock itself was covered by layers of sand and dust, which looked just like the rockface itself. As we found out, it was utterly unsuited for even light climbing. So many times when we though we had finally found a decent route out of the valley, we had to track back after feeling our hands slip in the layers of white dust. On the plus-side, we ran into this magnificent little dinosaur!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_114608.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_114608_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Foreground: Turtle, Background: Marc and Michal&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several failed attempts, we finally found a way up on the rock, where we looked magnificent against the backdrop of the valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_115659.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_115659_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed over on the other side of the ridge and were suddenly looking down into the main valley. The fairy chimneys visible in the second picture are the same ones, Marc, Mohamed and I saw during our first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_122122.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_122122_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_122739.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_122739_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way down into the valley the three of us almost fell into a 6-8m deep chasm. No big deal though. Also, it turned out that there was a perfectly safe crossing just a few meters to the side. We just hadn’t seen it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_123554.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_123554_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the fairy chimneys have a very characteristic shape. I will leave it to you to figure out what exactly the two gentlemen were doing here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_124612.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_124612_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_124452.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_124452_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_124008.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_124008_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Just something to dispell those rumors that I&#39;m making up these stories while playing video games in my mother&#39;s basement&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-castle&quot;&gt;The castle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having seen the valley, we headed back to town in time for lunch. Marc and I were both scheduled to leave Göreme in the evening, but that would leave us the afternoon to do some more exploring. We decided on taking a minibus up to the castle which loomed over Pidgeon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_144623.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_144623_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_144837.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_144837_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The castle itself turned out to be a bit of a let-down: From outside, it looked like a bee-hive and I was excited to see what remnamts of its occupation could be found inside. The answer: None. There was nothing there but a path up to the top. The view from up there compensated us though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_144918.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_144918_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_151118.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_151118_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_151356.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_151356_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking back down, we decided that we wanted to see the valley we had been looking down on. That was clearly one of the best decisions of my trip so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153009.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153009_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153439.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153439_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One entire side of the valley was lined with rocky peaks, one giant line of them which started with the castle hill itself. All along the steep rockface was a maze of houses, windows, half-eroded stairwells and scary-looking ledges. &lt;strong&gt;It. Was. Awesome.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153523.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153523_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153528.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153528_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153533.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153533_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three of us set out to explore, climbing higher and higher into the rocks. We even managed to climb into several of the empty rock-houses and have a look around inside. It is difficult to convey in writing, but the whole thing felt like a giant playground and I’m not ashamed to admit I felt like a kid. Including the confident risk affinity of somebody who has no understanding of even basic mechanics but very elastic bones…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a whale of a time in those ruins. Nothing was off-limits, nothing was roped off. We were free to climb everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153852.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153852_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_162044.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_162044_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_162153.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_162153_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we found a way out of the valley. As we couldn’t find a bus back, we hitchhiked the short distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_163230.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_163230_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in Göreme, I said my goodbyes to Marc and Michal and got on my coach to Samsun. Yes, the one I had complained about previously, that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sidenote:&lt;/strong&gt; If you go to Turkey, try to make time for Cappadocia. Just like Pammukale, it’s a unique landscape and certainly worth seeing. Next time I go there, I will definitely do one of those balloon tours which are largely accident free, but were booked out for the days we were there. I would also bring a proper camera to take some nicer pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/06/goreme_iii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/06/goreme_iii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cappadocia, part II - More pretty places</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Once more, I’m sitting in a cafe, this time in Samsun. The coffee is decent, but the wifi is not. I haven’t yet managed to outsource my writing to Vietnamese contractors, either. I guess I will have to continue the tale myself. Cappadocia, let’s see…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;selime-monastery&quot;&gt;Selime Monastery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next stop on our Cappadocia-tour was to be Selime monastery. When he wasn’t hitting on that poor Chinese girl, our tour guide did actually tell us a thing or two about the monastery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_112201.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_112201_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_113828.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_113828_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently George Lucas considered those spiky rocks in the distance as a set for Star Wars: A New Hope.  Unfortunately, he couldn’t get the permits to film in Turkey, so he had all that stuff rebuilt in North Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the pictures, the whole complex was not built on, but rather &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; the rock. The caves and tunnels had first been a caravanserai, a pre-modern motel for traders and travelers. Later it had been turned into a monastery by christian-orthodox monks. Wall-carvings and inscriptions can still be seen around the various rooms. After the monks left the place, it was used as a crow’s nest for the town and served, at various points, as garrison to armed units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_114139.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_114139_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the centuries after that, it had seen use as a giant fridge (the villagers kept their foodstuffs there) and as a hobo-haunt. The latter had - with enviable pragmatism and lofty disregard for the dusty past - all but destroyed countless wall paintings. Can’t have a rat BBQ without a smoky fire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_114512.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_114512_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Inside the chapel&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After listening dutifully, we were given about 20 minutes to explore the monastery on our own. Despite the annoyingly tight timeframe, we had lots of fun. It turns out that people here don’t really close off any parts of old ruins or monuments. This leads some people *cough* to climb through every small tunnel and jump from ledge to ledge like Prince-of-Persia reborn. The three of us really did enjoy this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_114531.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_114531_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Wallpaintings of early saints (very little hobo-damage)&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, before we knew it our time was up and we had to get back to the bus. This is one of the reasons I usually don’t like to take tours. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ihlara-valley&quot;&gt;Ihlara Valley&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch at some basic tourist restaurant, we drove a short while to Ihlara Valley. Here we would do a ‘hike’, all of 4km! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_131711.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_131711_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_133700.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_133700_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The valley used to be home to several hundred people, who lived in caves in the steep cliffs on either side of the valley. As we arrived there, our tourguide looked fairly annoyed at the sheer number of visitors. The valley itself turned out to be teeming with tourists, too. We ended up marching down into the valley and then along the river, swept along by a stream of tourists. This, again, was unfortunate: They valley was a pretty place: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_135115.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_135115_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_141118.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_141118_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_141902.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_141902_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we exited the valley at the other end and got back on the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;derinkuyu-underground-city&quot;&gt;Derinkuyu Underground City&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last real sight on this tour was Derinkuyu underground city. The entire area around Göreme is riddled with caves and tunnels. Partially, this is the result of geology, partially that of history. Göreme and neighbouring villages were home to early christian groups. For a long time, the roman emperor was not a fan. In order the escape religious persecution, the locals started digging emergency shelters. In their heyday, these would offer shelter to around 80,000 for a duration of up to three weeks. Of these underground cities, we visited the largest one, Derinkuyu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_153536.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_153536_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;One of the wider staircases&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The caves reach down 7 floors (around 60m) consisting of numerous caves, tunnes and staircases. As of 2015, only about 5% of the underground city are open to the public, the remaining bits are closed off for safety reasons (or maybe they are still hiding christians in there?). It is estimated that Derinkuyu could have sheltered around 20,000 people. The caves are acccessed via increasingly narrow and low staircases. Sooner or later the hunched-over posture leads to a headache, as we found out. Limbo’ing every other staircase helps and looks hilarious, too. The rooms themselves are a lot more spacious and have designated functions: Living rooms, nurseries, schools, a church and so forth. They even had underground stables, to protect their lifestock from all that religious persecution. While food stores would only have been sufficient for around 3 weeks, the city had several wells, dug down to 80m below ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_160602.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_160602_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many places the defensive nature of the caves was clearly visible: The narrow tunnels would have been easy to defend and many of them had massive disks of stone, which could be rolled to block the tunnels. If I was a legionnaire, I would prefer not to fight underground like that. Luckily, I wouldn’t have to: Hooray for flint, steel and resinous wood!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though most rooms do have eletric lighting, the entire affair is somewhat dark. This makes exploring the tunnels a lot more exciting but didn’t really do much for the value of my pictures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underground city is an impressive sight and well worth the entrance fee. However, it’s clearly not the place for people who are either claustrophobic, obese or both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After around an hour we forced our way past other tourist groups and back up to the surface. We hopped back on the bus and did one more photo shot from the other side of pidgeon valley:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_173238.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_173238_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Pidgeon Valley&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150501_173506.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150501_173506_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;More Pidgeon Valley&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a last step we stopped at a jewellery store to hear a ‘presentation’ on local minerals - you know the kind. Having stepped through the store, Marc, Mohamed and I waited for the others outside, before driving back into town. We spent the evening chilling at a restaurant/bar, before walking Mohamed to the coach station. He was taking a night bus back to Istanbul and we bid him goodbye before calling it an early night.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/04/goreme_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/04/goreme_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cappadocia, part I - Invisible cities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tired, so incredibly tired. I’m writing this on a a coach which has just left Göreme and is speeding steadily towards Samsun. I spent a day hiking and exploring Cappadocia, but now I’m exhausted. The tray table is loose and rattles. In the front of a bus, a child of maybe 3 years keeps himself occupied by straight-up screaming without interruption. Might as well use the time for writing then, although the coach is expected to reach at 03:00h and that means that every minute of sleep is valuable. I certainly hope you lot appreciate my sacrifice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oh-hills&quot;&gt;Oh, hills!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left off in Ankara, where Marc and Mohamed had convinced me to forego my plan to drive to Samsun and instead travel to Cappadocia with them (by asking “Are you coming?”). So we rose nice and early, took a metro to the huge coach station and got tickets and food. Since we had such a huge safety margin in our timetable, nobody thought of looking at the clock. We effectively jumped on the coach at the very last moment. Well, the very last moment before the official departure time. The time I foolishly thought the bus would depart. The time around 15 minutes before it actually did. German time vs. Turkish time, this has been an issue a few times already…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sidenote:&lt;/strong&gt; Kids are great, aren’t they? So full of life, so much energy! Kids are our &lt;em&gt;future&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The busride from Ankara to Göreme took around four hours and I spent most of the time just staring at the fields, hills and valleys outside the window. The countryside around Ankara seems incredibly devoid of people. Much of it looks like steppe and goes on and on until it meets the wide open skies at the horizon. I would have loved to get off the bus for a moment and just stand in that seemingly endless field. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking around on the bus, most passengers were too enthralled by “Scarface” (shown in Turkish) to notice. The coach was quiet, except for an elderly gentleman whose cough made me think of a sore-throated vulture in distress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halfway through the journey we had a break at a reststop near the massive salt lake Tuz. This is where the following, highly symbolic photograph was taken by an unknown artist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_125203.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_125203_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, yes, it was me. It symbolizes the salty lake-ness in which we sit. Allegorically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_125209.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_125209_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we continued onwards (again, around 15 minutes late), I was left wondering: Isn’t Cappadocia known for it’s cliffs and hills and such? The landscape all around me looked mostly flat. Somewhat hilly at best. It would stay that way until we arrived in Nevşehir, where we changed buses. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way into the city we passed a huge industrial area (empty) and loads of of apartment complexes (also empty). Not a single damn person. Why is everywhere I go empty? Where did all the people go, and why? Did they know I was on my way? Are they scared?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was on that second bus that we finally got to see some cliffs and rock formations, as it hurled down the empty highway at breathtaking speed. And then we passed a bend and suddenly a valley opened up befor us. This was the “OOOOHHH!” moment we had been waiting for: In the brilliant sunshine we saw formations of pale white rock sticking out of green meadows. To me, they looked like molten icecreme - I was hungry. Everywhere I turned, bizarre formations and stony columns pointed towards the sky, surrounded by blossoming trees and bushes. The passengers on the bus went whisper-quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus left us in the centre of the small town of Göreme. The name apparently means “you can’t see me”, since the village is tucked away in a valley and is hard to see from the surrounding hills. We found our hostel fairly quickly and headed out to explore. And boy, did we find places!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disregarding the suggestions of our host, we just picked a random direction and then followed the first incline up  towards the rocky ridges surrounding the town. On the way there we stopped amazed by the stone columns which stood all over the city. Each of them was higher than the houses around it, and all of them showed various entrances, windows, pidgeonholes and staircases cut from the rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_160952.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_160952_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_165859.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_165859_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_161218.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_161218_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we climbed up on the nearest ridge, we stood frozen for a while, just amazed by the view:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_162204.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_162204_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_162822.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_162822_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So-called ‘fairy chimneys’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look closely, you can see a small bird on top of one of the columns. It made a fantastically ridiculous “Whoop-whoop!” sound. I want one of those birds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_164139.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_164139_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, we decided to take a shortcut back into town. This largely meant sliding down steep rocksides, some of which were clearly the ‘roofs’ of cave hotels and apartments. We had a lot of fun and nobody died, so it was worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_165457.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_165457_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick dinner we walked up to the so-called sunset point, a cafe nestled on top of a cliff overlooking Göreme. The place was fairly crowded with tourists, but the view was something to behold. The three of us sat on the cliff edge and watched the sun slowly drop towards one of the table mountains around the city. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_191314.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_191314_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_192905.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_192905_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the sun disappeard, we remained there for a long time. The city below us turned dark and one by one, lights appeared in the darkness. Brightly lit billboards, streetlights and lights behind windows all over the city. A flock of sparrows swooped this way and that over our heads, feeding on the insects of the valley. One by one, the tourists left the sunset spot. As night fell, our seats on the cliff got colder and colder, until we decided to head back. After another quick meal, we walked back to the hostel and turned in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150430_200853.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_200853_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;roadtrip&quot;&gt;Roadtrip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we walked over to a local travel agency to go on a tour of some sights. We had discussed this move before, since we would have preferred to move about independently. However, Cappadocia is a relatively large area and sparsely populated, so public transport would not be ideal. Rentals turned out to be a lot more expensive than anticipated (did somebody say rip-off?). The tour included a guide, several sights and the obligatory meal. Summing up the prices for the individual tickets and adding transportation, we figured the tour might be the cheapest way to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sidenote:&lt;/strong&gt; The kid has started imitating a police siren with impressive endurance. Not kidding, it’s actually going “BEEEEE-BOOOOOO-BEEEEEEE-BOOOOOO”. 6 minutes and counting. His parents don’t seem overly suprised. Kids are, after all, our &lt;em&gt;future&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we found ourself on a minibus with a Turkish guide from the region, some Aussies, some Kiwis, some Chinese and the three of us. The guide assigned all of us Turkish names. While Muhamad got to stick with his name, Marc and I became Ahmed and Mehmed, since we apparently looked like twins. In the manner of tour guides everywhere, ours also began flirting with one of the Chinese girls, who was not impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sidenote:&lt;/strong&gt; Aaaand now that little ~~shit~~ bundle of delight is crying. Again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the previous day had been warm and sunny, it began drizzling as soon as our bus pulled out of Göreme. Once we reached our first stop, a panorama view over a nearby valley, the light drizzle had turned into heavy - and very cold - rain. So we each took that one photo, said something to the tune of “Yeup, it’s pretty alright.” and then jogged through the downpour back to the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way to the next step, Selime Monastery, our guide explained some historical background of the area, both in terms of its history and its geology. With regards to the latter, he was able to explain the formation of those ‘fairy chimneys’: Cappadocia’s top layers consist of very dense, heavy and dark basalt rock with a layer of spongy, brittle and white tufa underneath. Wind, extreme temperature changes (-25°C in winter, +40°C in summer), rain and melting snow erode the two layers. First, they dig away at the basalt on top, leaving those characteristic conical shapes. Then they start chipping away the softer stone below. However, by then the weight of the basalt on top will have compressed the softer stone underneath. Thus, it will not erode right under the basalt cones but only around them. Over time, this leaves those characteristic formations which look like…well, like chimneys, alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_123602.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_123602_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, the local people dug into them and built houses inside. Smoke rising from cooking fires throught openings at the top supposedly led travelers to believe that they were occupied by fairies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is getting late. The kid is finally asleep or passed-out or whatever. Since this article is way too wordy already, I’ll grab some shuteye now and report on the rest of our tour in a seperate post.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/01/goreme/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/01/goreme/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ankara, the Concrete Capital</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-way-in&quot;&gt;The way in&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach ride from Safranbolü to Ankara took me about three, four hours. We drove southwest towards Bolu and then southeast towards our destination. The journey took us through some beautiful mountains and plains, parts of which stil held small patches of snow. So much for my plans to travel through warm countries only…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I noticed during the drive were many small villages along the highway. Most of them looked…poor. Small cabins and sheds nailed together from driftwood and tarp. People dressed in patched, stained clothes toiling away on acres the size of tennis courts with handheld tools. Even in the small cities we passed, most houses were in various states of disrepair and trash was strewn everywhere. Trash also seamed every single meter of road, even in the otherwise most untouched places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But aboard the coach I had wifi and coffee, so that was good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view changed quickly as we approached Ankara: First, there were industrial buildings. Next came massive warehouses, then your assorted megastores and car dealerships. Before long, I saw the city. Ankara is somewhat larger than Izmir and it looks very different. Since the development of Ankara as the capital took place within the last 90 years, the city appears incredibly modern. More modern in fact than any city in, say, Germany. Wherever I looked, I saw shiny, new towers of glass and steel, and more were being built all over the city. Just to give an impression of the developments going on there: When the Republic of Turkey was founded in 1923, its new capital had about 35,000 residents. In 1950, it still had less than 300,000 residents. Today it has 5 million. And it didn’t look like they were going to run out of money or hunger for growth anytime soon. The contrast between this and the countryside I’d just passed through could not have been more striking. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach took us past several parks and military installations before reaching the coach station. Again, the coach company provided a handy - and free! - shuttle service to the city centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shuttle itself was easy enough to find: I walked up to the tourist information and grabbed a map. The attendant pointed me towards a carpark full of shuttles. Waving the map energetically, I walked up to a group of teenagers outside and quickly learned which shuttle I needed to get on. This was done by pointing at spots on the map, grunting and waving my hands about. Works like a charm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 0089:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;English. By and large, they don’t speak it here. They teach it as a mandatory class in school, which apparently does a sterling job of turning people off of ever learning the basics. Outside the tourist-y places, speaking English didn’t get me very far. Pointing and grunting did. Generally, the young are more likely to understand English than the old. Those of the female persuasion often seem to speak better English than those of male, but are also more hesitant about starting to speak it. While this whole thing is a bit inconvenient at times, it’s not really a hindrance. At first I got a bit frustrated when they would just keep talking at me in Turkish, even though I very clearly did not understand them…then it occured to me that I was doing the exact same thing in English. Anyway, before you come, download the offline language pack for Google Translate and you’ll be golden.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I hadn’t planned on coming to Ankara, I had neglected to look up a hostel. So I grabbed a quick meal and found myself a nice cafe with wifi. After finding a hostel and reading for a bit, I walked over the hostel, got a bed and stashed my belongings. Then I went out to explore the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;underrated&quot;&gt;Underrated!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The late afternoon found me walking north through the city center and up into the neighbourhood of the university. Past a concert hall advertising its rendition of ‘Carmen’ and through a nice little park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150427_191437.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150427_191437_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150427_191346.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150427_191346_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150427_191637.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150427_191637_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150427_191921.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150427_191921_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150427_191422.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150427_191422_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it me or does that fountain look like a cat on a bicycle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I made the acquaintance of an Australian hostel guest (Hi, Marc!), and through him I also met a Yemeni pilot  (Hi, Mohamed!) who was actually living in Turkey. Together we did some more meandering in the city. For example, we visited Kocatepe Mosque, the biggest mosque in Ankara. Marc and I were a bit surprised to learn that the mosque actually had a shopping centre in its basement. Yeup, didn’t see that coming. Despite this somewhat strange property arrangement, the mosque itself is beautiful: Serene on the outside, ornate and lofty on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150428_134359.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150428_134359_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt;The mosque in question. It’s big.&amp;lt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150428_134752.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150428_134752_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also big on the inside, and rather pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed the evening in a bar which had beer and nargile. You know, that pipe-thingy with the hose-thingies, which people think won’t kill them because the water miraculously filters out all the cancer…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-castle&quot;&gt;A castle!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we decided to go climb up to Ankara’s castle. The castle is well-positioned on a hill overlooking much of the city and actually so old nobody has dated its construction with any certainty. When the Galatians turned up around 300 BCE, they found the castle and started using it for themselves. So there is that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150429_155102.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150429_155102_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does everything have to be either an incline or stairs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The castle is also located in a part of town which a friend of mine (Hallo, Holger!) called “historical” and which I would call “shitty”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150429_155603.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150429_155603_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150429_161738.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150429_161738_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up in the castle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150429_162742.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150429_162742_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View down from the castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the castle there wasn’t a whole lot to do, besides take in the view or have coffee in a cafe tucked away in the corner. After a while we got bored and headed back down into town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-way-out&quot;&gt;The way out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening, Mohamed was due to go back to Istanbul, while Marc would leave for Pammukale the next morning. I myself was planning on taking a bus to Amasya or Samsun the next morning as well. I split for a few hours to do sort out some documents for my tax return in a cafe(the dreamy life of the traveler: “Glistening beaches. Dusty winding roads. Smiling locals. Tax deduction with original receipts only.”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I got back, I asked whether the two of them had managed to get their coach tickets. They had. Kinda. More on that in the next article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A word on Ankara:&lt;/strong&gt; Many people, both locals and foreigners, seem to dislike the capital. Unlike Istanbul Ankara has few truly ancient ruins or monuments. Instead, its history is the history of the Republic (coincidence, do you think?), which is fairly recent. Not much older than the house I grew up in, in fact. So there is that. Unlike so many other places in Turkey, the landscape is not spectacular. It doesn’t even have beaches. People  bemoan the lack of nightlife and entertainment. This seems plausible as a large share of the population are administrators and bureaucrats, whose notion of a. exciting evening out means filing taxes in a cafe. Yes, I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all those factors aside, Ankara seems to be a city that works. It’s organized. It’s clean. It has all the trappings of progress and civilization. It is clearly a place where people go to get stuff done. And even in this terribly functional city you find really nice spots - just look at the pictures! So if you find yourself in the area, give it a try! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/30/ankara/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/30/ankara/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Safranbolü</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not convinced this stop on my journey really deserves an article of its own. Largely, because I felt like I wasted two days of my life there. Then again, I’m sitting in a hotel room right now and I don’t have more pressing things to do. It’s one of those days where you might stuff your face with a load of chicken nuggets and then wash that down with a beer or two while watching an entire season of 30 Rock. Oh wait, that’s exactly what I just did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here is how it came to be:
I got bored in Istanbul and decided to head further eastwards. Some research on wikivoyage.org (the open-source successor of wikitravel, which apparently is a commerical platform now) brought up a few options along Turkey’s Black Sea coast. One of them was a village called Safranbolü, around 6 hours from Istanbul. The direction was right and apparently the town is UNESCO World Heritage because they have original Ottoman houses (and Turkey’s 4th biggest cave!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place also looked pretty on Google Image search, so I packed my bag in the late afternoon. Then I headed to the coach station (Otogar Baglanti Yolu) in the western part of Istanbul. I bought a ticket and spent two hours waiting in a departure lounge. Long waiting times have been pretty common for me. Making the best of delays is a valuable skill on a trip like this. Then again, I’m not in a rush, which helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That waiting-skill became useful during the trip as well, since the first 90 minutes were spent in Istanbul rush-hour traffic. Had I been smarter, I would have taken the tram to one of the &lt;em&gt;eastern&lt;/em&gt; coach stations and saved myself some of the slowest stop-and-go I have ever seen. On the plus side, taking a tour through the Asian side of Istanbul was impressive: Everything is built up, and yet they keep building more skyscapers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we exited the city, darkness fell quickly so I won’t be able to provide a description of the landscape. My guess would be gently swooping hills though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our journey we passed the city of Izmit (not to be confused with Izmir), of which I only saw a huge raffinery, lit up like a christmas tree and belching out burning gas from several chimneys (I really hope that was by design…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next five hours on the bus listening to music and napping. In the end, we arrived around 01:00h at night. I grabbed a shuttle bus to town (which didn’t look terribly interesting) and then a short cab ride to the old town (which looked interesting enough). Initially I had considered saving the cab fare and walking instead. That would have been an unfortunate choice, since the distance turned out a lot longer than anticipated. Mostly, because half of the drive took us down a spiraling path into the centre of a dark, pit-like valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The owner of an inn showed me to my room in one of the original Ottoman houses. A building built with lots of wood and carpets. Almost every surface was carpeted, which made the place feel very cozy. After a quick tour of the facilities, I went to bed and slept like a stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning I asked my host to show me the shower. He revealed quite an interesting setup: You know those squatting toilets? Hole-in-the-ground model? The ones we just don’t &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; in The West? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150426_181246.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_181246_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This picture was actually taken at a restaurant, but you get the idea)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the shower was this, plus a shower head. A small room of 1.5 x 1.5m, the showerhead, the hole-in-the-ground and no window. After overcoming my initial confusion, I managed to take a shower of sorts and also flooded the entire room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I understand that the UNESCO award probably discourages architectural innovations in Safranbolü. Fair enough. Yet I have seen the same setup in several newer buildings since. That just leads me to ask: WHY? Is it some sentimental attachment to the oh-so-quaint past? Mindless conservatism in sanitary engineering? We moved past this! Past the hole-in-the-ground, past flooding the entire bathroom by taking a shower. We moved past it, because it was rubbish. Get with the program, Turkey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I went out to take a look at the city and get breakfast. The town was…old. That much was clear. The good parts around the centre were old and nice. Two- and three-storey houses built from dark wood and whitewashed stone walls. Some restaurants and many stores. Safranbolü was, in its day, an important trading post, where Saffron was grown and traded. Consequently, everything you can buy there is Saffron-this or Saffron-that. You name it, somebody found a way of putting Saffron in it. I will give them credit for Saffron-flavoured Turkish Delight though, that stuff is delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150426_104251.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_104251_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150426_193605.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_193605_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the less-good parts of town were old and crap. Decrepit, dilapidated buildings. Broken windows, wonky doors. Rusting carcasses of cars left on the roadside, from where they would never move again on their own (I hope). Garbage strewn about the neighbourhood. I quickly made my way through this area and out into the countryside surrounding the village. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the sun broke through the cloud cover, I began to enjoy myself. My walk led me to a tall fence at the foot of a hill. A gate in the fence stood open. I followed the path to a sign advertising a cafe, and then onwards from there. Suddenly I noticed that the ground to the left of the path dropped away into nothingness. Confused, I walked over and found myself looking down into a deep gorge, with water running along the bottom. The further I followed the gorge, the deeper and wider it became, until I saw the very cafe I was looking for nestled deep down in the canyon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150426_105733.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_105733_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150426_105808.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_105808_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150426_105758.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_105758_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s how I ended up having breakfast in a canyon! After taking a look around the gorge, I strode back into town and did some shopping. Later that day I walked up to one of the hills surrounding the old town and had a look at the historical clocktower there. No pictures, you know what that means. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was going to get dark soon, I opted to forego a visit to Turkey’s 4th largest cave. Instead, I chose to take a look around some of the historic homes in town. To my disappointment, they looked almost exactly like the inn I was staying at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning I slept in. It didn’t help that the room I was staying in had no window, so I couldn’t get out of bed until 10:00h. Still somewhat drowsy I grabbed all my belongings and squeezed them into my backpack. Then I sat on it until I the zippers on the compartments would close. I shambled to the old town centre and got on a minibus to the coach station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had decided to try my luck in Amasya next, a scenic little town on a river. Unfortunately, there were only two coaches on that route on any given day (“Amasya? No. No. Morning Amasya, no. Evening Amasya, yes.”). I had missed the first coach by around an hour and wasn’t too keen to wait until the evening for the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The friendly attendant suggested I could also take a coach to Ankara, the much-maligned capital, and then continue from there. That coach was about to leave in ten minutes though. So I looked back and forth between the map and the idling coach standing in the parking lot. In the end, I said “Yeah, why not?”, shouldered my bag and got on the bus. And you won’t believe what happened next!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there, I just wrote around 1300 words on a city I didn’t want to bring up in the first place. Amazing, what you can accomplish with boredom and beer!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/29/safranbolu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/29/safranbolu/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
