<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Escaping Sloth</title>
    <description>...very slowly</description>
    <link>http://escapingsloth.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://escapingsloth.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Athens</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;at-least-its-warmwait-no-its-not&quot;&gt;At least it’s warm…wait, no, it’s not&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left Trikala soaking wet but excited to finally see Athens. At the coach station I bid farewell to my Canadian travel companion and stepped aboard the coach for a well-deserved nap. The road to Athens was sneaking up over hills and mountain passes. The view from up there, I have to assume, must be stunning on a clear day. Alas, all I saw was grey: The same fog that had shrouded Meteora was now hanging over the mountain roads. Just as well, at least I didn’t miss anything once I went - you guessed it - to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roughly halfway through the 5-hour drive I was woken by the bus driver turning up the radio. I’m sure the lyrics of Greek pop music are deep and meaningful and all that. And those music videos with very tan men and women looking all serious and longing while being surprisingly underdressed? Rich in symbolism and artistic depth! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invigorated by the catchy tunes I was able to observe the vistas along the North Euboean Gulf:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150325_162449.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also observed an oncoming column of battle tanks, transported on heavy trucks. It’s a pity I didn’t manage to snap a good picture, because tanks are decidedly awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, my enjoyment of Greek pop music was cut short: Since I had booked an AirBnB apartment in the northern part of Athens, the bus driver agreed to let me out close to that Area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good news: Short walk to the apartment. Bad news: Turns out I had screwed up my booking, as I learned from the following text exchange: “Alright, I’m in front of the apartment.” - “You arrive tomorrow, no?” - “Yes. Yes, I will see you tomorrow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This left me without a roof over my head, standing in a part of the city which a realtor might describe as “quirky, multicultural and lively”. I managed to find a cafe with wifi (and with a lot of coming and going in the backrooms). From there I booked a hostel. Apparently you can get passable hostels for 8 euro per night. Anything cheaper than that, you’ll have to provide your own cockroaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the evening walking around Patisia. The evening was rainy, but marked by that special tranquility and peace that only lots of police in full-on riot gear bring about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I moved into the AirBnB apartment, all 18sqm of it. It was…economical. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 003:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;My impression is that AirBnB in Greece just isn’t worth it. The main argument for AirBnB would be the privacy of having a flat to yourself. That’s not what you get under 20 euros per night though. Instead, you’ll have a sofa in somebody’s living room. So if you’re going to share the space with others anyway, hostels provide a much cheaper and more flexible option.
My favorites so far have been Little Big House (Thessaloniki) and Quinta (Athens), both of which charge around 15 euro per night. Small, friendly hostels. On a totally unrelated note, both of them offer free, unlimited coffee. Free. Unlimited. Coffee.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next 3-4 days exploring the area and taking in the many facets of this colourful district. As far as I’m concerned it should be burned, and the scorched earth then salted generously, but that’s just me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired to seek out other parts of the city, I also ventured into the city centre (a 15-minute walk) and had a look at Syntagma square and some of the more touristy areas. Mostly though I stayed indoors to escape the frequent rain. I got a lot of reading done, but there was no denying that I felt a bit cheated. Come on, Greece, get your act together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finally-lobstered&quot;&gt;Finally lobstered&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once my booking ran out, I checked out and hiked over to the aforementioned Hotel Quinta. ‘Twas a crisp, sunny morning and I found the place in a district much closer to the city centre. Located just 5 minutes walking distance from the foot of Lycavitus Hill, the entire neighbourhood is full of small, student-y cafes and bars. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the somewhat dreary AirBnB the hostel was an amazing surprise: I wandered around a lovingly graffiti-d block twice before I found the entrance in an alley. After ringing the doorbell I was led into a beautiful house with sky-high ceilings and decorations that were so ornate that they almost felt a bit ironic. Just to give you an impression:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150330_133713.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The lobby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150331_110800.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The upstairs hallway:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_161457.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
And the hostel dog (a million dog-years old and clinging to her furry life)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed here for a week. During the first day, I went for a long walk in the city centre with another German guy I met at the hostel. Wandering around the ruins of the Ancient Agora and the Roman Agora we enjoyed the view of the Acropolis hill and the remnamts of the Parthenon up top. This decidedly touristy area is full of enterprising young businessmen (or annoying, shit-peddling cutthroats, depending on just how badly you want that guaranteed-to-be-original Rolex for 20 quid).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150330_144715.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150330_145422.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Wooden dicks, because reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150330_163743.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Library near the university&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, I got up early and climbed up Lycavitus Hill. The hill is the highest point in the city and located smack in the middle of it. Having read about the view from up there, I grabbed a cup of coffee and started climbing the steep, steep roads up to the foot of the hill. From there, a circling path winds around the hill and through a light forest. I took a short break on one of the lower peaks to enjoy the view:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150331_101544.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After catching my breath, I continued upwards to the highest point of the hill, which is - of course - adorned by a cafe. I passed through the cafe, empty at that hour, and reached the peak which is marked by a chapel and a huge Greek flag. The view from up there was stunning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150331_103629.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I met up with my Canadian co-traveller and we went to see Acropolis Hill and the amazing ruins of the Parthenon. Standing there is every bit as impressive as the pictures would lead you to believe. That’s why I’ll refer you to Google Image Search once again, they have better quality shots. But here, have a picture of my sunburn instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150402_091313.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, maybe one or two pictures of the Acropolis, if you insist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150401_123618.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150401_130133.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150401_124335.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I was properly burned. What would a trip be without 2nd-degree burns? Fun fact: Sunscreen is a shameless racket in this country. 150ml of SPF 50 set me back 14 euros in Athens. On the islands, I would later see bottles of 200ml for 24 euros. So if any of you are interested in import/export, you should consider shipping sunscreen here. The margins would be worth it, I’m sure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next 2-3 days exploring the city centre and catching up on my reading. This included the Acropolis Museum and the National Archeological Museum. Both museums are definitely worth seeing. The Acropolis Museum holds most of the findings from Acropolis Hill (the parts not stolen by Brits at least…) so many of the objects on display are statues and fresks from the Parthenon or the Erechtheion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_133216.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_132903.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one section displayed a little-known fact about most antique ruins and statues: They were brightly painted! While we like to imagine ancient Greeks striding through cities of white marble, the truth of the matter is that most buildings - especially religious ones - were  decorated with paint, mostly made with mineral pigments which did not survive until today. The same goes for statues, which had painted clothes and skin. The Acropolis Museum had several examples of what these statues may have looked like and the effect is quite different from the serene-looking white images we tend to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_184623.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Mycenean acropolis is conspicuous for its mighty Cyclopean walls that led Homer to name it “well-walled” in the Illiad.” That doesn’t sound like a ringing endorsement, it sounds like old Homer’s version of “the walls were alright.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Archeological Museum was vast, but at the time of our visit, almost completely deserted. It held exhibitions of Cycladic art and jewellery (including Agamemnon’s Death Mask, though archeologists seem to think that it might not have been his bling after all), Egyptian…stuff (I confess I skipped that one, so I don’t know what exactly was on display there), the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antikythera_mechanism&quot;&gt;Antikythera mechanism&lt;/a&gt; and truckloads of statues from various epochs of Greek art. Some of my favourites included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_191645.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The effect of Emperor Octavian’s empty eyes staring down on you is quite startling…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_192244.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_190358.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_193653.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Yes, I laughed :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-out&quot;&gt;Going out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason I like to stay in hostels (or to avoid them like the plaque, depending on the mood I’m in) is the social aspect: You meet people so goddamn easily. The words “Hi” and “Any plans for tonight?” are usually enough to suddenly be surrounded by people. Of course I had read about this before, but I was sceptical of all those tall tales. Nope, turns out, it’s all true. Not that surprising, really, when you think about it: Lots of young people, no local friends, all looking for company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when a friendly guy from Spain told me he was meeting a friend who lived in Athens and asked me to join him, my answer was a resounding “No, thank you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight I’m quite glad I changed my mind to “Eh, why not?” quite quickly, because I eventually found myself bar-hopping with a crowd of 10-12 travellers and locals, wandering all over the centre of Athens. The evening as a lot of fun, especially talking to the local guys and girls. Overall, three aspects of the experience stood out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, drinks in Athens are not cheap. 5-6 euros for a beer seems fairly normal. Maybe that’s the reason you don’t see many truly drunk people. It’s just too expensive to get drunk. (Some might argue that being half-drunk is a waste of money, of course…) The entire experience is very relaxed. No aggression, no tension, just people having a few drinks with friends. Beautiful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, Athenians dress up properly before going out. Properly-properly. We didn’t, though. I dare say we stood out a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, a group that large will have an amazing mix of cultures and languages (“I’m from Morocco, sorry, I don’t speak English…”) but some things are the same everywhere (“…but I’ve worked for Daimler in Stuttgart for 4 years, so we can speak German if you like!”). Back at the hostel we counted that between us 6 alone, we spoke 15 different languages. Globalisation may have its ugly sides, but meeting people from all over the world is definitely not one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leaving-athens&quot;&gt;Leaving Athens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I met up with my friend Holger, who had come to Greece for a few days. After some relaxed sightseeing, we prepared to take a ferry to the islands and see Milos and Santorini!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/05/athens/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/05/athens/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meteora (according to my GPS at least)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After starting my journey in Thessaloniki, I went to see the famous monastries at Meteora. And by “see” I mean “not see”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arriving&quot;&gt;Arriving&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to escape the horrid weather in Thessaloniki by hopping on a coach to Trikala, the largest city in the vincinity of Meteora. Thus I squeezed myself on a bus to the coach station in the far west of the city, and managed to sit down between two middle-aged local ladies who spent most of the drive screaming at each other, not at all bothered by me sitting right in the midst of it all. At the coach station I bought a surprisingly cheap ticket (18 euros) and boarded a modern bus for the ~4-hour journey to Trikala.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to the drive, I remember three parts:
Firstly, the part where many of the cities along the way had a flair of closed-down theme parks. Empty office buildings and shops, deserted houses and a state of general disrepair. I have been told this is due to the timing, it being off-season and all, but I’m not sure I believe that explanation: Much of the forlorn atmosphere seemed to be more structural than seasonal. Many facettes of neglect looked way too long-running to be explained by simple seasonality. That’s not a theme park waiting for visitors, that’s one where the clown’s run off and the bear sold its bicycle for liquor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the part where I inevitably fell asleep. Something about the warmth and the rocking movement makes it impossible for me to stay awake on a bus - any mode of transport, really. So I slept for a solid two hours in what I must assume was the typical “head back &amp;amp; mouth wide open” position. Travel in style!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, the part where I saw beautiful regions of northern Greece. Mountains, cliffs, winding roads and wide, open fields and lots of springtime greenery. The bus zipped along a smooth highway with sloping hills on both sides. After a few hours of that, the sun began to set. Touched by the evening sun, the entire landscape began to look every bit as green and warm as I had expected Greece to be. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;germanic-invasion&quot;&gt;Germanic invasion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good thing though that it began to rain as soon as we reached Trikala. I managed to catch a minibus to the city centre and I also managed to get absolutely soaked on the 500m walk to my hostel. I grabbed another guest who had arrived on the same bus as me (a Canadian…ha, for once not a German!) and we got Dinner. As we got back, two new guys had arrived in our room. Germans, go figure. I remember turning to the Canadian guy and saying something along the lines of “don’t worry, we won’t be speaking German all the time…” He expressed his gratitude in fluent German. Turns out he was binational, raised speaking both languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the four of us hadn’ gotten along so well, I probably would have been a bit annoyed by now. Sure, there are 81 million of us, but…come on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;good-times-bad-times&quot;&gt;Good times, bad times&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning the four of us shuffled to the bus stop and got our tickets to ~~Karam~~ ~~Kalam~~(Meh, I’ll look this up later) where…it was raining. On top of the rain there was also a hint of fog.  Consequently, we decided to share a cab to the main monastry up on the highest hill around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand my feelings about this excursion, you have to understand my reason for being in Meteora in the first place: People recommended it to me, describing the views there using words such as “stunning”, “amazing” and “mesmerizing”. A quick Google search confirmed that: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=meteora&amp;amp;es_sm=91&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=7tIoVdH5K8PUas6kgbgL&amp;amp;ved=0CAcQ_AUoAQ&amp;amp;biw=1280&amp;amp;bih=702#tbm=isch&amp;amp;q=meteora+monasteries&amp;amp;revid=934822189&quot;&gt;Google Image search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I on the other hand would desribe the view as “what?”
I didn’t see shit. The fog we had noticed at the foot of the mountain was a joke compared to the thick, nebulous wall encircling the world at the peak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, behold the magnificence that is impenetrable fog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150324_110307.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The plaza in front of the biggest monastry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150324_110828.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The entrance of said monastry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undaunted, the four of us walked down the road through the mountains, back to Karambaka (sic? Just google it!). Along the way we visited the second-largest monastry, which seemed to be under construction at the time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150324_114542.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The view down from the tower&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazed, we entered the main sanctum of the monastry, a set of small rooms holding reliquies, with every inch of wall filled with intricate carvings and every inch of roof covered in paintings. As we stood there, awestruck by the opulence and the significance, a monks’ choir began to fill the air with a solemn hymn. That turned out to be played through speakers from a nearby boombox, but a good attempt nonetheless!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way out, we passed through a gift shop larger than the monastry itself with all kinds of Meteora-themed crap and - behold! - a pink crucifix nightlight!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the weather, we were in a rather cheerful mood, taking the overall situation with a large dose of gallows humour. Below a certain altitude, the fog cleared and even the rain died down to a drizzle. This allowed for some interesting shots of the unique rock formations in the landscape below. The positive atmosphere coupled with the rather gloomy-looking landscape led to some weirdly contrastful pictures (think Hound of Baskerville, but cheerful):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150324_125542.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
20 miles to Mordor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150324_122845.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Wet but happy enough, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down in town we just so managed to catch the next bus back to Trikala. The walk from the place we ate lunch at back to hostel became a race: We were all cold and wet and we knew very well that there was only one shower at the hostel. I must have stayed in that shower until I looked like a lobster robbed of its shell. By that time, two more Germans had arrived at the hostel, surprising no one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day was passed in the hostel, downing coffee and reading. A pity, really, since Trikala seemed like a nice little town, but we had all just about had it with that rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yes, I was in Meteora, according to the best of my knowledge. Can’t say I saw much of the place though…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 002:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Leather boots are well-suited for rain. Wait, no: well-maintained leather boots are. What I’m saying is: Keep your boots well maintained, or else you might get very wet feet and also very wet boots. Leather boots dry very slowly once they are wet. If you’re traveling with only one pair of boots, you really have no excuse for not taking care of them. I’m off to buy some wax…I really hope these things are dry when I come back.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/03/25/Meteora/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/03/25/Meteora/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thessaloniki</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;arrival&quot;&gt;Arrival&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached Thessaloniki after an early morning start (04:30h) and a short flight, during which I was effectively comatose. Every damn time I promise myself not to take flights at such a god-forsaken hour, but this one was half-price. And since flights are for future-Arne to enjoy but for present-Arne to pay for, the former ends up getting screwed over by the stingy latter…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I left Thessaloniki airport, I was only half-comatose, so it didn’t take me very long to realize that Greece was not anywhere near as warm and sunny as I had expected. Partially due to my still-dormant metabolism but mostly due to the frigid weather I was almost shivering at the bus stop. When the bus got close to the city centre, it also started to rain. There is a very special feeling of “oh…fantastic” when the mediterranean paradise you expected turns out to be cold and rainy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 001:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Research the climate and weather of your destination. Really research that stuff. Think about what it&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;means&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Adjust your expectations and daydreams accordingly. You will still be grumpy but at least you’ll be right.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of this feeling was the less than scenic route from the airport towards the city centre: While those outskirts are rarely very pretty, these particular outskirts seemed surprisingly destitute. Not in a “Oh my god, these people need help!” kind of way. More in a “Damn, I wouldn’t want to share a currency with those guys” kind of way. More on that later though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-city&quot;&gt;The city&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more central parts of Thessaloniki consist of an old town up on the hill and a newer part right on the bay. The old town, where my hostel was located, is exactly what you imagine when you think about the Mediterranean: Low houses, lots of narrow roads and passages and plenty of inclines to climb while cursing between clenched teeth. Mostly a residential area, the old town also contains tiny cornershops, small restaurants and the remnants of Byzantine-era fortifications and walls, some of which are easily 8-12 meters high. Coupled with the steep hill they are positioned on, the view down on the city and coastline is quite special (or at least it was on that one day the sun was out):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150319_124700_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150319_201431_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150319_125804_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150321_174658_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The areas near the promenade are very different indeed: They are all composed of multi-story buildings laid out on a grid of roads running parallel or perpendicular to the promenade. Here, Thessaloniki looks like most modern cities with loads of apartments, thick traffic and shopping streets. Sprinkled in between are churches (such as the Hagia Sophia or the Hagia Demetrios), excavations and other hints at the city’s glorious past, such as the White Tower:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150318_122006_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The promenade east of the White Tower connects to parks and playgrounds while the section next to the city centre is seamed with bars, cafes and restaurants. Near it’s western limit, the wharf, the promenade leads up to the poshest part of town. Branded stores, expensive restaurants, luxury food stores, the lot. Going out here was a sharp contrast to, say, Berlin: People were properly dressed up, even the hipsters. Properly dressed hipsters: Take note, Berlin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-did&quot;&gt;What I did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up staying in Thessaloniki for 5 days, sleeping at a lovely hostel in the east-most part of the Old Town. There I met two Teaching Assistants from the US who were working in Austria. While the unpredictable weather kept us from making long-term plans, we made good use of our time exploring the city, its cafes and some of the museums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We even made it to the beach during that one sunny day. 12°C water temperature, so it was definitely more of a plunge than a swim. The white dot in all that cold-looking water is me (if you look closely, you can see the enjoyment on my face…see lesson 001 above.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG-20150322-WA0000_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from that, I paid my dues in terms of visiting museums and doing the usual “oooh” and “aaaah” at most ruins and important sites. I won’t bore you with the details. Besides that, I spent a fair amount of time sitting in a cafe, slowly coming to terms with the idea of traveling for a year. Who in god’s name thought that was a good idea?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/03/20/thessaloniki/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/03/20/thessaloniki/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another travel site?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as I had settled in on Thessaloniki’s lustrous promenade, my peace was disturbed by a scary thought. Staring into the sunset over the bay and puffing on my celebratory cigar I was startled by the question “What if my friends forget about me?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before my departure some of my friends had indeed asked for regular status updates on my trip and/or whether my head was still attached to my shoulders (Day 1: yes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleary keeping my friends informed one by one seems like a lot of repetition. It’s likely that I would eventually start neglecting that task and lose touch. I can easily remedy this by putting regular updates online at a central location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I don’t really like or trust Facebook anymore, so putting all my stuff on there didn’t exactly appeal to me.
The obvious consequence then is a website, something I had discussed with some of my friends as well.
Here is the problem though: Since I am now traveling, my site would be a travel site. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t like travel sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst preparing for my trip I had skimmed through many travel-related sites. Quite simply too many of them were shit. 
Most of them seem to consist of listicles (a topic worthy of a rant of its own. Spoiler: I don’t like them.), “me at the beach” type pictures and rather heavy-handed prose.
I’m positive that’s not the kind of writing I would want to spend time on. Partially because of my drastic aversion to listicles, partially since I’m way too pale to be photographed at the beach. Lastly, I’m not under the delusion that I’m any kind of Hemingway.
So what is this site going to be then? 
Hopefully not a travel site!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I enjoy traveling, this undertaking was never meant to be about the travel itself. Instead, I wanted to have the freedom and energy to immerse myself in topics I find interesting. I could have gone  the formal-education route and lined up for another degree, tuition fees and a set curriculum. Instead I decided to pursue those interests on my own. That way I can spend the money saved at locations which are all a) sunnier, b) cheaper and c) friendlier than my birthplace. And if that’s the idea, why limit myself to one location? There, that’s how it accidentally turned into a trip.
So ideally, this site will be mainly be growing on articles on the topics I’m researching (and of course various vitriolic rants).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despair not, ye of little faith, I will surely write the occasional bit on my whereabouts (and yes, the status of my neck). Prepare for pictures of beaches, wine-glasses and my horribly sun-burned mug. Hell, I might even take a shot at some destination-related articles with a bit of substance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since writing here is also a desperate attempt to build some sort of self-discipline, please feel free to give me a friendly nudge between the eyes if I’m getting too lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s start this experiment then, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 21:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/03/18/another-travel-blog/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/03/18/another-travel-blog/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So long, suckers!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-better-words-to-start-a-personal-blog&quot;&gt;What better words to start a personal blog?&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/02/22/so-long-suckers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/02/22/so-long-suckers/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
