<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Escaping Sloth</title>
    <description>...very slowly</description>
    <link>http://escapingsloth.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://escapingsloth.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Sri Lanka - Nuwara Eliya</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; I found this draft in some subfolder to my website, based on the file timestamp I started writing this when I was in Singapore - so only 2 months after the events. With that in mind it seems only fair I finish and publish this now, a mere three and half years later. Strangely, much of it is still remarkably fresh in my mind…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Great, so you can join us then.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But…I only just got here!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, but there’s nothing to do here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Man, I haven’t slept in two days!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, you get one full night and we head out tomorrow morning.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four of us sit on the balcony and drink beer. Two stories below us the garden is sinking into evening gloom while rain drops keep rolling off the tree tops around us. In the distance the regular racket picks up again: A swelling and ebbing sound somewhere between a flock of hyperactive ducks and a badly maintained machine gun. Horny frogs, apparently, flirting loudly. Every now and then a swooping shadow in the sky catches my eye as one of the huge fruit bats takes flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did you guys buy tickets yet?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We were thinking we’d just go down to the station and ask them for the easiest way to get to Nuraw-…Nawuru-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nuwara Eliya.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That. So basically it would be a a few people from this hostel and us four.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Us, that’s Hayden, Sam, Krzysztof and myself. While Sam has just arrived, the rest of us have already spent a day or two in Kandy, Sri Lanka. All of us arrived a week too late for the big Perahera festival and have already seen the things we wanted to see in town. In my case this list comprised the Temple of the Tooth (built around Gautama Buddha’s tooth - swanky temples are exactly what that man was all about), the botanical garden and the Commonwealth War Cemetery. Other than that I felt that Kandy was just a tad too noisy, crowded and busy for my taste. When somebody suggested to go south towards the big national parks I eagerly jumped on that plan. In the course of this evening a combination of bizarre and hilarious conversation (and more than a few beers) also convinces Sam to join us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we eat an early breakfast, pack up our belongings and head out to rustle up a few tuktuks to take us down to the station. Since the other three are also travelling for longer periods they carry as little luggage as I do. A few others from the hostel, on the other hand, are there on vacation and have about three bags per person. Given the average number of hands per person, that seems like a bad idea, but then it’s not my problem, is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuktuks don’t have a whole lot of stowage so the short ride to the station ends up a being a rather cramped experience. So yes, in a way it’s also my problem now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So there is a train at 1pm.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hm, our accommodation is only reserved until 2pm or so, so we’d miss that…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What, we have accommodation planned?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, the lady from the hostel sorted out something…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s the place called?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No clue, she gave the info to this one girl…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The blond one?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know…is the blond girl also the tall girl?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on such definitive schedules we decide to take a small but air-conditioned shuttle bus instead, which should get us there on time for that dubious reservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could now describe to you the exciting tropical mountain landscapes that passed by our bus windows but the truth of the matter is that I slept through most of the ride on account of a) being pretty tired from the previous night and b) being slightly over-bused after traveling on buses for about half a year. Looking at the route on Google Streetview the journey looks indeed leafy, somewhat moist, yet dusty, all the while hilly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slowly drift back to consciousness as we reach the town of Hawa Eliya. The bus pulls into a vacant parking lot on what appears to be the main street and comes to a shuddering halt. Sloth-like we grab our belongings and get off the bus groaning and yawning. I wasn’t the only one to sleep, it seems. We stand around in parking lot as the bus starts moving again and look after it slightly dazed. After a moment’s silence the group does that thing where one person accidentally takes a step in any direction and the rest of the group just goes “That way? Okay, right behind you!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawa Eliya is located next to a very scenic lake and the entire town is quite presentable - many newer buildings, generally clean and well-kept. Not the part we’re in right now, but the rest is, we find out later. After a few hundred meters the first stomachs begin to growl irritably. This begins a pattern I would see play out a million times with other longer-term travellers: Everbody has to eat, but people who travel for a year or longer tend to stretch their budets a little. So a common meal is curry-with-rice, served in a shed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet the prelude to actually eating always seems to be the same: You find a place that looks suitably…well, crap. Everybody piles through the tiny entrance into the the spicy-smelling gloom beyond. Your eyes begin to water immediately and the steam hides a great many things better left unseen anyway. One of your group will eventually regain control of his vocal cords and yell into the boiling fog the immortal words “CURRYANDRICE - HOWMUCH?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be answered by incomprehensible yelling from the kitchen, after which most of your group will look at each other nodding. You nod because you’re hungry, and because curry and rice is definitely on the menu, it’s often tasty and at whatever price that man is asking, there really is no point to even wondering what might be in that curry. But no, it’s not meant to be: There is always that one guy who angrily yells “60 RUPEES? THAT’S AN OUTRAGE, WE’RE LEAVING!” (60 Sri Lankan Rupees came to around 0.35 USD when I was there.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And out of hungry, grudging solidarity with the most frugual of travellers, the group then files out through the exit and back into the sunlight. The group marches on, uniformly agreeing with one another that they were fully justified in not playing along with such a blatant rip-off. Eventually, another shed is found, the ritual repeated. Sooner or later you will eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the natural question to ask is: Does that make sense? Why haggle over what comes to a price difference of 5 cents? Well…yes and no. If you don’t have a time limit on your travels, their duration is largely set by budget. So the difference between paying 60 rupees and paying 40 theoretically adds up to 50% longer trips. I say theoretically because obviously it doesn’t work that way: In many parts of the world food is only a small part of travel expenses - certainly if you’re willing to stick to curry and rice. Other expenses drive total cost, such as accommodation, transport, activities and drinking. And you know what goes really well with curry and rice, especially if finding it has taken you two hours? A nice, cold beer! It’s only 200 Rupees after all!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2019/01/03/nuwara-eliya/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2019/01/03/nuwara-eliya/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bombay...or Mumbai?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Is this candy? Or soap? Nope, no label on the box either…,” I hesitate, the little orange cube held in my hand, and look around the compartment for a clue. The seven other passengers are busy with their rice dishes and small talk has given way to the steady rumble of train wheels on steel tracks. Eventually I catch the eye of an older man sitting across from me. He grabs the little orange thingy from his tray, pops it into his mouth and smiles at me while chewing with relish. Ah, okay. Not soap then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lean back and enjoy the sweet, buttery taste of the dessert and wash it down with some milk tea. This was the first of four meals, snacks and teas served aboard the night train from Delhi to Bombay. I pre-booked this ticket before my trip to Manali, as apparently train tickets in India need to be booked well in advance. On the upside, I got a ticket for a AC 3A class carriage (technically mid-range but also the cheapest option the travel agent deemed appropriate for me). The downside of the pre-booked ticket: I took an overnight coach back from Delhi to Manali (14 hours, and yes, they played the same bollywood movie again) only to hang out in Delhi for half a day before embarking on this 16-hour train journey. Who needs sleep anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Delhi, a friendly family on the platform had made sure I got on the right train and into the right carriage. Each carriage was divided into four compartments of eight bunks each. One stack of two bunks on one side, the aisle and then two stacks of three bunks perpendicular to the carriage itself. Having walked past some of the other carts I was gladdened by how clean and orderly things were. I chucked my bag onto one of the top bunks and sat down on the bottom bunk to have a look at the other passengers. Two women, five men. Ages between 20 and 60. All neat and tidy and quiet. Before any real conversation took place the attendant brought around sheets and blankets, followed by meal trays. The scent of spicy curry filled the cart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full and happy I start chatting with the others about their backgrounds and plans. The elevator-like awkwardness of strangers pushed together quickly melts away. Since I’m so obviously foreign, curiosity overrides detachment and everybody becomes involved in the conversation. They, it turns out, are going to Bombay for work: Two programmers, two lawyers, a banker, a call center worker and an aspiring actor. All of them seem to be from Delhi, somehow, but work in Bombay. The young aspiring actor says: “You make your life in Bombay, but you live it in Delhi.” The others nod. All of them seem to be part of the growing middle class: educated, ambitious and dedicated to their jobs. The night train takes a while for the journey, they admit, but domestic flights are still expensive by comparison. A flight from Delhi to Bombay costs about 60€, compared to the 13€ or so I paid for the train. Good career prospects are easily worth the hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pass the evening with small talk. Another snack is served and people start preparing their bunk beds. The elderly man wishes everybody a good night and conversation subsides. The lights are switched off. Up on my top bunk the air conditioning is causing me to shiver: The AC vent is right above me and a few icicles hang from it. I curse the irony of getting hypothermia in a 35°C climate as I wrap myself in the blanket and my jacket. I don’t sleep much, instead I lie awake and listen to the keening sound of the wheels, steady snoring, distant whispered conversations and bursts of muffled laughter. Eventually I drift off into dreamless dozing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning begins when breakfast is brought into the compartment and we all gather on the lower bunks to eat. Apparently I’m not the only one who felt cold at night and some of the others look just as frazzled as I feel. Hot tea works its miracle on us all and the talking continues as the sun rises on the tropical landscapes outside. Palm trees and mangroves line the tracks and the air smells hot and humid. For about an hour the train speeds southwards through Bombay’s metropolitan region: Small towns, suburbs and eventually the outer districts of the Bombay itself. The scale of the city astounds me but as soon as the city itself comes into view the skies open up and a deluge falls upon the city. All I see of Bombay until the train pulls into Bombay Central is water. As the train comes to a halt I shoulder my bag and say my goodbyes to the others. Then I step out into the rain.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2016/07/15/bombay_train/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2016/07/15/bombay_train/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Manali II - No, tell me more about this weed!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, Manali. I’ll remember Manali as one of the many places I would have liked to explore further. Since my silly eTourist visa only let me stay in India for 30 days, I only spent a total of 1.5 days in Manali…about as much time as I spent on the bus there and back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The landscapes around Manali are strikingly beautiful, with forrest-covered mountains, roaring waterfalls and staggering views just begging to be explored in extended hikes. Due to the time constraint (and lack of equipment) I decided to limit my excursions to Manali town. Manali itself is distinctly tourist-y, with that in-your-face mixture of western-style cafes and restaurants, clothes that go well with dreadlocks and a hundred travel agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four things I recall most keenly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weather&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I noticed up there: I did not feel like I was being roasted alive on a pyre of burning stars! Due to the altitude the state of Himachal Pradesh enjoys a temperate climate (and snow in winter!) which felt incredibly refreshing as I had been sweat-soaked ever since I left the Georgian mountains two months earlier. When I reached Manali it was a rainy, foggy, somewhat windy 13°C and loved every second of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150805_123218.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150805_123218_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The climate also means that the countryside looks a lot more like the Northern Europe I’m used to. Walking around town in the shade of the tall conifers made me feel oddly…home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150805_144242.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150805_144242_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historical sidenote: The British Raj had its summer residence in the town of Shimla, some hundred kilometers south of Manali for this very reason: British people are as ill-suited for the Indian summer as I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plant life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the sheer abundance of natural beauty there is a ton of things you can do. You can buy weed, sell weed, cook with weed, eat weed, drink weed, buy weed paraphernalia, and some people apparently even smoke weed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And more importantly, you can talk about weed. Since weed is clearly the most interesting topic in the world, there are so many facets to be discussed, weed-smoking-anecdotes to be recounted and hopes of future weed-related adventures to be shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150805_150050.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150805_150050_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a view widely shared amongst the crowds of Israeli and Russian backpackers that tend to prowl that whole triangle between Dharamsala, Rishikesh and Manali. Talking to them I found out that some of them had ended up staying in Manali for months when they had planned on staying a few days. Almost as if something made them a bit lazy and passive…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150805_145233.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150805_145233_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I’m not that interested in this side of botany (or other chemical experiments conducted there), I was glad to find two people who were also more interested in the town and we had a look around the town and its surroundings despite the unpredicatable weather and frequent rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mud. Mud everywhere&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yes, rain. In a town that doesn’t really do paved roads and is blessed with livestock aplenty. Basically most of Manali is mud of various origins and when I was there I stood in it up to my ankles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150805_152109.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150805_152109_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who said boots weren’t any good for travel in India? For the record: They are. They are absolutely perfect for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150805_152547.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150805_152547_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impossible interwebs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had one last educational moment when I logged onto the homestay wifi to send a few emails. Nothing much seemed to happen connection-wise and I tried a ping-command, just to see how bad things were. Oh boy…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ping tool sends a stream of data packets to a specified destination and measures how long it takes to return. When I ping google.com from home, I get times of 20-50ms. In Manali I did not see any replies coming back at all. Yet the packets did not time out either. Frustrated, I headed out for dinner and when I got back I saw that my loyal packets had indeed returned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;64 bytes from 78.47.139.10: icmp_seq=3212 ttl=46 time=1614652.104 ms
64 bytes from 78.47.139.10: icmp_seq=3213 ttl=46 time=1613654.267 ms
64 bytes from 78.47.139.10: icmp_seq=3214 ttl=46 time=1612656.231 ms
64 bytes from 78.47.139.10: icmp_seq=3217 ttl=46 time=1609908.252 ms
64 bytes from 78.47.139.10: icmp_seq=3218 ttl=46 time=1608912.793 ms
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, measured times of 1.6 million ms. That’s 27 minutes.  I didn’t even know that was technically possible and I still suspect that it really shouldn’t be. Either way, I had a good laugh and went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2016/06/11/manali_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2016/06/11/manali_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Manali I - Woohoo, mountains!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Did I tell you about that time I went to Tibet and met the Dalai Llama? Good, because the closest I got was the lower Himalayas and people there were not so much enlightened as just plain lit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 10 days in Delhi I felt like I deserved some peace and quiet for once. Some guys I met in the hostel had mentioned Manali, a small town in the lower reaches of the Himalayas, which was apparently downright divine. That sounded about right to me, so I visited one of the many travel agencies clustered around New Delhi Station. After some haggling I managed to get a ticket for the 14-hour bus journey up into the mountains. 14 hours for 550km, that comes to about 40km/h. Great. On top of that the ticket was hand-written onto a block of greasy receipts which looked so dodgy that I asked my local friend Arko if that was even going to get me on the bus. Apparently it was. I wasn’t entirely convinced there was even going to be a bus but that’s just because I’m a half-empty kind of guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arko graciously accompanied me to the bus stop the next day and together we stood in the blistering afternoon heat and waited for a coach which was about to turn up really soon, probably, eventually. To my great surprise - not his though! - a coach did turn up barely an hour later and I got on board without any problems. The conductor gave me a seat in the last row - not good - and between a very talkative local teenager and two Israeli girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two hours of our journey were spent on just getting out of Delhi. Yes, I knew that Delhi is home to about 20 million people, and yet the geographical size of the metropolitan area surprised me. Eventually the scenery became more suburban, interrupted by the occasional industrial park. The sun set as we finally left Delhi behind us. I spent a few moments getting annoyed by the fact that the Israeli girls had their shoes up on the seats. Sure, this seems picky in a region where garbage disposal follows the “chuck-it-in-the-streets-and-set-it-on-fire” paradigm (also applicable to the deceased - and sometimes also the diseased), but come on! Take your shoes off the cushions you filthy peasants!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I protected myself against the onslaught of small-talk emanating from my other seat neighbour by jamming my earphones right into my eardrums, turned up the volume and watched the countryside swoosh past. After a while I just dozed off and didn’t wake up until it was properly dark and the bus was twisting it’s way up a mountain road. Sitting in the back of the bus, I was thrown left and right at every turn like a pale, increasingly disgruntled pendulum. Since the road mainly consisted of potholes, I also got to spend about an hour being bounced up to the roof before crashing back down into my seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidenote: My friend Hayden would later tell me of a bus trip in Myanmar during which three different people threw up on him. That in mind, a bit of bouncing-around doesn’t feel so bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 22:00h the on-board entertainment system was switched on and I got to the enjoy “Bajrangi Bhaijaan”, two and a half hours of action, singing, dance and drama.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vyX4toD395U&quot;&gt;Here, have a taste!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the bus was merrily crashing through the mountains, the driver had dialled up the volume to 11. That didn’t exactly help me because the movie was in Hindi but I certainly enjoyed the song-and-dance scenes. Eventually I pulled my trusty travel blanket over my head and passed out. I only woke a few times when a particularly deep pothole caused me to slam back into my seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I did wake up, it was because the driver had stopped at a restaurant/gas station/shack around 05:00h. I felt fairly groggy but got off the bus because I was curious where we had arrived. Outside, the scenery was amazing: The road passed high over the Beas river which ran deep in a canyon below us. All around me the mountainsides were steep and full of lush greenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150804_063752.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150804_063752_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;First sunrise in the lower Himalayas&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun hadn’t risen above the surrounding peaks yet and hazy light shone through the fog covering everything around us. Watching the landscape peel itself out of the haze in slow-motion felt incredible. It was only then it really hit me that I was actually in the Himalayas. Yes, yes, &lt;em&gt;lower&lt;/em&gt; Himalayas, shuddup, I’m having a moment here! Despite the early hour I couldn’t help but grin at the thought of just how far away from home I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150804_054223.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150804_054223_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The rest stop&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few moments later a look at the toilet facilities wiped that grin off my face. Far away indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got back on the bus, we followed the Beas river for several hours. The valley contains dozens of small towns, one after another like links on a chain. Some of them are tiny hamlets built on the sheer drops, others - like Kullu - are proper cities including an airport. For the remaining drive, I sat with my face glued to the window, soaking up the fantastic landscape and the views. The few pictures I managed to take from the moving bus really don’t do justice to the scenery that unfolded before me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150804_064820.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150804_064820_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150804_075520.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150804_075520_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 09:00h we finally reached Manali bus station, basically an empty lot right next to the river and full of tour buses. As soon as the first passengers disembarked, a horde of tuktuk-drivers gathered around them. I just got off, grabbed my bag and stepped aside for a moment to take a breather. It was then that I observed a young Russian perform an act of masterful tuktuk management: He turned to the crowd of drivers and yelled “Okay, who wants to drive me tup to Olive Garden for 50 rupees?” One by one the drivers turned away from his low-ball offer and other tourists promised much better business. But eventually one driver stepped forward and agreed to take him up on his offer. I stood amazed. What a lession in market efficiency!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150805_130202.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150805_130202_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Downtown Manali&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boris and I started talking and when he heard that I hadn’t decided where to stay, he offered me a ride. Turns out that he had been to Manali eight times already and always stayed at the same place. Entirely convinced I got into the cab and we drove up through the centre of Manali and further up onto one incline overlooking the town. At first glance the town looked strange: Many buildings were half-finished, most roads covered in mud and trash. Most stores seemed to be either travel agencies or restaurants and cafes targeted at tourists. At the same time the view of the area was stunning. Boris told the driver where to stop and together we walked up a small path (full of mud) to a building which was half-finished and half…concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150804_093759.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150804_093759_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The view from my room&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, Boris sought out the owner and affectionately yelled at him until he grudlingly accepted Boris’ suggestion that I really should be allowed to get a double room for about 3 USD per night. This sounded just fine to me, so I dumped my bag in my new room and then enjoyed the view from my balcony for a bit before heading into town for a late breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2016/03/24/manali/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2016/03/24/manali/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Agra - The Taj Mahal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Can’t go to India without seeing the Taj Mahal. Actually, you very well can as it’s a big country and the Taj is not a franchise business, so there is only one and…I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was in Delhi, it seemed like a smart idea to go take a look though: The Taj Mahal is located in a neighbouring city called Agra only a few hours away and I wanted to see what all the fuss is about. Luckily I had run into a group of friends from England at the hostel, and they were planning to go, so I just tagged along. Unfortunately, they had moved to another hostel in the meantime and hired a car from there. And so it happened that I had to kick myself out of bed around 3am and take an auto/tuktuk/threewheeler from Paharganj to South Delhi. This time of night the roads were wonderfully quiet and empty, just like my brain. Unfortunately this was also true for the driver, who took a somewhat experimental approach to navigation. As luck would have it, the others were delayed, too, since their driver hadn’t turned up yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he did, we were all a bit surprised: Our ride was a lot cleaner and fancier than expected. Impressed, we settled down for a 4-hour nap on our way to Agra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HONK! - HONK! - HOOOOOOOONK!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately our driver did not live up to the distinguished flair of our ride: As we drove through South Delhi, he honked continuously, weaving in and out of traffic. Yay, we were riding with Indian Ayrton Senna…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since there was no hope of sleeping, I enjoyed the view of the sprawling city as it was slowly waking up. Everywhere construction sites were reaching up into the sky. As we drove past Faridabad Industrial Town I found myself staring at the swanky appartment buildings the multinationals had built there for their staff. My amazement was shortlived at this ungodly hour, so I drifted off before too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely not drooling, I had sunk against the window and only woke up when I heard the sound of dull thumping. When I looked around, I saw that the sound was caused by our driver repeatedly punching his thigh. When asked why, he responded “So I stay awake!” Oooo-kay. We insisted he stop at the next gas station and bought him a coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As luck would have it, our driver was clearly not used to higher doses of caffeine and decided to liven up the early morning by turning on the radio and tuning into a station playing native dance music (think squealing pipes, a tinny beat and the sounds of small animals in agony). Good thinking, genius: Not like any of us wanted to sleep at goddamn six in the morning…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of much-need sleep I got to see some of the country side and some villages between Delhi and Agra. Simply put: Not a fan. Most of the villages seemed fairly underdeveloped, the roads were bad and traffic consisted of various configurations of wheels, axles, curious-looking engines and livestock. Often a little bit of everything, all bound together with sticky tape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_081926.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_081926_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Low-emissions transportation&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We picked up our tour guide in the outskirts of Agra, a polite and well-spoken professional guide. Next we stopped at a fairly swanky-looking hotel (in a decidedly less swanky-looking neighbourhood) for brunch before heading towards the Taj Mahal itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The powers-that-be forbid traffic of cars and tuktuks around the Taj Mahal (generally a good idea: black soot, white stone, makes sense). The downside of that was that as we stepped out of the car, we also stepped into a massive pack of waiting hawkers and shitpeddlers. “No. No. No, thank you. I swear to god, if you touch me again..!” So we made our way throught the thick of commerce towards the entrance. Here, our guide collected money for the entrance fees. As I had seen before in Delhi, discriminatory prices apply. This means that tourists like us paid about 10€ per person, where locals and other Asians paid about one Euro or two. While this seems a bit unusual, a part of me hopes that the money is actually used for the upkeep of this impressive monument. It probably is. I mean, they say it is. So it probably is. Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our tickets, complimentary water bottles and plastic overshoes we passed through yet another security checkpoint and found ourselves in front of the Great Gate. Now I’ll leave the history lesson to Wikipedia, but the gist is: The entire complex was built under orders of emperor Shah Jahan in the early 17th century. Weirdly, I had assumed it to be much older but that might just be me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pointy white building is a tomb for his favourite wife, Mumtaz Mahal, as a symbol of his undying love for her. His other three wives got smaller buildings, as a type of undying fuck-you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_084753.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_084753_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The Great Gate&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outer gates and walls consist of red stone with incredibly intricate inlays of stones and mother of pearl. Shah Jahan being a Moghul, and hence muslim, emperor, many of the inlays and inscriptions are actually calligraphy and verses of the the Qur’an.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_085144.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_085144_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Calligraphy in marble&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the mesmerizing detail of inlays, the entire complex is filled with interesting architectural mindgames. For example, the calligraphy on the Great Gate is written in increasingly larger font towards the top, to ensure all letters look the same size when viewed from the ground. The effect is hard to describe but there is a tangible feeling of “…huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The the Great Gate one enters the mausoleum grounds, in which a long pool points towards the white mausoleum itself. Eventhough we were less than lucky with the weather, the view was captivating. While we were swarmed by other tourists, seeing this World Wonder just before us was oddly moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_085404.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_085404_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View from the Great Gate&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I should also note that the grounds were kept very clean and orderly. Now that’s what I paid for!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the path along the pool we reached the foot of the mausoleum. Here, our guide pointed out that the four towers around the main building were actually built at an angle, slightly slanting outwards. This was primarily done to keep them from damaging the main dome should they fall, but also has the curious effect of - again - reducing skewing a bit when viewed from the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_090529.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_090529_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we all slipped on our overshoes and slowly shuffled into the mausoleum. Every inch of white marble was covered in intricate patterns and inlays. The level of detail was truly astonishing. In the light of flashlights we wandered around the tomb of Mumtaz Mahal and marveled at the decoration all around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_091650.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_091650_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_092039.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_092039_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we managed to push through the throng of tourists and exited the tomb on the backside. The Taj had been build right on the Yamuna riverbank. Rumor has it that Shah Jahan had begun construction of a second tomb for himself on the opposite riverbank, only built from black stone. However, when researching that topic, I found conflicting reports about that tale. We ended up enjoying the view of the misty river for a bit before heading back towards the gate. We used the way back to take a few more pictures (for Facebook, you know) and then fought our way back towards the entrance and our car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_094630.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_094630_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stood around for about 15 minutes, waiting for our driver to turn up, all the while every damn hawker of Agra danced around us. “No. No. No. Just. No. Jesus. No. No. Fffffff…NO!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were supposed to go see the Red Fort of Agra next, but were dropped off at a “Crafts Museum” first. Here, a few crafty local guys were creating some of those amazing stone inlays for decoration. It took a while to explain to them that yes, that marble table top with 18 kinds of gem inlays was very impressive, but no, I was not going to buy, partially because it weighed 80kg. No, I did not want them to ship it to my home address, but thanks for asking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_111654.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_111654_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Traditional crafts&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After tactfully leaving the “museum”, we visited the Red Fort. I’ll be honest: I remember next to nothing about that part. The sun had come out and burned my brain to a crisp. I was incredibly glad to get back into the car eventually. Most of us fell asleep almost right away and slept blissfully through the bumpy ride back to Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2016/02/03/agra-taj-mahal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2016/02/03/agra-taj-mahal/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Delhi III - The Sikh temple</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Once again I’m in Bangalore, India, the last stop of my journey. As a result of a gypsy curse (long story), every internet connection I connect to in this city dies immediately. The only connection that seems to work is the wifi at Starbucks. So yes, I’m sitting here, yet another free spirit with a Macbook in their lap, busily typing away. If you ask the staff nicely, you can even get coffee  - without milk, sugar, caramel and whatever other pollutants they want to cram into your cup. Apparently my last post still had me in Delhi, so let’s pick it up there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gurudwara-bangla-sahib&quot;&gt;Gurudwara Bangla Sahib&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One downside of traveling by yourself is that every now and then you find yourself with zero motivation in a place you should find interesting. And nobody else does anything about it! It was one of those days. I was lying on my bunk at the hostel doing nothing. Not reading anything, not watching anything, not listening to anything - not even thinking about anything, really. I was mainly enjoying the relative cool and quiet, while outside the sun was roasting that particular sensory overload that is Delhi. Unbidden, the realisation that I only had one more day left in Delhi popped in my head, followed by the guilty admission that I really should be more travel-ly. In my experience, people tend to underestimate the energy required for travel. It’s those people that tend to message you “Oh, why are you inside? You should be out, exploring stuff!” Why don’t you go out yourself, smartass!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I find it easy enough to ignore those awful yay-sayers, tuning out that nagging voice in my head was a lot more difficult. Eventually I dragged myself out of bed and stepped out into the heat, the noise and the chaos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somebody had mentioned that there was a beautiful Sikh temple not too far away. Sikh are the guys with the turbans, in case you were wondering, and they tend to build nice temples. So I found myself a tuktuk/auto and got myself dropped off at Connaught Place, from where I would walk the remaining stretch to Gurudwara Bangla Sahib.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The residential neighbourhood surrounding the temple is oddly calm and quiet. I see few people in the streets, and the buildings and trees absorb most of the noise. Instead of people I see monkeys (and the occasional security guard failing to chase them off with sticks). Monkeys tend to be egotistical, ungrateful assholes prone to violence, shrieking and poop-flinging (lending a whole lot of support the the idea of evolution). In Europe we don’t get monkeys, which sadly means that most poop remains un-flung but makes those animals all the more interesting when I finally get to see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150726_171556.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150726_171556_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Monkey patrol&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hundred meters out from the temple a low hum rises above the silence of the area. Soon I reach an intersection and spy a white tower with a gilded dome  loom over the block. The hum turns out to be a huge crowd around what must be the temple. As I get closer, the crowd of colourfully dressed families closes around me. The chatter, singing and sound of bells is deafening. I can smell food and a lot of burning incense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150726_172105.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150726_172105_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Main gate to the temple&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I end up following the crowd through a white gate onto a square in front of the temple. Everybody else is taking off their shoes and leaves them at a wardrobe outside the temple. I follow suit and then let the flow of people carry me up the stairs. A young Sikh stops me and hands me a scarf, which I tie around my head, covering my hair. After a few minutes, the result is acceptable, though it leaves him and his friends grinning broadly. Whatever man!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temple is made up of two parts: The prayer hall itself, which a continuous stream of people passes through, and an outside area of a large pool with a roofed archway around it. Everything is made of white stone with intricate inlays. Gold twinkles in the sun. I decide to take a walk around the pool, together with many other visitors. The atmosphere outside is relaxed: People chat and laugh together, children run around playing and several visitors sit down under the arches and eat. Many visitors take a ritual bath in the pool, surrounded by others taking selfies in front of the spectacular temple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150726_173759.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150726_173759_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View from the pool&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the clouds grow darker and darker, I decide to sit down under the arches for a break. Every few minutes, small groups break off from the stream of passers-by and come up to me, asking for a picture with me. I don’t really see a reason to decline, so I obediently pose for a few pictures and exchange a few handshakes. Unfortunately, many of them seem a bit too shy for conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150726_174122.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150726_174122_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The arcades around the pool&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a walk around the pool I decide to brave the crowds and step inside the temple itself. This being India, personal space is not much of  an issue for anybody and as a slow-moving group cuddle we flow into the main hall of the temple. Inside, every inch of marble is covered in ornate patterns in gold and lively colours. The throng of people carries me past a huge arrangement of flowers and statues, while the air is full of incense and chanting. I’m looking around, my senses  completely overwhelmed. At some point, I feel a hand clamping down on my shoulder, which belongs to one of the younger guys I spoke to earlier outside. He gave me a fairly unexpected hug and then disappeared in the crowd, leaving me a bit bewildered. Finally, the crowd around me pushed itself over the doorstep at the exit and out into the open air. Still stunned by the noise and the whirl of colours inside I’m walking down to the wardrobe robotically. I pull on my boots and sit there for a while, processing the experience. Eventually, I wrestle myself free of the sights and head back out into the streets.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/04/delhi_iii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/04/delhi_iii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Delhi II - First Night, part 2</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-actually-happened&quot;&gt;What ACTUALLY happened&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, I’m being a bit retarded. Not so much a shark, more of a deranged hippo in a sewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you catch what was going on? I obviously didn’t and it took me half a day and a few conversations with other travellers to really appreciate the beauty of what happened here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course they were all in on it! The whole thing is a brazen scam and famous enough that I could have avoided it just by doing some basic research on Delhi. Oh well…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s the thing: There’s exactly &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; official, legit tourist information in Delhi. This one wasn’t it. You find places calling themselves “Government Tourist Information” all over town, but these places are just travel agencies exploiting tourists’ belief that anything calling itself that must be legit. Nope, not in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is how it works: The tuktuk driver finds some pretense to take his passengers to one of those agencies - a festival, a political event, the second coming of the messiah. The agency picks up the pretense for why you can’t get to your hotel. In the absence of an internet connection you can’t really check. When they offer to call the hotel, they don’t dial the number you give them, instead they dial their accomplices in the room next door, who’ll play along and confirm the initial pretense. In the meantime the agency tries to sell you on overpriced tour packages. Eventually, the accomplices call you back, letting you know you won’t be able to stay at your hotel. At this point, the driver will take you to whatever hotel they recommend instead. There you’ll be drastically overcharged for the room, a part of which goes to the driver as a commission for luring you there in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple, eh? I fell for it completely. When I figured it out I felt this particular mixture of anger and shame you get when you find yourself scammed. I briefly entertained the notion of going back to the ‘Government Tourist Information’ and having a little chat with them. I daydreamed of the whole building burning down and the smell of bacon rising from their charred bodies. In the end, none of that came to pass. Instead, I put it down as a learning experience:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is always room for a bit more cynicism:&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re reading this you’re likely a fairly sceptical person - by western standards. In India, that’s not enough. Somebody says they work for the government? Could be, but I wouldn’t count on it. A taxi driver tells you he knows the place you want to get to? Maybe, but it’s unlikely. The truth had a distinctly subjective flavour in Delhi and I felt myself tiring of that, especially with the petty, bold-faced lies of vendors, tour guides and drivers. I’ve always tried to think the worst of people, but some people managed to be even worst-er. Lesson learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common sense, bring it:&lt;/strong&gt; No free hotel rooms under 150 USD a night. Come on. Think about it: Delhi has a population of about 20 million. Average monthly income is around 300 USD. Sound fishy? My only excuse is that it was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; late and I was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; tired and…eh, forget it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get that SIM card at the airport:&lt;/strong&gt; The internet is a fantastic way of fact-checking a lot of things. Festival dates for example, or hotel prices. Addresses even. Don’t rely on other peoples’ internet connections, they have a habit of cutting out at inconvenient times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sidenote: About 4 out of 5 western travelers I spoke to in Delhi had fallen for the exact same scam. One of them had been taken for 250 USD that night. All of them seemed to feel that mixture of embarrassment and amazement at the shamelessness of the scam. Why the city is allowing those places to keep using the whole ‘government’ label is beyond me, though I do have a suspicion…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first night was probably the crappiest first impression I ever got of a country. Luckily, after that things got better: I met some amazing people, saw some incredibly sights and had a great time overall. Despite what you have read so far, I thoroughly enjoyed my time in India. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/04/delhi_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/04/delhi_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beirut</title>
        <description>&lt;div align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;color:gray&quot;&gt;
&quot;Lebanon...Beirut of all evil!&quot;
-- Gary
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first two weeks of October I visited Lebanon, just so I could continue my writing projects on here. No, really!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, fine: I flew there to visit my friends Andrew and Angie and I did not have any prior notion of what Lebanon would be like, nor any intention of writing about it. My main aim was to spend time with my friends and start building up some flabby insulation for the coming winter. Since Lebanon isn’t the most common destination for tourism and tends to be on the news because of the other t-word, upon my return I was asked the same questions by several people. Consequently, I figured I’d dust off my text editor and make sure I could answer the next friendly question with the immortal sentence, “Just google it…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here is how this is going to happen: I’ll throw in some random headlines and a bunch of photographs that in no way relate to the heading under with they’re posted. You’ll do your best to be both amused and informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;is-it-safe&quot;&gt;Is it safe?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was probably the most commonly asked question about my trip. Weirdly enough, I hadn’t really given this much thought beforehand. On the one hand the whole region is somewhat famous for being a bit tense at the best of times. On the other hand, my friends were already living there and so surely that meant there was no reason for concern. Somehow it did not occur to me that my friends work in security and refugee aid, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did check the foreign departments’ website just to see about visa requirements and there was a tersely worded travel warning which I read as “Beirut is totally fine, don’t worry, just maybe stay away from the borders if you can, mmmmkay?”. The fact that Beirut is small enough to consist mostly of borders didn’t really concern me at the time. Nor did the fact that Lebanon is on a number of lists which mean I had to declare my trip to my employer. Most of those lists are not exactly of the best-of kind. Speaking of lists… &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_attacks_in_Lebanon&quot;&gt;Wikipedia: List of attacks in Lebanon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But none of that really seemed to matter. When I flew in, my arrival wasn’t any different from other countries. Beirut it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-must-be-incredibly-full-of-refugees-right&quot;&gt;It must be incredibly full of refugees, right?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistically speaking, yes. Lebanon has taken in about XYZ million refugees from Syria. It also harbors about XYZ million Palestinian refugees, many of whom have been in the country since the XXs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-did-you-do-in-the-desert&quot;&gt;What did you do in the desert?&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/03/beirut/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/03/beirut/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Delhi I - First Night, part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;div align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;color:gray&quot;&gt;
&quot;Write drunk, edit sober!&quot;
-- Alcoholics
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently in Hoi An, a lovely seaside-town in eastern Vietnam. So why is this post titled “Delhi”, you may wonder. Well, the reasons are complicated, but they involve a very generous restaurant owner, at least 7 shots of rice wine and the realization that if I can’t be bothered to write about certain parts of my journey you probably couldn’t be bothered to read about them either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that spirit - and several others - I’ll procrastinate writing more about the Middle East by writing about my arrival in India instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll say this much up front: Of the countries I visited during this trip, India was the one that felt strangest to me. In terms of getting out of my comfort zone, it was a fantastic success. It was also a series of impressions and experiences that made what else I saw of Southeast Asia seem…tame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India felt extreme in several ways. Some things were extremely pleasant, others extremely annoying. As a result, India probably had the strongest effect on my perspective.
Was that a consistently pleasant experience? Well…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;arriving-in-delhi&quot;&gt;Arriving in Delhi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached Delhi around 11pm, after a short layover in Abu Dhabi. Obviously I had some images in my head, but the airport really didn’t match them: Turns out, Delhi Airport is actually very new, very clean and suspiciously quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a long day I was glad to see that my eVisa carried me through immigration without too many questions (I did get fingerprinted though). I had booked a hotel in advance and was eager to find it and go to sleep. Luckily the airport terminal has a direct metro connection to the city centre. While trying to figure out the ticket system, I started chatting with two local university students who had just returned from a trip to Europe and took me under their wings, making sure I got off the metro at the right stop, namely New Delhi Station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was lovely. I got out there and took a tuktuk (hehe) to my hotel. And that’s where that evening suddenly turned around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-point-of-view&quot;&gt;My point-of-view&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m worldly and well-traveled, easily adapting to a new city like a shark smoothly sliding into a new current.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are cruising past Connaught Place, a circular area full of shops and bars, one of Delhi’s central sights. The night is lively, but cooler than Oman and calmer than I expected of India. Suddenly the driver pulls over and asks me to repeat the address of my hotel. I read it out to him. His English is tough to understand but he wants to know which block the hotel is at. I don’t know, the email doesn’t say and I don’t have internet to check. Not to worry, he says, he’ll just drive me to the Government Tourist Information and they’ll find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decline and show him the map on my phone, telling him to just drive up there. He insists on going to the tourist information, telling me that the area around my hotel is cordoned off for a festival and he can’t drive there. This seems weird, because I didn’t see any blockades or signs and it’s really rather quiet. After about 5 minutes of arguing I relent and tell him to just get on with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then drives to an unassuming-looking building down the road with a big sign saying “Government Tourist Information”, stops and ushers me in. I’m greeted by a middle-aged man with a badge clipped to his shirt and he invites me to sit down in an office. The shelves are full of travel guides, brochures and a few framed official-looking documents and letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then tells me that the city is a bit out of control due to a big festival taking place in the centre. When he looks up my hotel on a map he finds out that, yeup, it’s definitely blocked off right now. The internet connection is down at the moment, but we can call my hotel from his office. I read the number to him and he passes me the handset. I recite my booking code into the handset and I’m being told that yes, the hotel is difficult to reach right now, but they’ll think of something and call me back. Lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tourist-information-guy then tells me that it might be difficult to find alternative accommodation tonight, since every hotel is going to be booked out because of the festival. Pretty much impossible to find anything under 150 USD a night, really. But I could spend a few days in one of the surrounding cities, do some sightseeing. He proposes to put together a nice tour around Rajasthan, maybe a week or so including all the major sighs and cities. A nice idea, but unfortunately his plan for one week costs about as much as I budget for a month. So maybe I would like to take a private car to Agra tonight, see the Taj Mahal tomorrow? A cheap way of evading all the hassle with the festival and all? He quotes me 200 USD for that, which seems…steep. I politely decline. Man, at this point I’m getting proper sleepy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually the hotel rings back, informing me that regrettably they could not find a way of getting me there. Of course they’ll refund me for it, but I’ll have to find another place to stay. A bit of a blow for me, because I wasn’t planning on spending 150 USD on a single night and my new friend really didn’t know any hotel that would have cheaper rooms available. Checking online would help, but the internet connection is still down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, around one o’clock he does think of one or two places that might be a bit cheaper. The tuktuk driver, who has been faithfully waiting outside agrees to drive me there after getting the address from the tourist information. I almost fall asleep on the way and get hotel room at the other end of the city. I haggle the price down to 70 USD, go up to my room and pass out on the bed immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/03/delhi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/03/delhi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bahrain II - Life in the desert</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;All in all I spent about 3 weeks in Bahrain, staying with my friend Andrew who graciously showed me around. This was my first time in the middle east, so here are a few assorted observations. Seriously, it’s 01:00h here and I had a few beers…if you expect a coherent narrative you came to the wrong place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;still-pretty-warm&quot;&gt;Still pretty warm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahrain is a desert country. No surprises there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150619_133523.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150619_133523_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;See? Desert!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, it’s an island, but a desert island in a shallow, half-boiling pond (called ‘the gulf’) surrounded by more desert in almost every direction. A few times I stepped outside during the day. I lived to regret it every single time: The heat was unbearable. A casual 40°C and a city baked to a smoking crisp by a sun as merciless as a very merciless thing. You don’t see other people in the streets because they’ve learned their lesson long ago: Just. Don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150617_153210.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150617_153210_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Al Fateh Grand Mosque&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150617_152201.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150617_152201_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Inside the mosque&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150617_152736.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150617_152736_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The gorgeous prayer hall&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I being overly sensitive because I’m used to northern European climate? Sure. Does that make the Emirates any less hostile to human life? Not really. Airconditioning alone keeps people from turning into a human form of jerky. And this is the greater irony:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is Bahrain insanely hot, it’s also freezing cold. The same geniuses who thought it was a good idea to build cities on sand that’s a few degrees above its melting point also thought it might be amazing to cool every living space down to about 16°C. Suddenly popping out to the shops means that within 5 minutes you experience a temperature difference that most European countries get over the course of a year. You leave the cinema with icicles hanging from your nose. Your sweat-soaked shirt is frozen to your frost-bitten back, which then burns once you step out into the sun. Awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this seems perfectly plausible to the locals. My favourite remark: “But you’re from the north, you must love the cold!” No, we fricking don’t! We have heating for that, and warm clothes and vacation days! We hate the cold more than anything. So why do you do that?! Why does your office make me think of the Winter War or Stalingrad ‘42?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-ramadan&quot;&gt;It’s Ramadan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About halfway through my stay in Bahrain, Ramadan started. I was familiar with the concept on an individual level but not quite prepared for what it looks like on a societal level. For the period between 18.06. and 17.07. public life slowed down to allow the population time for introspection, their faith and reconnecting with family and loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were also not supposed to consume anything between sunrise and sunset. In Bahrain this is taken seriously as far as public life is concerned: You can’t eat in public. Or drink (even water). Or smoke. Or chew gum. Any one of those things is grounds for a stint in a cell and a hefty fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, any place serving food or drink is closed during the day. Good way to avoid temptation, I guess. But once the sun sinks below the horizon…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;food-is-amazing-i-like-food&quot;&gt;Food is amazing. I like food.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food. Oh my god, the food! As you’d expect, not eating during the day gets people quite excited about food! As a result, the meals available after sunset are just astonishing in quantity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150619_211319.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150619_211319_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;No doubt that&#39;s exactly what the inventor intended...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Bahrain is such a melting pot, the sheer variety of fantastic food also shines in terms of quality. My friends took me to one great restaurant after the other, every one of which left me grinning like an idiot. Luckily, the desert heat did little to dampen the ever-present hunger that comes with the fusion-drive that is my metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150617_160608.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150617_160608_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Mmmhhmm...cow!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahrain being a bit of a melting pot there is no shortage of cuisines to chose from: Middle eastern, American, European, Indian, Thai, you name it. Most service jobs in Bahrain are done by workers from Southeast Asia or the Philippines. Consequently, whichever cuisine you chose, the food will be served by people from that part of the world. Turkish food? Indians. American food? Indians. Indian food? Philipinos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the fantastic Indian food served at Andrew’s place to the mix and it’s a proper miracle they didn’t have to roll me back over the border. Some of my favourite treats included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Milkshake “Miley Cyrus” (Cookie dough + Reese’s Peanut Butter cups)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fresh lemon juice with mint&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cheese samosas&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tandoori fish filet&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lebanese BBQ&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So. Many. Things.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uh…excuse me for a second, I need to go find some dinner!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/11/22/bahrain_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/11/22/bahrain_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
