<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Escaping Sloth</title>
    <description>...very slowly</description>
    <link>http://escapingsloth.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://escapingsloth.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Cappadocia, part I - Invisible cities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tired, so incredibly tired. I’m writing this on a a coach which has just left Göreme and is speeding steadily towards Samsun. I spent a day hiking and exploring Cappadocia, but now I’m exhausted. The tray table is loose and rattles. In the front of a bus, a child of maybe 3 years keeps himself occupied by straight-up screaming without interruption. Might as well use the time for writing then, although the coach is expected to reach at 03:00h and that means that every minute of sleep is valuable. I certainly hope you lot appreciate my sacrifice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oh-hills&quot;&gt;Oh, hills!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left off in Ankara, where Marc and Mohamed had convinced me to forego my plan to drive to Samsun and instead travel to Cappadocia with them (by asking “Are you coming?”). So we rose nice and early, took a metro to the huge coach station and got tickets and food. Since we had such a huge safety margin in our timetable, nobody thought of looking at the clock. We effectively jumped on the coach at the very last moment. Well, the very last moment before the official departure time. The time I foolishly thought the bus would depart. The time around 15 minutes before it actually did. German time vs. Turkish time, this has been an issue a few times already…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sidenote:&lt;/strong&gt; Kids are great, aren’t they? So full of life, so much energy! Kids are our &lt;em&gt;future&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The busride from Ankara to Göreme took around four hours and I spent most of the time just staring at the fields, hills and valleys outside the window. The countryside around Ankara seems incredibly devoid of people. Much of it looks like steppe and goes on and on until it meets the wide open skies at the horizon. I would have loved to get off the bus for a moment and just stand in that seemingly endless field. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking around on the bus, most passengers were too enthralled by “Scarface” (shown in Turkish) to notice. The coach was quiet, except for an elderly gentleman whose cough made me think of a sore-throated vulture in distress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halfway through the journey we had a break at a reststop near the massive salt lake Tuz. This is where the following, highly symbolic photograph was taken by an unknown artist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_125203_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, yes, it was me. It symbolizes the salty lake-ness in which we sit. Allegorically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_125209_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we continued onwards (again, around 15 minutes late), I was left wondering: Isn’t Cappadocia known for it’s cliffs and hills and such? The landscape all around me looked mostly flat. Somewhat hilly at best. It would stay that way until we arrived in Nevşehir, where we changed buses. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way into the city we passed a huge industrial area (empty) and loads of of apartment complexes (also empty). Not a single damn person. Why is everywhere I go empty? Where did all the people go, and why? Did they know I was on my way? Are they scared?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was on that second bus that we finally got to see some cliffs and rock formations, as it hurled down the empty highway at breathtaking speed. And then we passed a bend and suddenly a valley opened up befor us. This was the “OOOOHHH!” moment we had been waiting for: In the brilliant sunshine we saw formations of pale white rock sticking out of green meadows. To me, they looked like molten icecreme - I was hungry. Everywhere I turned, bizarre formations and stony columns pointed towards the sky, surrounded by blossoming trees and bushes. The passengers on the bus went whisper-quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus left us in the centre of the small town of Göreme. The name apparently means “you can’t see me”, since the village is tucked away in a valley and is hard to see from the surrounding hills. We found our hostel fairly quickly and headed out to explore. And boy, did we find places!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disregarding the suggestions of our host, we just picked a random direction and then followed the first incline up  towards the rocky ridges surrounding the town. On the way there we stopped amazed by the stone columns which stood all over the city. Each of them was higher than the houses around it, and all of them showed various entrances, windows, pidgeonholes and staircases cut from the rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_160952_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_165859_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_161218_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we climbed up on the nearest ridge, we stood frozen for a while, just amazed by the view:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_162204_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_162822_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So-called ‘fairy chimneys’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look closely, you can see a small bird on top of one of the columns. It made a fantastically ridiculous “Whoop-whoop!” sound. I want one of those birds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_164139_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, we decided to take a shortcut back into town. This largely meant sliding down steep rocksides, some of which were clearly the ‘roofs’ of cave hotels and apartments. We had a lot of fun and nobody died, so it was worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_165457_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick dinner we walked up to the so-called sunset point, a cafe nestled on top of a cliff overlooking Göreme. The place was fairly crowded with tourists, but the view was something to behold. The three of us sat on the cliff edge and watched the sun slowly drop towards one of the table mountains around the city. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_191314_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_192905_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the sun disappeard, we remained there for a long time. The city below us turned dark and one by one, lights appeared in the darkness. Brightly lit billboards, streetlights and lights behind windows all over the city. A flock of sparrows swooped this way and that over our heads, feeding on the insects of the valley. One by one, the tourists left the sunset spot. As night fell, our seats on the cliff got colder and colder, until we decided to head back. After another quick meal, we walked back to the hostel and turned in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150430_200853_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;roadtrip&quot;&gt;Roadtrip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we walked over to a local travel agency to go on a tour of some sights. We had discussed this move before, since we would have preferred to move about independently. However, Cappadocia is a relatively large area and sparsely populated, so public transport would not be ideal. Rentals turned out to be a lot more expensive than anticipated (did somebody say rip-off?). The tour included a guide, several sights and the obligatory meal. Summing up the prices for the individual tickets and adding transportation, we figured the tour might be the cheapest way to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sidenote:&lt;/strong&gt; The kid has started imitating a police siren with impressive endurance. Not kidding, it’s actually going “BEEEEE-BOOOOOO-BEEEEEEE-BOOOOOO”. 6 minutes and counting. His parents don’t seem overly suprised. Kids are, after all, our &lt;em&gt;future&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we found ourself on a minibus with a Turkish guide from the region, some Aussies, some Kiwis, some Chinese and the three of us. The guide assigned all of us Turkish names. While Muhamad got to stick with his name, Marc and I became Ahmed and Mehmed, since we apparently looked like twins. In the manner of tour guides everywhere, ours also began flirting with one of the Chinese girls, who was not impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sidenote:&lt;/strong&gt; Aaaand now that little ~~shit~~ bundle of delight is crying. Again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the previous day had been warm and sunny, it began drizzling as soon as our bus pulled out of Göreme. Once we reached our first stop, a panorama view over a nearby valley, the light drizzle had turned into heavy - and very cold - rain. So we each took that one photo, said something to the tune of “Yeup, it’s pretty alright.” and then jogged through the downpour back to the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way to the next step, Selime Monastery, our guide explained some historical background of the area, both in terms of its history and its geology. With regards to the latter, he was able to explain the formation of those ‘fairy chimneys’: Cappadocia’s top layers consist of very dense, heavy and dark basalt rock with a layer of spongy, brittle and white tufa underneath. Wind, extreme temperature changes (-25°C in winter, +40°C in summer), rain and melting snow erode the two layers. First, they dig away at the basalt on top, leaving those characteristic conical shapes. Then they start chipping away the softer stone below. However, by then the weight of the basalt on top will have compressed the softer stone underneath. Thus, it will not erode right under the basalt cones but only around them. Over time, this leaves those characteristic formations which look like…well, like chimneys, alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_123602_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, the local people dug into them and built houses inside. Smoke rising from cooking fires throught openings at the top supposedly led travelers to believe that they were occupied by fairies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is getting late. The kid is finally asleep or passed-out or whatever. Since this article is way too wordy already, I’ll grab some shuteye now and report on the rest of our tour in a seperate post.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/01/goreme/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/01/goreme/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ankara, the Concrete Capital</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-way-in&quot;&gt;The way in&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach ride from Safranbolü to Ankara took me about three, four hours. We drove southwest towards Bolu and then southeast towards our destination. The journey took us through some beautiful mountains and plains, parts of which stil held small patches of snow. So much for my plans to travel through warm countries only…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I noticed during the drive were many small villages along the highway. Most of them looked…poor. Small cabins and sheds nailed together from driftwood and tarp. People dressed in patched, stained clothes toiling away on acres the size of tennis courts with handheld tools. Even in the small cities we passed, most houses were in various states of disrepair and trash was strewn everywhere. Trash also seamed every single meter of road, even in the otherwise most untouched places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But aboard the coach I had wifi and coffee, so that was good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view changed quickly as we approached Ankara: First, there were industrial buildings. Next came massive warehouses, then your assorted megastores and car dealerships. Before long, I saw the city. Ankara is somewhat larger than Izmir and it looks very different. Since the development of Ankara as the capital took place within the last 90 years, the city appears incredibly modern. More modern in fact than any city in, say, Germany. Wherever I looked, I saw shiny, new towers of glass and steel, and more were being built all over the city. Just to give an impression of the developments going on there: When the Republic of Turkey was founded in 1923, its new capital had about 35,000 residents. In 1950, it still had less than 300,000 residents. Today it has 5 million. And it didn’t look like they were going to run out of money or hunger for growth anytime soon. The contrast between this and the countryside I’d just passed through could not have been more striking. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach took us past several parks and military installations before reaching the coach station. Again, the coach company provided a handy - and free! - shuttle service to the city centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shuttle itself was easy enough to find: I walked up to the tourist information and grabbed a map. The attendant pointed me towards a carpark full of shuttles. Waving the map energetically, I walked up to a group of teenagers outside and quickly learned which shuttle I needed to get on. This was done by pointing at spots on the map, grunting and waving my hands about. Works like a charm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 0089:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;English. By and large, they don’t speak it here. They teach it as a mandatory class in school, which apparently does a sterling job of turning people off of ever learning the basics. Outside the tourist-y places, speaking English didn’t get me very far. Pointing and grunting did. Generally, the young are more likely to understand English than the old. Those of the female persuasion often seem to speak better English than those of male, but are also more hesitant about starting to speak it. While this whole thing is a bit inconvenient at times, it’s not really a hindrance. At first I got a bit frustrated when they would just keep talking at me in Turkish, even though I very clearly did not understand them…then it occured to me that I was doing the exact same thing in English. Anyway, before you come, download the offline language pack for Google Translate and you’ll be golden.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I hadn’t planned on coming to Ankara, I had neglected to look up a hostel. So I grabbed a quick meal and found myself a nice cafe with wifi. After finding a hostel and reading for a bit, I walked over the hostel, got a bed and stashed my belongings. Then I went out to explore the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;underrated&quot;&gt;Underrated!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The late afternoon found me walking north through the city center and up into the neighbourhood of the university. Past a concert hall advertising its rendition of ‘Carmen’ and through a nice little park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150427_191437_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150427_191346_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150427_191637_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150427_191921_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150427_191422_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it me or does that fountain look like a cat on a bicycle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I made the acquaintance of an Australian hostel guest (Hi, Marc!), and through him I also met a Yemeni pilot  (Hi, Mohamed!) who was actually living in Turkey. Together we did some more meandering in the city. For example, we visited Kocatepe Mosque, the biggest mosque in Ankara. Marc and I were a bit surprised to learn that the mosque actually had a shopping centre in its basement. Yeup, didn’t see that coming. Despite this somewhat strange property arrangement, the mosque itself is beautiful: Serene on the outside, ornate and lofty on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150428_134359_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;gt;The mosque in question. It’s big.&amp;lt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150428_134752_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also big on the inside, and rather pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed the evening in a bar which had beer and nargile. You know, that pipe-thingy with the hose-thingies, which people think won’t kill them because the water miraculously filters out all the cancer…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-castle&quot;&gt;A castle!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we decided to go climb up to Ankara’s castle. The castle is well-positioned on a hill overlooking much of the city and actually so old nobody has dated its construction with any certainty. When the Galatians turned up around 300 BCE, they found the castle and started using it for themselves. So there is that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150429_155102_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does everything have to be either an incline or stairs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The castle is also located in a part of town which a friend of mine (Hallo, Holger!) called “historical” and which I would call “shitty”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150429_155603_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150429_161738_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up in the castle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150429_162742_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View down from the castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the castle there wasn’t a whole lot to do, besides take in the view or have coffee in a cafe tucked away in the corner. After a while we got bored and headed back down into town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-way-out&quot;&gt;The way out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening, Mohamed was due to go back to Istanbul, while Marc would leave for Pammukale the next morning. I myself was planning on taking a bus to Amasya or Samsun the next morning as well. I split for a few hours to do sort out some documents for my tax return in a cafe(the dreamy life of the traveler: “Glistening beaches. Dusty winding roads. Smiling locals. Tax deduction with original receipts only.”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I got back, I asked whether the two of them had managed to get their coach tickets. They had. Kinda. More on that in the next article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A word on Ankara:&lt;/strong&gt; Many people, both locals and foreigners, seem to dislike the capital. Unlike Istanbul Ankara has few truly ancient ruins or monuments. Instead, its history is the history of the Republic (coincidence, do you think?), which is fairly recent. Not much older than the house I grew up in, in fact. So there is that. Unlike so many other places in Turkey, the landscape is not spectacular. It doesn’t even have beaches. People  bemoan the lack of nightlife and entertainment. This seems plausible as a large share of the population are administrators and bureaucrats, whose notion of a. exciting evening out means filing taxes in a cafe. Yes, I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all those factors aside, Ankara seems to be a city that works. It’s organized. It’s clean. It has all the trappings of progress and civilization. It is clearly a place where people go to get stuff done. And even in this terribly functional city you find really nice spots - just look at the pictures! So if you find yourself in the area, give it a try! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/30/ankara/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/30/ankara/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Safranbolü</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not convinced this stop on my journey really deserves an article of its own. Largely, because I felt like I wasted two days of my life there. Then again, I’m sitting in a hotel room right now and I don’t have more pressing things to do. It’s one of those days where you might stuff your face with a load of chicken nuggets and then wash that down with a beer or two while watching an entire season of 30 Rock. Oh wait, that’s exactly what I just did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here is how it came to be:
I got bored in Istanbul and decided to head further eastwards. Some research on wikivoyage.org (the open-source successor of wikitravel, which apparently is a commerical platform now) brought up a few options along Turkey’s Black Sea coast. One of them was a village called Safranbolü, around 6 hours from Istanbul. The direction was right and apparently the town is UNESCO World Heritage because they have original Ottoman houses (and Turkey’s 4th biggest cave!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place also looked pretty on Google Image search, so I packed my bag in the late afternoon. Then I headed to the coach station (Otogar Baglanti Yolu) in the western part of Istanbul. I bought a ticket and spent two hours waiting in a departure lounge. Long waiting times have been pretty common for me. Making the best of delays is a valuable skill on a trip like this. Then again, I’m not in a rush, which helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That waiting-skill became useful during the trip as well, since the first 90 minutes were spent in Istanbul rush-hour traffic. Had I been smarter, I would have taken the tram to one of the &lt;em&gt;eastern&lt;/em&gt; coach stations and saved myself some of the slowest stop-and-go I have ever seen. On the plus side, taking a tour through the Asian side of Istanbul was impressive: Everything is built up, and yet they keep building more skyscapers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we exited the city, darkness fell quickly so I won’t be able to provide a description of the landscape. My guess would be gently swooping hills though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our journey we passed the city of Izmit (not to be confused with Izmir), of which I only saw a huge raffinery, lit up like a christmas tree and belching out burning gas from several chimneys (I really hope that was by design…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next five hours on the bus listening to music and napping. In the end, we arrived around 01:00h at night. I grabbed a shuttle bus to town (which didn’t look terribly interesting) and then a short cab ride to the old town (which looked interesting enough). Initially I had considered saving the cab fare and walking instead. That would have been an unfortunate choice, since the distance turned out a lot longer than anticipated. Mostly, because half of the drive took us down a spiraling path into the centre of a dark, pit-like valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The owner of an inn showed me to my room in one of the original Ottoman houses. A building built with lots of wood and carpets. Almost every surface was carpeted, which made the place feel very cozy. After a quick tour of the facilities, I went to bed and slept like a stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning I asked my host to show me the shower. He revealed quite an interesting setup: You know those squatting toilets? Hole-in-the-ground model? The ones we just don’t &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; in The West? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_181246_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This picture was actually taken at a restaurant, but you get the idea)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the shower was this, plus a shower head. A small room of 1.5 x 1.5m, the showerhead, the hole-in-the-ground and no window. After overcoming my initial confusion, I managed to take a shower of sorts and also flooded the entire room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I understand that the UNESCO award probably discourages architectural innovations in Safranbolü. Fair enough. Yet I have seen the same setup in several newer buildings since. That just leads me to ask: WHY? Is it some sentimental attachment to the oh-so-quaint past? Mindless conservatism in sanitary engineering? We moved past this! Past the hole-in-the-ground, past flooding the entire bathroom by taking a shower. We moved past it, because it was rubbish. Get with the program, Turkey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I went out to take a look at the city and get breakfast. The town was…old. That much was clear. The good parts around the centre were old and nice. Two- and three-storey houses built from dark wood and whitewashed stone walls. Some restaurants and many stores. Safranbolü was, in its day, an important trading post, where Saffron was grown and traded. Consequently, everything you can buy there is Saffron-this or Saffron-that. You name it, somebody found a way of putting Saffron in it. I will give them credit for Saffron-flavoured Turkish Delight though, that stuff is delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_104251_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_193605_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the less-good parts of town were old and crap. Decrepit, dilapidated buildings. Broken windows, wonky doors. Rusting carcasses of cars left on the roadside, from where they would never move again on their own (I hope). Garbage strewn about the neighbourhood. I quickly made my way through this area and out into the countryside surrounding the village. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the sun broke through the cloud cover, I began to enjoy myself. My walk led me to a tall fence at the foot of a hill. A gate in the fence stood open. I followed the path to a sign advertising a cafe, and then onwards from there. Suddenly I noticed that the ground to the left of the path dropped away into nothingness. Confused, I walked over and found myself looking down into a deep gorge, with water running along the bottom. The further I followed the gorge, the deeper and wider it became, until I saw the very cafe I was looking for nestled deep down in the canyon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_105733_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_105808_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150426_105758_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s how I ended up having breakfast in a canyon! After taking a look around the gorge, I strode back into town and did some shopping. Later that day I walked up to one of the hills surrounding the old town and had a look at the historical clocktower there. No pictures, you know what that means. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was going to get dark soon, I opted to forego a visit to Turkey’s 4th largest cave. Instead, I chose to take a look around some of the historic homes in town. To my disappointment, they looked almost exactly like the inn I was staying at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning I slept in. It didn’t help that the room I was staying in had no window, so I couldn’t get out of bed until 10:00h. Still somewhat drowsy I grabbed all my belongings and squeezed them into my backpack. Then I sat on it until I the zippers on the compartments would close. I shambled to the old town centre and got on a minibus to the coach station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had decided to try my luck in Amasya next, a scenic little town on a river. Unfortunately, there were only two coaches on that route on any given day (“Amasya? No. No. Morning Amasya, no. Evening Amasya, yes.”). I had missed the first coach by around an hour and wasn’t too keen to wait until the evening for the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The friendly attendant suggested I could also take a coach to Ankara, the much-maligned capital, and then continue from there. That coach was about to leave in ten minutes though. So I looked back and forth between the map and the idling coach standing in the parking lot. In the end, I said “Yeah, why not?”, shouldered my bag and got on the bus. And you won’t believe what happened next!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there, I just wrote around 1300 words on a city I didn’t want to bring up in the first place. Amazing, what you can accomplish with boredom and beer!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/29/safranbolu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/29/safranbolu/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Istanbul, again</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Him: “So what’s that tattoo say?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: “Well, it used to say ‘Curt’, my ex’s name.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Him: “And now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: “Now it says…something similar. Still reminds me of him, too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Overheard in a hostel lounge)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahhh, Istanbul! Beating heart of empires past! A city built, cultivated, pillaged, burnt and then rebuilt. And then pillaged and burnt again. An immense melting pot with millenia-long history, steeped in an air of timelessness. Full of cats, too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached Istanbul after a 7-hour overnight bus ride. While the coaches are comfortable enough, sleeping is almost impossible because they stop often. Lights are turned on and announcements are made. People shuffle on or off the bus. People who seriously need to learn to shut the hell up. The journey was a fairly disorientating experience of drifting between wakefulness and sleep. At some point somebody shook me awake, repeating “Istanbul, Istanbul!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I took the hint and stumbled off the bus out into a grey-ish dawn, clutching my backpack and travel blanket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 008:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Get a travel blanket! Mine is almost full-sized but very thin, so it’s compact. It’s nice to have something to keep you warm or keep the light out of your eyes. Whichever bed I go to sleep in, once I spread out&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;blanket, it becomes&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;bed. Rolled up in a ziploc-bag it compresses a lot and stays dry, too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Istanbul is home to around 14 million people, it has at least four large coach stations. Helpfully, the coach driver had woken me at the one closest to the area I was going to stay in, called Sultanahmet. At this hour however, the massive coach station was deserted. The sun was not up yet, so the entire site was grey buildings, grey tarmac and grey skies. I shouldered my backpack and just walked around for a few minutes to see where exactly I had to go. It turned out that the station was around 11-12 subway stops away from where I wanted to go. Since the metro seemed like the easiest mode of transport anyway, I went looking for the metro station. Just like your typical bloody tourist would, I ended up wandering all over the coach station, mistakenly walking into at least one storage building and one underground garage. I finally found the metro station (cleverly hidden right in the middle of the coach station). From there, it was a relatively straight forward trip east towards Sultanahmet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150419_181125_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sultanahmet, the east-most part of the city’s European half, is its oldest and most famous district. It contains the Hagia Sophia, the Blue Mosque, the ancient Hippodrome, the Topkapi Palace and several museums. It is the most tourist-y part of town with many hotels and hostels. It is also where I found &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; hostel, which I immediately identified as such because they had kittens!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think that cats are alright. Sure, I took a few pictures. But it’s not like I’m a crazy cat person with dozens of pictures of kittens on their phone. Just a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150424_230757_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150419_071918_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150419_223358_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, one more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150420_153635_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there such a thing as a “cat habit”? You know, like a “coke habit”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed in Istanbul for five or six days (no, I really can’t tell). Since I had been to the city before, I had gotten most of the big sights out of the way already. So this time around I spend most days just walking around and exploring the more lived-in districts. Ironically, I took no pictures there, so here are some more common views instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150420_181632_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150420_181328_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150421_185657_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On most days this meant 6-hour walks. On two days, the weather was actually so terrible that I barely left the hostel, except for food/coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150422_125934_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeup, that’s sleet. From the thunderstorm which nearly flooded Gülhane Park in a torrential downpour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the hostel I also spent time with a group of other travelers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An Australian solicitor (Hi, David!)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Another Aussie and his Kiwi friend who were in town for ANZAC day&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A couple from Boston&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A data analyst from London (Hi, Paul!)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also used the occasion to visit the famous Topkapi palace, which I hadn’t seen during my last trip. The palace is a mindbogglingly ornate affair located at the northern tip of Sultanahmet. It served as residence of the Ottoman sultans 15th-19th century. Today, it’s a UNESCO site with lots of visitors and almost as many selfie-sticks. Seriously, people: You have arms, right? What the hell is the world coming to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150422_172556_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150422_172644_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150422_173056_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150422_175536_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember being thoroughly impressed by two exhibits in the palace:
Firstly, the scrolls and calligraphy in the privies. The amount of detail in the carvings above pales in comparison with the granularity and precision shown in the religious manuscripts. Unfortunately I did not take any pictures of them, but their effect is startling: You tend to get lost in the levels of detail. Every pattern is made up of smaller, more intricate patterns, which in turn contain their own symmetries and rules. Taking pictures of these with a cellphone camera seemed a bit pointless…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the religious artifacts in the Chamber of Sacred Relics. It’s not every day that you get to see Moses’ very own staff! You’d think that even by conservative estimates of biodegradation, that thing would be gone by now. But no, there it is! They also have Abraham’s saucepan™. I had been told of this unique item before, still I felt incredibly privileged to find myself in the company of such distinguished cookware. I didn’t take pictures of those, you’ll have to go see them yourselves. Or google it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I also found myself in a Turkish heavy metal bar. I know, but the band did play some great covers of Led Zeppelin, Megadeth and Anthrax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Istanbul is obviously a colourful city with a rich history. Exploring its facets as a tourist is an amazing experience and I’m sure I will come back here. At the same time, the second trip here showed me some of the more mundane, less exciting aspects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer number of people and extent of the city feel suffocating at times. The districts feel like they are just going on and on and on. For most people, living here seems a trade-off: Either you sacrifice a sizable share of your income to rent a centrally-located apartment, or you spend hours of your life commuting through traffic the consistency of jam mixed with bunker fuel. Two examples: One, even on the busiest highways around the city you find men selling bottled water and pretzels while standing right between the lanes. That sounds risky, but there really is no danger to them, since traffic barely moves at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two, when I eventually took a coach to Safranbolü, 90 minutes of the six-hour ride were spent just on getting out of Istanbul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This being the capital, most things tend to be just a little more expensive than in other parts of the country. Food, drink, fares, you name it. Both in Izmir and in Ankara I spoke to locals who had at some points in there lives moved to Istanbul. They all told me that they had moved back for a higher quality of life and standard of living. Counterpoint: I also met plenty of people in Istanbul who had moved there and had no plans of moving away again, because, you know, it’s Istanbul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While those realizations were sobering, they did reassure me that coming back and taking a look behind all those important sights was worthwhile: I only noticed those things because I spent more time here and had the leisure to observe in peace. If you only come to Istanbul for a few days, by all means take in all those magnificent buildings and museums, they are worth your time. But then make time to come here again, and use it to meandre around the city. Have coffee somewhere and have a look around. Go to the less pretty parts of town and soak up all the glances which say “The hell are you doing here?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days however, I happened to look at a world map in the hostel. And then at a calendar. I got angsty, so I packed my bag, did some hasty research and took a tram to the coach station. Eastwards! Actually, the coach station was west, which turned out to be a stupid mistake, as you’ll see…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/28/istanbul/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/28/istanbul/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Izmir, again</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I left Greece with the confidence that I had gained deep and meaningful insights into the psyche of its culture, history and people. Unfortunately, I can’t exactly remember any of them right now, so let’s just move on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bodrum&quot;&gt;Bodrum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s also what I did, leaving Kos on a completely unspectacular little boat on a somewhat overcast day. It took that boat almost an hour to reach the Turkish coast and the city of Bodrum. I spent that time on deck, with a beer in my hand and the wind in my hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow it had completely slipped my mind that Turkey is not part of the Schengen Agreement, so the passport control at the pier took me by surprise. Then again, German citizens get in without a visa or anything. Beautiful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note: Next time you go through passport control, pay close attention to the officer at the counter. The instant you hand them your passport, they will be completely puzzled for a second. I can only assume that the following thought process takes place: “Huh, what am I supposed to do with this? …Oh, right. I work for the border patrol, I’m supposed to check those things.”
Every. Single. Time. The more often I observe this phenomenon, the funnier it gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleared to enter the country I had a quick look around the port area and the center of Bodrum. Then I hastily walked towards the coach station. Looking at the crowds of early-bird tourists I felt no urgent need to stay in Bodrum any longer than I had to. So instead, I took a coach to Izmir straight away. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it hypocritical that the sight of tourists makes me run for the hills, given that I’m clearly a tourist myself? There, I said it: I’m a tourist. Not going to waste time trying to polish that turd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride from Bodrum to Izmir took about 4 hours on a nice, new coach which was effectively empty. Once we left Bodrum, I was instantly reminded why I had wanted to go back to Turkey: Holy hell, the Turkish Riviera is beautiful! I sat on this airconditioned, wifi-enabled gem of a coach and watched the sun set over a ragged coastline, sloping hills and a mountain highway. For most of that drive I struggled to keep my mouth closed and my nose from leaving prints on the windows. The fields and woods outside were showing incredible hues of green. Every single tree and bush seemed to be blooming. Meadows and hillsides shone in the last rays of sunlight and looked almost unnaturally &lt;em&gt;green&lt;/em&gt;. So &lt;em&gt;green&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;izmir&quot;&gt;Izmir&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached Izmir around 11pm. The last time I had been here I had seen the coach station, a hotel and the airport. Then it was just a layover on the way to Istanbul, but this time I wanted to explore the city, too. From what I saw, it certainly offered many, many shades of beige.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach operater (Metro) offers free shuttle buses from the often remote coach stations to the city center. Hooray for shiny coaches! Since I had looked up a hostel beforehand, I got the driver to let me out of the shuttle at Basmane Square:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: &lt;em&gt;points and grunts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driver: &lt;em&gt;grunts questioningly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: &lt;em&gt;grunts affirmatively&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driver: &lt;em&gt;opens door&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: &lt;em&gt;grunts gratefully&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had a look around, I actually remembered the square from my last stay. Then I walked north towards the hostel, along the giant Kültürpark and into a part of town which is basically just one giant high street. From there I took a sideroad and ended up at the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Izmir is Turkey’s 3rd largest city (after Istanbul and Ankara) with a population of around 4 million and about 4000 years of history. Unfortunately a combination of earthquakes, petty wars and the occasional kitchen fire getting out of hand left the city without many historical sights. On the other hand, Izmir is a very modern and open city with a fairly young population. Quality of life there seemed pretty high: The city is smaller and cheaper than Istanbul, while being just as worldly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next four days I would stay in Izmir, take long walks around the city and study at coffee shops. I would also, for once, not look at ancient stuff, since there wasn’t any. I stayed at that first hostel which I had booked online - chosen due to its good reviews. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using those booking sites has been a mixed experience: Recently I’ve grown more and more frustrated with them. There is a plethora of sites such as booking.com, hostels.com, hostelworld.com and hostelbookers.com. All of them have review mechanisms and rankings for hostels. Yet, for every well-rated hostel that deserved its laurels, I’ve stayed at one which simply did not. Another big drawback is that booking a hostel via one of those sites locks in the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 007:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Booking sites obviously charge a commission, which we supposedly pay for convenience and validation through reviews. Yet if the convenience makes my travel plan less flexible, and the reviews are not reliable, what exactly am I paying for? Here is what I recommend instead:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look up a few suitable places online.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upon arrival, take a look at those hostels and the neighbourhood.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Walk in through the door, ask about vacancies and have them show you some of their rooms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask them about the price per night.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask: “Could I pay [75% of that]?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store your bag and go spend the money you just saved on coffee!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Izmir, my exploits mainly consisted of walking around the city and chugging liters of coffee at coffee shops on the promenade. Neither of those lends itself to terribly impressive pictures, so here are few generic ones instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150416_192251_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The promenade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150416_114732_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like that people in Turkey actually take care of the stray cats and dogs. Looking at you, Greece!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150416_115507_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This left me giggling for at least five minutes. Mainly because of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5nRzh4CJTZs&quot;&gt;this clip from the show Community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, even at mediocre hostels you meet interesting people. Case in point: I spend a day with a delightful couple from Australia and two students from the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150418_194815_1_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days, I got restless in Izmir. Looking at a map I began to hear Istanbul calling, and that call just didn’t feel like it could be denied. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/26/izmir/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/26/izmir/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My personal Grexit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since Kos was the last destination in Greece, I should probably wrap up my experience there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-pre-season-for-a-reason&quot;&gt;It’s pre-season for a reason&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, I was there at the wrong time. Well, technically every Greek person assured me that normally the weather isn’t this bad this time of year. The effect was the same though: I remember being cold more often than being warm. I also used my rainjacket way more than my sunscreen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, being there before all the tourists was a blessing. Especially on the islands many locals told us various horror-stories about the numbers of tourists that would descend on the small towns like drunk, sunburned and tattooed locusts. If that’s not your thing - it certainly isn’t mine - than you really want to go to the islands outside of main season. Given my experience with the weather, I would probably prefer to go post-season rather than pre-season. That way, the weather might be a bit more predictable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nobody-told-me-they-hated-me&quot;&gt;Nobody told me they hated me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, at least not to my face. Coming from Germany, I had some mild reservations about going to Greece. “Sorry your economy is in the toilet, but isn’t it lovely how cheap everything is?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow this never came up. I didn’t even see any riots in Athens, which was a bit of a letdown, really. No burning flags or Merkel effigies either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had several conversations with locals about the whole topic (mostly young people). The consensus there seemed to be that the whole Euro-kerfuffle was a thing of politics, and politics were always fucked up. You know, the elites oppressing the little people like you and I. But you and I, we get along just fine, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand that was reassuring to hear. On the other hand, I could not help but wonder if the fact that I sat right across from them may have moderated their positions a bit. Maybe they they secretly harbored more negative opinions? After all, I couldn’t really blame them for being angry about the economic situation. One way or another, people were consistently friendly, so I have no complaints there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;everybody-here-should-be-fat&quot;&gt;Everybody here should be fat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right at the start of my trip, in Thessaloniki, I asked the hostel staff to recommend a restaurant. “You like meat?” they asked back. Those words warmed my heart. Why yes, I do! And meat likes me! Meat and I are made for each other!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a meat perspective, Greece was all I could have asked it to be. Grilled, fried, cooked, you name it. Meat of course does not make anyone fat. Virtually anything else served here does. The sheer variety of pies, puff pastries and sugary desserts would be enough to give a heart attack a bad case of the beetus (sic). Yet, you rarely see overweight people. Certainly none of the towering hamplanets you tend to get in some Anglosaxon countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One explanation must be that most of Greece is built on hills. So whereever you go, you’re either working your way up an incline or doing your best not to fall down one. The other explanation might lie in portion control. Most foreigners clearly sucked at that: On one occasion, two Americans and I devoured a huge serving of juicy, sugary baclava right in the bakery. The digusted look the owner gave us had “You animals!” written all over it. I think we may have obliterated what was meant to be a family serving…each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The locals seem to pace themselves a bit better: Most restaurants offer decent servings but nothing excessive. Many of the locals tend to consume various greenery with their meat. Maybe that’s their secret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;damn-its-a-beautiful-country&quot;&gt;Damn, it’s a beautiful country&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even ignoring all other benefits Greece has to offer, the nature alone would compel me to go again. I didn’t see a single part (excluding Patisia, Athens) that wasn’t beautiful in some way. You know what I’m talking about, you saw the pictures! Hills, mountains, rivers, cliffs, fields, and of course the sea. Oh, the sea! If nothing else, go there for the sea!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/21/my-personal-grexit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/21/my-personal-grexit/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kos</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;grumpy-mornings&quot;&gt;Grumpy mornings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last leg of my journey through Greece I took a ferry from Santorini to the island of Kos. Kos is actually so close to the Turkish coast that most people tend to assume the island is part of Turkey. It is also what you might call a tourist shithole. But since it was pre-season still, I resolved to try my luck before escaping to Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I ended up taking a ferry from Santorini close to one o’clock in the morning. As I had chosen the cheapest ticket, I did not get a cabin like a civilized person would. Instead I boarded the ferry (yes, shiny blue ferry!) with a handful of bleary-eyed tourists and began looking for a cushioned, flat surface. The ferry had come all the way from Athens and stopped at several islands. Consequently, all the good spots were already taken. I resigned myself to a short stretch of couch I extended with a heavy high-backed chair. Voila!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fleece rolled up as a pillow, rainjacket as a blanket and earplugs to give me peace and quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 005:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Earplugs! Unlike most of the other lessons, this is one I actually learned a while back. You can’t travel without earplugs. Maybe you think you can, because you’re an exceptionally heavy sleeper. But some day you’ll sleep in a dorm with a Romanian truck driver. Or on a boat with a broken muffler. Or there is a noisy civil war going on. In any of those cases, earplugs will keep you from rising grumpy.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rose &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; grumpy. In part, because the entire night Greek action movies were blaring from a nearby TV and the occasial explosion must have reached my ear. Mostly though, because I knew we would arrive around 04:30h. Somehow knowing that I get to sleep very little makes it impossible for me to get any sleep whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all I was not at my best as a grabbed my possessions and trudged down the stairs to the ferry’s gangway…at 04:30h. I remember standing inside the neon-lit belly of the ferry and viciously chewing on a piece of gym. Amidst the cars stood other passengers, few of them looked well-rested. Most of them must have felt just as exhausted as I did, but I was tired and therefor pissed off, so I glared at them angrily anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon a klaxon rang out and the loading gate was lowered with an unnecessary amount of noise. Stupid klaxon, stupid loading gate. Looking out, Kos didn’t seem like anything special. Stupid Kos. Then again, I only saw the outlines of some buildings and a few yellow-ish streetlights. For a moment I was wondering: Why do I do this again?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, my arrival protocol consists of sitting down for a cup of coffee and taking a moment to gather my wits. At 04:30h in the morning this wasn’t really an option and my wits felt pretty far gone anyway. Since I didn’t think I’d be able to check into any rooms, I decided to go for a walk around the port instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grumpiness nonwithstanding, I began to wonder if I was onto something as I noticed the massive ancient stonewalls surrounding part of the port. Intrigued I took some detours and found myself striding through a silent park and through gates in the walls. The air was cool and rich with the smell of blooming trees and bushes. Just as I reached the other side of the port, the horizon lit up. I found myself staring at the sun rising over the Turkish coast in the distance. For half an hour I just stood there, watching as the sunlight washed over the harbor, the marina and the small cafes and restaurants on the promenade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_060416_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_061419_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_061936_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, THIS is why I’m doing this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly a lot less grumpy, I wandered off towards the city centre, along the beach. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_064703_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_065408_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, right here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considerably reassured about the purpose of my travels I found a place renting out apartments and sat down on the stairs overlooking the still street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, a stately-looking lady opened the door and invited me in. Through a mixture of my roguish charme, my pityfully exhausted appearance and the fact that it was still pre-season, I managed to haggle the price down to half. And thus I got two nights in a double for 20 euros. After dumping my stuff I went for a walk and got breakfast. Then I took a long, luxurious nap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lazy-days&quot;&gt;Lazy days&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I basically continued that nap, with minor interruptions, for two more days. Whenever I accidentally woke from my slumber - pesky biorythm! - I would go for a walk. The town looked about as empty as my brain felt, so I mostly stuck to the equally deserted beach. I passed the time wandering along the waterline and skipping flat stones over the waves. This mindless process of “See stone” -&amp;gt; “Grab stone” -&amp;gt; “Throw stone” -&amp;gt; “Repeat” proved almost meditative. Time begins to slow and eventually breaks down around you when you’re looking for that perfect stone and that perfect pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point I foolishly attempted to streamline the logistics by gathering a big pile of suitable stones and then chucking them all in quick succession. Of course that’s a hugely efficient and Germanic thing to do. It also totally defeats the purpose of the exercise and almost left me with a dislocated shoulder. After that experience I ended up throwing with my weaker, left arm, which must have looked every bit as spastic as you would think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 006:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The secret to good skipping lies in both the stone and the throwing movement. You want a stone which is smooth and flat-ish. A certain amount of rounded bevel is necessary for it to skip upon contact with the waves, so shards of ceramic or flint don’t work. I find that a slightly oblong shape of about 8-10cm provides better leverage for my fingers, resulting in better spin and thus more jumps. For the throw, I prefer a looping sideways pitch with a neutral grip. Haha, did you suckers really just spend 3 minutes reading about a guy chucking rocks in the sea?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recall taking a long walk through Kos’ impressive marina. The entire thing was a charming mixture of clear blue water and…well, lots of boats. I don’t really know anything about boats. Most of them where white, relatively shiny and somewhere between “somewhat large” and “definitely very large indeed”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_095450_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_095444_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you think this thing would be fast?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking decidedly out of place I resolved to walk around very purposefully. I also spent some serious time devising witty answers in case anybody asked me which one of the boats was mine. “Oh, just browsing, really. You got anything you’d recommend for whaling?”
Unfortunately, I must have walked so purposefully that people were just too intimidated to stop and ask me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not ashamed to admit that the days in Kos were anything but productive (though I did manage to watch a series of videos on relational algebra). I’m lazy, so sue me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two days I began to feel that particular itch in my bones, telling me to move on. So I took a ferry from Kos over to Bodrum, Turkey. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/20/kos/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/20/kos/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stranded, part III - Look at that water! Look at it!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;eastersaturday&quot;&gt;Easter…Saturday?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day after all the sparks and stuff was pretty low-key. I recall spending most of the day either reading, eating or napping. Judging from my photographs of that day, I must have spent a good share of the day with a cat sleeping on my chest. A recurring theme: I’m writing these lines with a 6-week old kitten sleeping snuggled in my fleece jacket. Don’t believe me? Joke’s on you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150420_153626_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we wanted to go see the fireworks. A guy working at the hostel had gotten us all excited about it. He used the words “homemade bombs” and “loud as hell”, so of course we wanted to go. He had even shown us a few videos from his hometown, which really did look like the world was coming to an end in a hurricane of colourful lights and explosions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the evening we gathered the group from the night before (plus a few additions) and sauntered over to the cliff to watch the sunset. It did indeed set, and it was magnificent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I remember - I really need to start writing these articles in a more timely fashion - we went out for a drink afterwards. At midnight - I think - we went up to the biggest church in Fira to see the ceremony. A crowd was already waiting, holding unlit candles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a procession exited the curch and sang a song or two, they began lighting candles from a candle brought from the church. No ordinary flame this, but a descendant of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holy_Fire&quot;&gt;Holy Fire&lt;/a&gt;. Yep, brought from the grave of Jesus Christ by the orthodox patriarch himself. A miracle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pilgrims and clergy claim that the Holy Fire does not burn them.” (So quoted on Wikipedia) 
That’s just asking for it, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I digress. The flame was handed out to the crowd accompanied by cheering, hugging and some more singing. Then the fireworks began: Teenagers began throwing firecrackers into the church yard. Amplified by the building, one loud BANG after another rang out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that was it. For a moment we were left wondering when the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; fireworks would start. No, that was it. Even without the high expectations after the night before this would have been a let-down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this trip I’ve indiscriminately taken pictures of almost everything. Not of this ceremony though, which should tell you something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shaking our heads - and in two cases clutching our holy candles - we headed back towards the bars, eventually ending the night in an Irish pub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;easter-sunday&quot;&gt;Easter Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning the common room was quiet. Most of our group had ended the evening rather late and were still out of commission. The few survivors - the dauntless Finn and his Spanish friend - suggested heading for Oia. We walked around for a spell and I used the opportunity to re-shoot all the rainy pictures I had taken when I was there with my friend Holger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_124956_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_125904_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow we figured it might be fun to take a small boat to  the island of Thirasia which was visible in the distance (previous picture, island on the upper right). So we began to look for a path down to the small port. The path we found consisted of a long series of looping, serpentine stairs. Sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This descent was a bit more hurried though, as we saw a small boat approaching the port from the direction of Thirasia. This being a public holiday, we figured that missing that particular boat could well mean not getting another chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_130851_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_131058_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from one local, we were the only passengers as the small boat set off and zipped across the waves to Thirasia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_131346_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arrival, Thirasia looked like it had been left there by somebody and then forgotten. The port was somewhat charming with its sleepy looks, but empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had lunch in a restaurant right on the beach. The place was somewhat minimalist (little furniture, fewer guests), and the owner had the dirtiest hands I have ever seen on a human being. He turned out to be incredibly friendly (I think he was - we couldn’t really find a language we shared) and the Easter lamb that was served was delicious. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_135832_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exhibit A: Before roast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_135836_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exhibit B: After roast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a generous meal and an even more generous helping of various desserts, our host offered to drive us to town. In many ways it seems to be true that the further you get off the mainstream destinations, the more helpful and friendly people become. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a scenic drive to the centre of the island our host bid us farewell in the middle of what he called “the capital”. Of the 200 people living on that island, we saw maybe six. So we spent around half an hour milling about town until we got bored and decided to hike back to the harbor to catch the boat back to Oia. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended up seeing more donkeys than we saw people. Even finding something to drink turned out to be impossible, since the few people we saw insisted their restaurants were closed, and the donkeys had no suggestions either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_145414_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Properly roasted by the sun we arrived back at the harbor. The lure of that azure-blue water was just impossible to resist, so Jarno and I decided to go for a quick swim. Just to give you an impression:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_162035_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The water here must have been around 2-2.5m deep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we made our way back to the pier, where we boarded the boat together with a group of French hikers, most of them quite middle-aged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we reached the port on Oia, this fact would become a bit embarrassing. The group of what should have been grey panthers began to attack the stairs with the dexterity of mountain goats, quickly overtaking us. In our defense: It was really hot, the stairs were steep and…yeah, there is no excuse, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed the phenomenal view from a cafe over drinks before heading back to Fira. There, we met up with the rest of our group and had a delightful dinner of even more lamb, followed by a few relaxed beers. Around midnight I said my goodbyes before taking a bus to the ferry terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My extended stay on Santorini came to an end as the ferry (once again one of the shiny ones!) docked at the pier just shy of one o’clock. When the storm first screwed up my travel plans, I had been a bit annoyed. Seeing the Easter celebrations and spending the weekend with an amazing group of people changed my attitude considerably. That’s the good thing about poor plans: They can only get better!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/18/easter2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/18/easter2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stranded, part II - The Easter Bunny is an arsonist!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;These orthodox Greeks have their own Easter which apparently takes place a week after, well, normal Easter. Since I was going to be stuck on the island until Sunday night, I tried to see as much of the celebrations as possible. In practice, that meant three parts, starting with lots of fire on Good Friday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my donkey-themed excursion, the afternoon found me reading - being useless - in the hostel. The charming Finnish gentleman I had met there pointed out that the locals were famous for their Good Friday celebration in the village of Pyrgos. From Google Image Search I knew that this festivity consisted of them decorating all the roofs with candles right after dark. A procession would then head down from the church on the peak of the hill down into town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pyrgos was around 6km from our hostel. Of course we would have loved to walk, but with sundown approaching quickly, we’d have to take a cab. Bad luck. The Norwegian we had befriended at the hostel agreed to join us, leaving one seat in the taxi free. In the interest of saving money, we also shanghai’ed two Canadian backpackers (“Oy, there’s going to be fire on a hill. You should come!”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approaching Pyrgos, we immediately saw the hilltop sticking out of the landscape. Since the sun was still up and there weren’t too many people around, we decided to walk up to the peak to take a look. As most organically grown Greek towns, the area consisted of houses built on top of and into each other with tiny, narrow walkways and stairs leading through this maze. The closer we got to the peak, the more urgently we were reminded of the storm which whistled around the walls and corners of the tiny houses. Eventually we ascended a stairway and found ourselves on the flat roof right next to the main church. Here, the gusts were so strong that we had trouble standing or walking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking that maybe, just maybe the wind wasn’t strong enough were we stood, we climbed up to the flat roof of the church on the top of the hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a few pictures of the sunset but they turned out blurry, since I simply could not stand still in that wind. My Finnish friend did a little better, so I’ll just post his pictures instead (thanks, Jarno!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/P4100112_scaled.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/P4100107_scaled.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_193452_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From up there, we also noticed the lights that had been placed on every wall, every roof and every pillar in town. Not candles, as we had imagined, but tin cans filled with wood shavings and candle wax. Keep this in mind, this will get important in a minute!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sundown we headed back down into town to grab a cup of coffee and observe the procession from the comfort of a bar or restaurant. After finishing a jug of rakomelo (a hot drink made from raki and honey) we got a bit impatient and began to head back up the hill. Still, there weren’t many lights in sight, but a crowd was gathering around the church. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One by one, the lights were lit by local youngster armed with propane torches. The wind, however, had not lessened a bit. If anything, it was stronger than before. Remember those wood shavings in the cans? Soaked in candlewax? The ones set on fire by the local teenagers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gusts ripped the burning wood from the cans and sent them flying through the darkness, turning the night into a storm of sparks and light. Dozens, if not hundreds of those cans were lit and with each light, more sparks were sent flying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The glowing wood was blown from the roofs down the narrow walkways and stairs. Since the wind sent them flying so fast, the sparks didn’t touch anything for long enough to pose an actual danger to anyone. They sure enough made for an amazing sight though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes, I braved the storm for long enough to climb back up on the roof of the main church. The experience up there was fantastic: The church bells rang out next to me, barely audible of the deafening roar of the wind. I looked down into the town with more and more spots of light appearing in the darkness below every minute. And over all of this, showers of sparks blew past me like massive waves, engulfing the church and the spot I was standing in. It was like standing in the middle of a firestorm. I remember grinning like a maniac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dutifully, I attempted to take a few pictures, but I don’t think they really reflect the sheer intensity of those moments up on that church roof:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_205155_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_205211_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I decided to climb down from there. The wind threatened to throw me on my face, off the roof or both. Instead I joined the others in front of the church and we headed back down through the town. Not before taking a few more pictures near the top though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/P4100110_scaled.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_210602_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/P4100094_scaled.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/P4100109_scaled.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards we navigated the labyrinth of passages and stairs. We also had the decidedly weird experience of walking right through a choir of priests and the congregration. As in: right between the priest and the singing congregation. “Excuse me - so sorry - my bad!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we reached the foot of the hill. As we looked back, we saw the very image that countless photographers had captured before us: Pyrgos, on the hill, as a sea of shimmering lights in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_213237_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took us a while to pull ourselves away from this sight. We weaseled our way through what had become dense traffic at the foot of the hill and called a cab. After finding our cab and being stuck in traffic for the better part of 20 minutes, we finally managed to drive back to Fira, the brightly lit hill left behind us.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/16/easter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/16/easter/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stranded, part I - Hiking down Donkey Turd Avenue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So picture this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your friend has left the island and you’re settled in in your hostel, awaiting your ferry’s departure the next day. But then you hear whispers in the common room about ferries getting canceled due to the storm, so you go out and check. A look down from the main road seems to support that rumor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_084952_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as the first heavy drops fall you reach the travel agency, and yes, ferry traffic has been cancelled. Outside, stray dogs and cats run for shelter. Probably for the best not to be on a boat right now. The ticket gets moved to the next ferry, which leaves on Sunday night. If the storm has calmed by then, which it might. Or might not. You know how islands are, says the friendly lady with a shrug. Since there is not much you can do you  flick up your collar and step outside and get drenched on the way to the bakery next door. Armed with coffee and a sandwich you half-walk, half-run back to the hostel. Since plenty of other people are just as stranded as you are, most of the guests are sitting in the common room. So you settle in for the day and get to know the others, which include a guy from Finland and a girl from Norway. So far so good. So you end up spending the day watching Taken 3 and Wild Card and being generally useless, while outside the palms are whipped back and forth by gusts of wind. Sunset happens without anyone noticing, because the sky was pretty dark to begin with. After a day holed up in the hostel you sneak off to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, lo and behold, the skies have cleared. The wind is still coming in powerful gusts, but the sky is mostly blue. So you decide to be less useless than you were yesterday and set out to explore the cliff-side of Fira. 220 meter above the sea, the cold wind sucks all the warmth right out of your clothes. This part of the town is pretty, but devoid of substance: Bars for tourists. Souvenir stores for tourists. Restaurants for tourists. Without tourists, the area is mostly empty. The view however, is stunning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/PANO_20150410_114642_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting there, staring down into the water, you notice a path leading all the way down to the sea and the old port. So you try to find a way to the beginning of that path, which isn’t easy because whoever planned this city had no plan at all. What you absolutely don’t do is climb over lower walls or gates when you get frustrated. No sir, not even when nobody’s looking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually you find the start of the path down. Right at the start you pass a man brushing the sidewalk in front of of his store. He’s build a neat pile of manure. Where did he get that from, you wonder? Suddenly you are distracted by a conversation between a local man and a tourist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tourist: &quot;So are you from around here?&quot;
Local: &quot;No, I&#39;m from Pireas.&quot;
Tourist: &quot;Pyras?&quot;
Local: &quot;No, Pireas.&quot;
Tourist: &quot;Ohhh...you mean PEE-RAY-US!&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nestled between the cliffs, the path is somewhat protected from the cold winds and you can feel the heat radiating from the cobbles under your feet. You smell the sun on the stones, the salt of the sea and, again, manure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_121258_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The avenue in question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You turn onto the start of a serpentine stretch of shallow stairs, and suddenly you understand where all that manure comes from: Donkeys. Not horses, because that would be stupid. No, donkeys. Apparently there is a class of people who are too lazy to walk but too outdoors-y to take the cable car. For those people the locals have two or three dozen donkeys shuttling tourists up and down the stairs. And covering those stairs in donkey poop in the process, evidently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_121335_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the furry culprits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course you wouldn’t be caught dead on one of those four-legged mobility scooters, you’ll walk. So you pass the group of donkeys currently being loaded with a few tourists. You see one of the donkeys strutting off towards a wall at a casual pace. The British teenager riding it begins to scream in panic. In slow-motion she begins to tip out of the saddle, suddenly hanging on with one hand and one leg only. For an instant, the other donkeys seem to shake their collective heads in disgust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving a respectful distance between yourself and the donkeys you walk around that group and hike down the stairs. Further down, the wind picks up and throws more and more dust in your face. Most of that dust is dried donkey turds, actually, but there isn’t a whole lot you can do about it. The entire stairway is covered in it, after all. Onwards and downwards. After nine serpentine loops you see the old port down there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You pass a sign “Donkey Terminal”, followed by a row of two dozen donkeys, patiently waiting for the next group of tourists going up the stairs. After that, you’re in the old port. One or two restaurants are open for business, but most of the harbour seems to be empty ruins with occasional bits of maritime engineering strewn around and left for good: An anchor winch here, part of a rudder there, some damaged rowboards pulled up on the dock. Everything is sun-baked and covered in salt. Some glass-bottom boats are hidden from the storm behind a pier. Leaning against the sudden gusts, you carefully climb up the stairs to the pier wall and follow it until its very end, marked by a light tower and a bench. You sit down and pull up your collar against the stiff wind, then you look out over the bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day, the clear, blue water looked so inviting. Today, it shows a very different face: Waves surge violently and crash into the pier, filling the air with a salty mist. Out in the bay, the squall grabs the crests off the waves and rips the spray up in the air in hazy shapes. Close to the volcano in the middle of the bay seabirds struggle to stay in the air as angry gusts throw them this way and that. The sun shines on it all. And you just sit there, on your bench, and smile at this phenomenal display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting completely lost in the view for an hour you get up and slowly make your way back to the stairs. You scoff at the next group of tourists which is just getting on their respective donkeys and start taking the steps, two at a time. After two of the serpentine loops you begin to feel that welcome sense of going somewhere. After three, your breath comes quickly and you start feeling rather warm in your jacket. How many of those loops were there again? Oh, that’s right: Nine. Two loops later you notice that the weird dimensions of the steps mean you’re stressing one leg more than the other. You begin to alternate the pace. Maybe that will make it less exhausting. Five loops done and you’re breathing through your mouth. You can definitely feel your legs now. Can’t really slow down though, because then the donkeys might overtake you. How would that look? Loop six is a short one, thank god. You feel sweat soaking your shirt and your pulse hammering in your neck as you ascend the last few stairs and lean on a low wall to catch your breath. Way, way down below the donkey caravan is crawling up, leaving another unmistakable trail on the stairs you just conquered. Who the hell needs donkeys anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/13/hiking-down-donkey-turd-avenue/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/13/hiking-down-donkey-turd-avenue/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
