<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Escaping Sloth</title>
    <description>...very slowly</description>
    <link>http://escapingsloth.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://escapingsloth.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Agra - The Taj Mahal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Can’t go to India without seeing the Taj Mahal. Actually, you very well can as it’s a big country and the Taj is not a franchise business, so there is only one and…I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was in Delhi, it seemed like a smart idea to go take a look though: The Taj Mahal is located in a neighbouring city called Agra only a few hours away and I wanted to see what all the fuss is about. Luckily I had run into a group of friends from England at the hostel, and they were planning to go, so I just tagged along. Unfortunately, they had moved to another hostel in the meantime and hired a car from there. And so it happened that I had to kick myself out of bed around 3am and take an auto/tuktuk/threewheeler from Paharganj to South Delhi. This time of night the roads were wonderfully quiet and empty, just like my brain. Unfortunately this was also true for the driver, who took a somewhat experimental approach to navigation. As luck would have it, the others were delayed, too, since their driver hadn’t turned up yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he did, we were all a bit surprised: Our ride was a lot cleaner and fancier than expected. Impressed, we settled down for a 4-hour nap on our way to Agra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HONK! - HONK! - HOOOOOOOONK!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately our driver did not live up to the distinguished flair of our ride: As we drove through South Delhi, he honked continuously, weaving in and out of traffic. Yay, we were riding with Indian Ayrton Senna…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since there was no hope of sleeping, I enjoyed the view of the sprawling city as it was slowly waking up. Everywhere construction sites were reaching up into the sky. As we drove past Faridabad Industrial Town I found myself staring at the swanky appartment buildings the multinationals had built there for their staff. My amazement was shortlived at this ungodly hour, so I drifted off before too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely not drooling, I had sunk against the window and only woke up when I heard the sound of dull thumping. When I looked around, I saw that the sound was caused by our driver repeatedly punching his thigh. When asked why, he responded “So I stay awake!” Oooo-kay. We insisted he stop at the next gas station and bought him a coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As luck would have it, our driver was clearly not used to higher doses of caffeine and decided to liven up the early morning by turning on the radio and tuning into a station playing native dance music (think squealing pipes, a tinny beat and the sounds of small animals in agony). Good thinking, genius: Not like any of us wanted to sleep at goddamn six in the morning…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of much-need sleep I got to see some of the country side and some villages between Delhi and Agra. Simply put: Not a fan. Most of the villages seemed fairly underdeveloped, the roads were bad and traffic consisted of various configurations of wheels, axles, curious-looking engines and livestock. Often a little bit of everything, all bound together with sticky tape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_081926.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_081926_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Low-emissions transportation&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We picked up our tour guide in the outskirts of Agra, a polite and well-spoken professional guide. Next we stopped at a fairly swanky-looking hotel (in a decidedly less swanky-looking neighbourhood) for brunch before heading towards the Taj Mahal itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The powers-that-be forbid traffic of cars and tuktuks around the Taj Mahal (generally a good idea: black soot, white stone, makes sense). The downside of that was that as we stepped out of the car, we also stepped into a massive pack of waiting hawkers and shitpeddlers. “No. No. No, thank you. I swear to god, if you touch me again..!” So we made our way throught the thick of commerce towards the entrance. Here, our guide collected money for the entrance fees. As I had seen before in Delhi, discriminatory prices apply. This means that tourists like us paid about 10€ per person, where locals and other Asians paid about one Euro or two. While this seems a bit unusual, a part of me hopes that the money is actually used for the upkeep of this impressive monument. It probably is. I mean, they say it is. So it probably is. Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our tickets, complimentary water bottles and plastic overshoes we passed through yet another security checkpoint and found ourselves in front of the Great Gate. Now I’ll leave the history lesson to Wikipedia, but the gist is: The entire complex was built under orders of emperor Shah Jahan in the early 17th century. Weirdly, I had assumed it to be much older but that might just be me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pointy white building is a tomb for his favourite wife, Mumtaz Mahal, as a symbol of his undying love for her. His other three wives got smaller buildings, as a type of undying fuck-you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_084753.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_084753_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The Great Gate&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outer gates and walls consist of red stone with incredibly intricate inlays of stones and mother of pearl. Shah Jahan being a Moghul, and hence muslim, emperor, many of the inlays and inscriptions are actually calligraphy and verses of the the Qur’an.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_085144.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_085144_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Calligraphy in marble&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the mesmerizing detail of inlays, the entire complex is filled with interesting architectural mindgames. For example, the calligraphy on the Great Gate is written in increasingly larger font towards the top, to ensure all letters look the same size when viewed from the ground. The effect is hard to describe but there is a tangible feeling of “…huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The the Great Gate one enters the mausoleum grounds, in which a long pool points towards the white mausoleum itself. Eventhough we were less than lucky with the weather, the view was captivating. While we were swarmed by other tourists, seeing this World Wonder just before us was oddly moving. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_085404.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_085404_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View from the Great Gate&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I should also note that the grounds were kept very clean and orderly. Now that’s what I paid for!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the path along the pool we reached the foot of the mausoleum. Here, our guide pointed out that the four towers around the main building were actually built at an angle, slightly slanting outwards. This was primarily done to keep them from damaging the main dome should they fall, but also has the curious effect of - again - reducing skewing a bit when viewed from the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_090529.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_090529_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we all slipped on our overshoes and slowly shuffled into the mausoleum. Every inch of white marble was covered in intricate patterns and inlays. The level of detail was truly astonishing. In the light of flashlights we wandered around the tomb of Mumtaz Mahal and marveled at the decoration all around us. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_091650.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_091650_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_092039.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_092039_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we managed to push through the throng of tourists and exited the tomb on the backside. The Taj had been build right on the Yamuna riverbank. Rumor has it that Shah Jahan had begun construction of a second tomb for himself on the opposite riverbank, only built from black stone. However, when researching that topic, I found conflicting reports about that tale. We ended up enjoying the view of the misty river for a bit before heading back towards the gate. We used the way back to take a few more pictures (for Facebook, you know) and then fought our way back towards the entrance and our car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_094630.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_094630_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stood around for about 15 minutes, waiting for our driver to turn up, all the while every damn hawker of Agra danced around us. “No. No. No. Just. No. Jesus. No. No. Fffffff…NO!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were supposed to go see the Red Fort of Agra next, but were dropped off at a “Crafts Museum” first. Here, a few crafty local guys were creating some of those amazing stone inlays for decoration. It took a while to explain to them that yes, that marble table top with 18 kinds of gem inlays was very impressive, but no, I was not going to buy, partially because it weighed 80kg. No, I did not want them to ship it to my home address, but thanks for asking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150801_111654.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150801_111654_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Traditional crafts&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After tactfully leaving the “museum”, we visited the Red Fort. I’ll be honest: I remember next to nothing about that part. The sun had come out and burned my brain to a crisp. I was incredibly glad to get back into the car eventually. Most of us fell asleep almost right away and slept blissfully through the bumpy ride back to Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2016/02/03/agra-taj-mahal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2016/02/03/agra-taj-mahal/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Delhi III - The Sikh temple</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Once again I’m in Bangalore, India, the last stop of my journey. As a result of a gypsy curse (long story), every internet connection I connect to in this city dies immediately. The only connection that seems to work is the wifi at Starbucks. So yes, I’m sitting here, yet another free spirit with a Macbook in their lap, busily typing away. If you ask the staff nicely, you can even get coffee  - without milk, sugar, caramel and whatever other pollutants they want to cram into your cup. Apparently my last post still had me in Delhi, so let’s pick it up there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Gurudwara Bangla Sahib&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One downside of traveling by yourself is that every now and then you find yourself with zero motivation in a place you should find interesting. And nobody else does anything about it! It was one of those days. I was lying on my bunk at the hostel doing nothing. Not reading anything, not watching anything, not listening to anything - not even thinking about anything, really. I was mainly enjoying the relative cool and quiet, while outside the sun was roasting that particular sensory overload that is Delhi. Unbidden, the realisation that I only had one more day left in Delhi popped in my head, followed by the guilty admission that I really should be more travel-ly. In my experience, people tend to underestimate the energy required for travel. It’s those people that tend to message you “Oh, why are you inside? You should be out, exploring stuff!” Why don’t you go out yourself, smartass!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I find it easy enough to ignore those awful yay-sayers, tuning out that nagging voice in my head was a lot more difficult. Eventually I dragged myself out of bed and stepped out into the heat, the noise and the chaos. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somebody had mentioned that there was a beautiful Sikh temple not too far away. Sikh are the guys with the turbans, in case you were wondering, and they tend to build nice temples. So I found myself a tuktuk/auto and got myself dropped off at Connaught Place, from where I would walk the remaining stretch to Gurudwara Bangla Sahib.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The residential neighbourhood surrounding the temple is oddly calm and quiet. I see few people in the streets, and the buildings and trees absorb most of the noise. Instead of people I see monkeys (and the occasional security guard failing to chase them off with sticks). Monkeys tend to be egotistical, ungrateful assholes prone to violence, shrieking and poop-flinging (lending a whole lot of support the the idea of evolution). In Europe we don’t get monkeys, which sadly means that most poop remains un-flung but makes those animals all the more interesting when I finally get to see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150726_171556.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150726_171556_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Monkey patrol&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hundred meters out from the temple a low hum rises above the silence of the area. Soon I reach an intersection and spy a white tower with a gilded dome  loom over the block. The hum turns out to be a huge crowd around what must be the temple. As I get closer, the crowd of colourfully dressed families closes around me. The chatter, singing and sound of bells is deafening. I can smell food and a lot of burning incense. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150726_172105.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150726_172105_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Main gate to the temple&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I end up following the crowd through a white gate onto a square in front of the temple. Everybody else is taking off their shoes and leaves them at a wardrobe outside the temple. I follow suit and then let the flow of people carry me up the stairs. A young Sikh stops me and hands me a scarf, which I tie around my head, covering my hair. After a few minutes, the result is acceptable, though it leaves him and his friends grinning broadly. Whatever man!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temple is made up of two parts: The prayer hall itself, which a continuous stream of people passes through, and an outside area of a large pool with a roofed archway around it. Everything is made of white stone with intricate inlays. Gold twinkles in the sun. I decide to take a walk around the pool, together with many other visitors. The atmosphere outside is relaxed: People chat and laugh together, children run around playing and several visitors sit down under the arches and eat. Many visitors take a ritual bath in the pool, surrounded by others taking selfies in front of the spectacular temple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150726_173759.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150726_173759_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View from the pool&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the clouds grow darker and darker, I decide to sit down under the arches for a break. Every few minutes, small groups break off from the stream of passers-by and come up to me, asking for a picture with me. I don’t really see a reason to decline, so I obediently pose for a few pictures and exchange a few handshakes. Unfortunately, many of them seem a bit too shy for conversation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150726_174122.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150726_174122_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The arcades around the pool&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a walk around the pool I decide to brave the crowds and step inside the temple itself. This being India, personal space is not much of  an issue for anybody and as a slow-moving group cuddle we flow into the main hall of the temple. Inside, every inch of marble is covered in ornate patterns in gold and lively colours. The throng of people carries me past a huge arrangement of flowers and statues, while the air is full of incense and chanting. I’m looking around, my senses  completely overwhelmed. At some point, I feel a hand clamping down on my shoulder, which belongs to one of the younger guys I spoke to earlier outside. He gave me a fairly unexpected hug and then disappeared in the crowd, leaving me a bit bewildered. Finally, the crowd around me pushed itself over the doorstep at the exit and out into the open air. Still stunned by the noise and the whirl of colours inside I’m walking down to the wardrobe robotically. I pull on my boots and sit there for a while, processing the experience. Eventually, I wrestle myself free of the sights and head back out into the streets.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/04/delhi_iii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/04/delhi_iii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Delhi II - First Night, part 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;###What ACTUALLY happened&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, I’m being a bit retarded. Not so much a shark, more of a deranged hippo in a sewer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you catch what was going on? I obviously didn’t and it took me half a day and a few conversations with other travellers to really appreciate the beauty of what happened here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course they were all in on it! The whole thing is a brazen scam and famous enough that I could have avoided it just by doing some basic research on Delhi. Oh well…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s the thing: There’s exactly &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; official, legit tourist information in Delhi. This one wasn’t it. You find places calling themselves “Government Tourist Information” all over town, but these places are just travel agencies exploiting tourists’ belief that anything calling itself that must be legit. Nope, not in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is how it works: The tuktuk driver finds some pretense to take his passengers to one of those agencies - a festival, a political event, the second coming of the messiah. The agency picks up the pretense for why you can’t get to your hotel. In the absence of an internet connection you can’t really check. When they offer to call the hotel, they don’t dial the number you give them, instead they dial their accomplices in the room next door, who’ll play along and confirm the initial pretense. In the meantime the agency tries to sell you on overpriced tour packages. Eventually, the accomplices call you back, letting you know you won’t be able to stay at your hotel. At this point, the driver will take you to whatever hotel they recommend instead. There you’ll be drastically overcharged for the room, a part of which goes to the driver as a commission for luring you there in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple, eh? I fell for it completely. When I figured it out I felt this particular mixture of anger and shame you get when you find yourself scammed. I briefly entertained the notion of going back to the ‘Government Tourist Information’ and having a little chat with them. I daydreamed of the whole building burning down and the smell of bacon rising from their charred bodies. In the end, none of that came to pass. Instead, I put it down as a learning experience:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is always room for a bit more cynicism:&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re reading this you’re likely a fairly sceptical person - by western standards. In India, that’s not enough. Somebody says they work for the government? Could be, but I wouldn’t count on it. A taxi driver tells you he knows the place you want to get to? Maybe, but it’s unlikely. The truth had a distinctly subjective flavour in Delhi and I felt myself tiring of that, especially with the petty, bold-faced lies of vendors, tour guides and drivers. I’ve always tried to think the worst of people, but some people managed to be even worst-er. Lesson learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common sense, bring it:&lt;/strong&gt; No free hotel rooms under 150 USD a night. Come on. Think about it: Delhi has a population of about 20 million. Average monthly income is around 300 USD. Sound fishy? My only excuse is that it was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; late and I was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; tired and…eh, forget it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get that SIM card at the airport:&lt;/strong&gt; The internet is a fantastic way of fact-checking a lot of things. Festival dates for example, or hotel prices. Addresses even. Don’t rely on other peoples’ internet connections, they have a habit of cutting out at inconvenient times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sidenote: About 4 out of 5 western travelers I spoke to in Delhi had fallen for the exact same scam. One of them had been taken for 250 USD that night. All of them seemed to feel that mixture of embarrassment and amazement at the shamelessness of the scam. Why the city is allowing those places to keep using the whole ‘government’ label is beyond me, though I do have a suspicion…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first night was probably the crappiest first impression I ever got of a country. Luckily, after that things got better: I met some amazing people, saw some incredibly sights and had a great time overall. Despite what you have read so far, I thoroughly enjoyed my time in India. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/04/delhi_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/04/delhi_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Delhi I - First Night, part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;div align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;color:gray&quot;&gt;
&quot;Write drunk, edit sober!&quot;
-- Alcoholics
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently in Hoi An, a lovely seaside-town in eastern Vietnam. So why is this post titled “Delhi”, you may wonder. Well, the reasons are complicated, but they involve a very generous restaurant owner, at least 7 shots of rice wine and the realization that if I can’t be bothered to write about certain parts of my journey you probably couldn’t be bothered to read about them either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that spirit - and several others - I’ll procrastinate writing more about the Middle East by writing about my arrival in India instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll say this much up front: Of the countries I visited during this trip, India was the one that felt strangest to me. In terms of getting out of my comfort zone, it was a fantastic success. It was also a series of impressions and experiences that made what else I saw of Southeast Asia seem…tame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India felt extreme in several ways. Some things were extremely pleasant, others extremely annoying. As a result, India probably had the strongest effect on my perspective.
Was that a consistently pleasant experience? Well…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Arriving in Delhi
I reached Delhi around 11pm, after a short layover in Abu Dhabi. Obviously I had some images in my head, but the airport really didn’t match them: Turns out, Delhi Airport is actually very new, very clean and suspiciously quiet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a long day I was glad to see that my eVisa carried me through immigration without too many questions (I did get fingerprinted though). I had booked a hotel in advance and was eager to find it and go to sleep. Luckily the airport terminal has a direct metro connection to the city centre. While trying to figure out the ticket system, I started chatting with two local university students who had just returned from a trip to Europe and took me under their wings, making sure I got off the metro at the right stop, namely New Delhi Station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was lovely. I got out there and took a tuktuk (hehe) to my hotel. And that’s where that evening suddenly turned around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###My point-of-view&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m worldly and well-traveled, easily adapting to a new city like a shark smoothly sliding into a new current.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are cruising past Connaught Place, a circular area full of shops and bars, one of Delhi’s central sights. The night is lively, but cooler than Oman and calmer than I expected of India. Suddenly the driver pulls over and asks me to repeat the address of my hotel. I read it out to him. His English is tough to understand but he wants to know which block the hotel is at. I don’t know, the email doesn’t say and I don’t have internet to check. Not to worry, he says, he’ll just drive me to the Government Tourist Information and they’ll find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decline and show him the map on my phone, telling him to just drive up there. He insists on going to the tourist information, telling me that the area around my hotel is cordoned off for a festival and he can’t drive there. This seems weird, because I didn’t see any blockades or signs and it’s really rather quiet. After about 5 minutes of arguing I relent and tell him to just get on with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then drives to an unassuming-looking building down the road with a big sign saying “Government Tourist Information”, stops and ushers me in. I’m greeted by a middle-aged man with a badge clipped to his shirt and he invites me to sit down in an office. The shelves are full of travel guides, brochures and a few framed official-looking documents and letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then tells me that the city is a bit out of control due to a big festival taking place in the centre. When he looks up my hotel on a map he finds out that, yeup, it’s definitely blocked off right now. The internet connection is down at the moment, but we can call my hotel from his office. I read the number to him and he passes me the handset. I recite my booking code into the handset and I’m being told that yes, the hotel is difficult to reach right now, but they’ll think of something and call me back. Lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tourist-information-guy then tells me that it might be difficult to find alternative accommodation tonight, since every hotel is going to be booked out because of the festival. Pretty much impossible to find anything under 150 USD a night, really. But I could spend a few days in one of the surrounding cities, do some sightseeing. He proposes to put together a nice tour around Rajasthan, maybe a week or so including all the major sighs and cities. A nice idea, but unfortunately his plan for one week costs about as much as I budget for a month. So maybe I would like to take a private car to Agra tonight, see the Taj Mahal tomorrow? A cheap way of evading all the hassle with the festival and all? He quotes me 200 USD for that, which seems…steep. I politely decline. Man, at this point I’m getting proper sleepy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually the hotel rings back, informing me that regrettably they could not find a way of getting me there. Of course they’ll refund me for it, but I’ll have to find another place to stay. A bit of a blow for me, because I wasn’t planning on spending 150 USD on a single night and my new friend really didn’t know any hotel that would have cheaper rooms available. Checking online would help, but the internet connection is still down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, around one o’clock he does think of one or two places that might be a bit cheaper. The tuktuk driver, who has been faithfully waiting outside agrees to drive me there after getting the address from the tourist information. I almost fall asleep on the way and get hotel room at the other end of the city. I haggle the price down to 70 USD, go up to my room and pass out on the bed immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/03/delhi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/12/03/delhi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bahrain II - Life in the desert</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;All in all I spent about 3 weeks in Bahrain, staying with my friend Andrew who graciously showed me around. This was my first time in the middle east, so here are a few assorted observations. Seriously, it’s 01:00h here and I had a few beers…if you expect a coherent narrative you came to the wrong place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Still pretty warm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahrain is a desert country. No surprises there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150619_133523.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150619_133523_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;See? Desert!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, it’s an island, but a desert island in a shallow, half-boiling pond (called ‘the gulf’) surrounded by more desert in almost every direction. A few times I stepped outside during the day. I lived to regret it every single time: The heat was unbearable. A casual 40°C and a city baked to a smoking crisp by a sun as merciless as a very merciless thing. You don’t see other people in the streets because they’ve learned their lesson long ago: Just. Don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150617_153210.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150617_153210_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Al Fateh Grand Mosque&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150617_152201.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150617_152201_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Inside the mosque&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150617_152736.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150617_152736_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The gorgeous prayer hall&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I being overly sensitive because I’m used to northern European climate? Sure. Does that make the Emirates any less hostile to human life? Not really. Airconditioning alone keeps people from turning into a human form of jerky. And this is the greater irony:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is Bahrain insanely hot, it’s also freezing cold. The same geniuses who thought it was a good idea to build cities on sand that’s a few degrees above its melting point also thought it might be amazing to cool every living space down to about 16°C. Suddenly popping out to the shops means that within 5 minutes you experience a temperature difference that most European countries get over the course of a year. You leave the cinema with icicles hanging from your nose. Your sweat-soaked shirt is frozen to your frost-bitten back, which then burns once you step out into the sun. Awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this seems perfectly plausible to the locals. My favourite remark: “But you’re from the north, you must love the cold!” No, we fricking don’t! We have heating for that, and warm clothes and vacation days! We hate the cold more than anything. So why do you do that?! Why does your office make me think of the Winter War or Stalingrad ‘42?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##It’s Ramadan
About halfway through my stay in Bahrain, Ramadan started. I was familiar with the concept on an individual level but not quite prepared for what it looks like on a societal level. For the period between 18.06. and 17.07. public life slowed down to allow the population time for introspection, their faith and reconnecting with family and loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were also not supposed to consume anything between sunrise and sunset. In Bahrain this is taken seriously as far as public life is concerned: You can’t eat in public. Or drink (even water). Or smoke. Or chew gum. Any one of those things is grounds for a stint in a cell and a hefty fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, any place serving food or drink is closed during the day. Good way to avoid temptation, I guess. But once the sun sinks below the horizon…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Food is amazing. I like food.
The food. Oh my god, the food! As you’d expect, not eating during the day gets people quite excited about food! As a result, the meals available after sunset are just astonishing in quantity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150619_211319.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150619_211319_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;No doubt that&#39;s exactly what the inventor intended...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Bahrain is such a melting pot, the sheer variety of fantastic food also shines in terms of quality. My friends took me to one great restaurant after the other, every one of which left me grinning like an idiot. Luckily, the desert heat did little to dampen the ever-present hunger that comes with the fusion-drive that is my metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150617_160608.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150617_160608_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Mmmhhmm...cow!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahrain being a bit of a melting pot there is no shortage of cuisines to chose from: Middle eastern, American, European, Indian, Thai, you name it. Most service jobs in Bahrain are done by workers from Southeast Asia or the Philippines. Consequently, whichever cuisine you chose, the food will be served by people from that part of the world. Turkish food? Indians. American food? Indians. Indian food? Philipinos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the fantastic Indian food served at Andrew’s place to the mix and it’s a proper miracle they didn’t have to roll me back over the border. Some of my favourite treats included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Milkshake “Miley Cyrus” (Cookie dough + Reese’s Peanut Butter cups)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fresh lemon juice with mint&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cheese samosas&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tandoori fish filet&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Lebanese BBQ&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So. Many. Things.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uh…excuse me for a second, I need to go find some dinner!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/11/22/bahrain_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/11/22/bahrain_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bahrain - Visa woes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, look: A text editor! What would one do with that? Why, write tall tales of course! Stories to amaze and entrance the readers, tales of distant lands, perilous journeys and wondrous people. Adventures and anecdotes of giants and midgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But actually I’m writing this in a well-airconditioned coffee shop. On Koh Samet, which is about as exotic as Berlin Mitte. Warmer though, with a lot more beaches. People are smiling, food is excellent. You see coconuts and palm trees everywhere. Okay, maybe it’s a bit more exotic after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just spent some time looking through my photographs of this trip (~4000 so far). It’s staggering how this travel-thing distorts one’s perception of time: It feels as if many of those pictures were taken several years ago when they’re only a few months old. That’s what happens in the absence of a routine. Or when your memory is, like, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was I talking about? Oh, right: I’m in Thailand. How in god’s name did I get here?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Georgia to Bahrain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Twas a warm, sunny morning in May in Tbilisi, capital of the heartwarmingly hard-drinking Georgians…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera pans over a low-slung town nestled into a valley framed by a steep hill on one side. The sun lights up the roofs and the cobbled roads that lead up the hill towards the castle that looms over it. Just below the castle stands a big building with huge windows. The camera zooms in one one of the windows and spies our intrepid protagonist, who lazily rolls out of bed. He yawns, lifts his arms and stretches, his joints crackling like a bag of crisps under a hydraulic press. Slowly he trots into the bathroom to emerge a bit later looking exactly the same but smelling a lot better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, you recognized me? Excellent. It was indeed me getting up before heading off to the airport, to fly out to Bahrain. As the title gives away, that didn’t work so swimmingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with money, the root of all evil. After getting up I went to the hostel’s front desk to ask how much money I owed them, and then stumbled down the hill to get breakfast and cash. My remaining cash paid for the breakfast and afterwards I found an ATM. It took my card and then went all “Nope! Not today!” as would any other ATM I could find. I had booked a few flights earlier that week, so it was conceivable that the card was just empty. Fair enough. Weirdly, the same happened with my debit card, which I knew for sure had money on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhat concerned I walked back to the hostel. There, I managed to sweet-talk the staff into letting me pay my debts via online transfer instead. I also booked one more night, which I then immediately cancelled, somewhat to the surprise of the hostel staff. They did however refund me on the spot, giving me just enough money for the taxi to the airport. Grinning proudly, I got into the cab and drove to Tbilisi airport and handed over the last of my cash to the cab driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I breezed through check-in and security and then sat at the gate, excited to finally go to Bahrain. Eventually, this Indian couple sat down across from me and I overheard this exchange:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: Do you have the cash for the visa by the way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Him: Of course I have the cash for the visa! What idiot would fly to Bahrain without cash for the visa?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: Well, obviously nobody would be daft enough to reach Bahrain without cash for the visa, haha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They may not have said those exact words, but that’s what I remember hearing. Yes. Cash. Visa. The cash. For the visa. In Bahrain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the Bahrain visa would cost about 60 USD on arrival, payable immediately at immigration. See the problem? In my experience, immigration officials are usually not the most relaxed of people. If I turned out to be unable to pay for the visa, they might ask me to book a flight out on the spot (no, thank you) or have me sort it out from a border police cell (lovely, but no thank you). So I had a moment of panic at Tbilisi airport and then messaged my friend Andrew, who had graciously agreed to my one-person host-a-hobo programme. He promised to take a look but obviously couldn’t promise anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I spent a three-hour flight to Dubai thinking about immigration, borders and cells. At Dubai airport I called up my bank in Germany to ask why my debit card would not work. The result of a 10-minute, 20-Euro phone call? It didn’t work because it doesn’t work in that part of the world. Alright then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The connecting flight to Manama (Bahrain) took another 45 minutes which I spent thinking that I was really way too pretty to spend a night in jail. After a tense flight, we finally landed in Manama. Stepping out onto the runway felt…well, hot! Sure, I knew the place was in the desert. I just never really thought about the implications. The 200m walk to the terminal was enough to leave me wondering if maybe global warming is a bad thing after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After turning my phone back on (wouldn’t want to crash that plane, would we?), I received a text from Andrew instructing me to contact a service desk at the airport. Luckily, it turned out to be just in front of immigration. A nice lady handed me an envelope with money from Andrew. Lovely, fresh, crisp money! Money, the solution to all my problems!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly flush with cash I walked through immigration smiling and was met on the other side by Andrew and his girlfriend Angie. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Arne’s insights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Immigration restrictions suck. 
I think we all knew that one already. As of right now I’ve spent 300+ Euro for visa fees. I’m lucky enough to have European passports which are easy to travel on. And yet, you still have to deal with visa and immigration rules. This takes time, effort and money. In my mind it’s a waste of all three but there is no way around it if you want to travel anywhere outside of Europe. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Deserts can be hot.
Not all of them are. Those in the middle east tend to be. This really shouldn’t surprise anybody but I wasn’t prepared for the sheer physical sensation of being grilled in the open air. Also, I’m quite clearly not built for that kind of climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Money is nice.
Traveling without access to cash (even temporarily) is an unnverving experience. I felt incredibly ill-prepared and exposed. Not a nice feeling at all. Before this particular anecdote I had been carrying around a cash reserve in US dollars for tough spots like this. Stupidly, I had at some point run out of cash and decided to exchange my dollars for Georgian Lari because the closest ATM was further away than the currency exchange. So when I needed the cash reserve I had already spent it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual tragedy here was that I walked past a Krispy Kreme doughnut shop at Dubai airport and had no cash…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/11/21/bahrain/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/11/21/bahrain/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travel - A Luxury</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m traveling from the sleepy town of Ella (Sri Lanka) to the city of Cebu (Philippines). Here’s how that works out. Spoiler: I spend about 52 hours in transit. Don’t do that, it’s retarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The walk
Around six o’clock in the evening my friends walk me to Ella train station.  Spirits are high, as we were just beginning to recover from the coconut cider drunk the night before. We pass the waiting time making fun of a particularly low-nippled stray dog running around the station. When I ask an attendant where the 3rd-class carriage carriage will stop, he mentions it might be a sleeper carriage, with beds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The train
It’s not. This becomes quite clear when the train finally arrives, but is also gleefully pointed out by my friends. We part ways on good terms anyway, and I walk out into the starry night, hop down onto the tracks and climb up into the carriage. Third class is barebones but…largely barebones, really. I sprawl out over two seats, which happens automatically if you’re wider than 30cm. The train is pretty empty at this stage. I use the first of twelve hours to craft an insightful and well-received essay on my situation. Then I plug in my headphones and start napping. I wake up as a heavy-set local squeezes in next to me. Heavy-set and twitchy: He’ll spend the next 10 hours fidgeting. I can’t sleep properly anyway. Instead, I spend the night somewhere between wakefulness and dreams. My perception of time just stops, until I notice the sky brightening. We reach Colombo at six in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The bus
At Colombo station I find myself some Samosas for breakfast, which I eat waiting for the airport bus. I try to stare down a crow which is overtly curios about my samosa. The crow is not impressed. A few meters down the road a local guy is blowing chunks with abandon. Into a trash can - Sri Lankans are a considerate bunch. The crow and its friends are visibly excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus ride is long, but uneventful. I doze off a few times, before we reach the airport. I end up walking a kilometer to the terminal and reach it sweat-soaked around 9 in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The first airport
Colombo airport is quiet and relaxed. Through the big windows I can see the tropical garden outside the terminal. Since my flight is not leaving until 4 o’clock, I can’t check in yet and end up sitting in the departure hall. My friends are all still asleep, so I have nobody to complain to. Instead, I buy chocolate. When I check in, I save 50 Euro on baggage, since the staff accepts my only bag as a carry-on. Joke’s on them, as it’s vastly overweight and held together by straining - and alarmingly frayed - compression straps. You don’t want to be anywhere near them when they eventually snap. Even more miraculously the security guys let me keep my scissors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The first flight
I get a window seat on our Airbus 330 and settle in. Even after flying my entire life I can’t get over how inspiring it is: I’m being hurled into the air faster than any bird, in a house made of metal, powered by continuous explosions of liquefied dinosaurs. But sure, keep reading your Financial Times, you philistine! 
Once in the air, I do fall asleep though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wake up half-way through the flight. Outside, night is falling and we’re flying right into it. The view is mesmerizing: the stars loom up over us in a black sky. Beneath them clusters of lights trace coastlines, which separate the lights which are stars from those that are ships on the black seas. It feels as if we could be among the stars if we just banked a little to the left. After a while I wipe my nose-print off the window and doze off again. We reach Kuala Lumpur at 22:00h.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The second airport
Kuala Lumpur International Airport No. 2 (KLIA2) is vast, modern and bright. There are plenty of people around, but nobody is yelling. Shouldn’t there be yelling? This is all very confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my connecting flight to Manila only leaves at 08:20h the next morning, I have booked 12 hours in a sleeping capsule, so I have to go through immigration, even though the place is right in the terminal (“capsule by container”, KLIA2 - go look it up, I’ll wait!). I check in, take a few pictures and go hunt for dinner. The airport is more of a mall anyway, with the occasional flight arriving or departing. I end up eating junk and then book a flight out of the Philippines, which I apparently need to get a visa. I turn in around midnight local time but lie awake for almost an hour because my body clock is two hours behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get ripped out of deep sleep by my alarm after what feels like a painfully short nap. It’s 05:30h. Four and a half hours of sleep. Three thirty in the morning, by my inner clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I check out and trudge back through the airport in a state of angry, confused stupor. It’s packed with people. There are too many people here. We need a new plague. Whatever became of SARS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The walk to the gate is so long I’m beginning to wonder where the security check is. What is that hassle even good for? What if a county decided to just trust people not to be idiots and …nothing happened? What then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this airport the process is quick and efficient though. It pleases me. I’m considerably less pleased when I find out that there is no coffee available after security. This seems doubly unfair as the departure hall had two Starbucks and various other sources for that hot, black magic that keeps me moving. I refuse to eat noodles-in-a-cup for breakfast (I’m an adult) and settle for two fudge brownies (…I can do what I want!). At the gate the boarding process is fast and I’m on the plane in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The second flight
Another window seat. Fog and clouds outside. Sleep-deprived me passes out as soon as we pass through the clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pass over some insanely beautiful islands and reefs, before we land. Oddly, I see no major urban areas during our decent. Turns out, we didn’t land in Manila. Ooops! Due to bad weather we landed in the province. In Clarkfield. Now we’re refueling, to fly to Manila. Hopefully. Pleasantly little panic aboard about the delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope, one hour later we’re still standing on the airfield. I relent and order coffee. It’s amazing to see how relaxed people are about the whole thing. No whining, no complaints. Conversation and laughter instead. If I think of this happening in Europe…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, we’re taking off! After 13 minutes in the air and a generous loop over the sprawling cityscape of Manila we land at the right airport. Non-sarcastic applause fills the cabin. I stand amazed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The third airport
Since I arrived three hours late, I rush through immigration and to transfers to catch my connecting flight. Wikivoyage has Manila as one of the world’s worst airports, but what I see looks relatively orderly and efficient. A quick jog brings me to the gate just in time for the announcement that this flight is delayed by about two hours. The intended plane has failed to show up. I’m concerned over how little concern I see in the faces of other passengers: Is that normal? Will we get a similarly deadpan eulogy?
About an hour later a plane does show up at the gate just as I return from a food-run. I board the plane filled with a sense of doom and two beef-and-cheese panini.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The third flight
Isle seat. Bumpy take-off. Language hard, brain much tired. Head ouch. Are we there yet? I buy a can of beer for…several rup-…ring-…moneys. Finally the plane touches down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The fourth airport
The airport is alright. Outside it’s raining. I stand in line for a taxi and then get in a taxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The taxi
After a few attempts the driver finds the hostel. The city looks dark and rainy. I pay about 4 Euro for 13km and mutter something that rhymes with “clucking bell” as I stumble out of the taxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The hostel
The lobby is full of blond-curled Australian surfer-dudes whose offer to join them I regrettably decline. Better save that experience for tomorrow. I grab my complimentary beer and find my dorm. 52 hours, door to door. About 4,5 hours of proper sleep, a few naps. Otherwise propelled onwards by coffee, beer and junk food. Travel, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/09/16/Travel-a-luxury/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/09/16/Travel-a-luxury/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yerevan II - The city</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So here’s the deal: I’m in Sri Lanka. My last article was in Armenia. That’s way behind, and I find it harder and harder to pretend I’m bothered by my own tardiness. Yes, I’m very forgiving that way. I’ve also gotten a bit tired of the overall style of this site: Went here, went there, did this, did that. Since I’m largely writing this for my own benefit (sorry) and to aid my memory, this doesn’t really do much for me: I already have that sort of information in my pictures (and Google’s GPS data…). At the same time I actually do enjoy writing about this journey in general. So maybe it’s time to try out a different writing style, a different method? Move away from itineraries to moments and impressions? From here on it’s going to be heavy-handed prose and pretty pictures all the way…maybe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##First Impressions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m bad with first impressions. By that I mean: I tend to get a bad first impression places and people. One of the main reasons is that I’m a certifiable retard in terms of scheduling my travels. As a result, I often arrive in new places at night, which I deal with badly. There is something about setting foot into a new city after dark that feels like stepping out into the dark jungle. By that point I’m usually tired (and grumpy), which isn’t really the mindset for exploration or adventure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By some one-in-a-million stroke of luck, my arrival in Yerevan happened in the early morning hours. On a sunny day, no less! Somehow, that made all the difference and I was quite excited to have a look at the city. So was my companion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_062206.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_062206_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After disembarking at Yerevan central, we stepped out into the sun and grabbed a taxi to my hostel. The driver took us through the city centre, which was entirely quiet due to the early morning hours. Quiet, and totally not what I had expected Yerevan to be like. Somehow, my image of Armenia had been that of an impoverished, agrarian nation. To put it bluntly, I had expected Yerevan to be a poorer, downtrodden version of Tbilisi. I was wrong. The city we saw was grand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_092645.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_092645_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_092650.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_092650_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One reason for the elegant cityscape we found ourselves in was that the Soviets “re-designed” the city in the 1960s. The result was a modern, open and airy plan for the city. On top of that, everywhere we looked, the city was well-cared for: No trash, no litter, no graffiti. The city gave of a surprisingly westernized vibe: Even off the main drag we saw various boutique stores, nice coffee shops and restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_095950.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_095950_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that day I found myself exploring the Cascades, a huge complex of art installations in the north of the city centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_100004.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_100004_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amongst other statues, the Cascades are also home to one of my favorite sculptures, a huge black lion fashioned from tire parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_100408.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_100408_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The way the sculpture captures all the traits of a predator gives you an almost physical sensation of menace&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having climbed all the stairs to the top of the Cascades, I was rewarded by this fantastic view of the city&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_100503.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_100503_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Barely visible through the haze you can see Mt. Arahat&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_100944.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_100944_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end I probably sat up top for almost an hour, slowly roasting away in the hot afternoon sun. Whenever I thought I was done, I noticed something new in the panorama before me. I couldn’t help but notice how beautiful a city Yerevan really is. It’s almost ridiculous how surprised I was by that. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/16/yerevan_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/16/yerevan_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yerevan I - Night Train</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My journey to Armenia started with a trip to the central train station in Tbilisi. For foreigners, that’s apparently the only place where they can buy train tickets. So I took a sweaty subway to the central station and walked up to the counter. The lady there looked as if she had smiled maybe once in her life and found the experience wanting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, she also understood some English so I approached the topic with all the minimalist eloquence developed during this trip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Ticket. Yerevan. Tomorrow? Bileti?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: What time? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Time? *pointing at the clock*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: *writes 10pm on a sheet of paper*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: How much money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: *holding up my wallet*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: *writes down 80 GEL and 100 GEL*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Class one and class two?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: *nods*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Yerevan. Tomorrow. Class one bileti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: Passport?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had left my passport in the hostel. Showing her a scan of my passport on my phone also elicited several headshakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Reserve bileti?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Money now. Reserve Bileti. Passport two hours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patiently massaging my temples I said a cheerful goodbye (and mumbled a few other things not fit for publication) and walked back to the subway to get my passport. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I blame myself. But I also kind of blame the Soviets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, after this trip I probably won’t be able to form coherent sentences anymore…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening of the following day, I arrived at the central station with plenty of time to spare. I was told to await the train on platform 3 and went to sit outside and enjoy the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150607_194005.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150607_194005_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Why is every place I go always deserted?&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About ten minutes before the planned departure there was no train in sight. Getting nervous, I started paying attention to the announcements on the platform. Most of it was unintelligible, but I thought I heard something like “Yerevan” and “four” in the same sentence. The only other person on platform 3 was a girl with a backpack. Of course she was a German on her way to Yerevan. Since neither of us was sure about the announcements we walked back to the service desk and were, once again, told to go to platform 3. We did, only to hear the same announcement as before. So we went back to the desk to really, really make sure. No, no, platform 3 was right. In the end, we ignored them and went to platform 4, where we just barely managed to jump on before the train pulled out of the station. We parted ways, since she had been frugal and gotten the 2nd-class ticket while I had splurged on the fancy 1st-class luxury sleeper cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150607_202135.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150607_202135_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;1st class: Two instead of four bunks per cabin&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we drove out of Tbilisi, a thunderstorm started and lightning flashed over the dark villages and Georgia’s beautiful rolling countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was standing outside my cabin and taking in the view, I was offered a bottle of wine by the guy from the cabin next door. He turned out to be a German photographer from my hometown, who was travelling around the Caucasus for both work and pleasure. Since we got along quite well, we decided to head to the dining car and have a few beers. A few beers turned into many beers, until suddenly we were ushered out of the dining car. It turned out that we had stopped at the border. Consequently, all toilets had been locked. So had the train doors. For some of us, this caused some distress. A few beers, some wine, some water even. 
It was only after having our passports checked at the Georgian side of the border that we were allowed to leave the train at the Armenian border station and use the facilities there. In return, the Armenians took close to 90 minutes to check our passports. Eventually we started moving again. I fell on my bunk and into restless, dreamless sleep as we rolled into Armenia.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/14/yerevan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/14/yerevan/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kazbegi III - Last Day in the Mountains</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One advantage of having my writing lag behind is that I get to consider episodes of my trip in hindsight.  A pattern I keep noticing is how some weeks are infinitely more eventful than others. This is the third article on Kazbegi (a trip that lasted all of the 3,5 days). Yet I know that other periods of several weeks will barely warrant more than one article. The obvious lesson is that a trip of several months is not just one exciting adventure after another. I suppose it could be, if I really wanted it to be, but who has the energy? Instead, I find that enjoying some downtime can be much more educational than frantic sightseeing. Stay in one place for a bit, have some tea, observe what is happening around you. Heck, maybe use the time to write down how you got there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aren’t these story-in-a-story things fun? So artistic, much wow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Day 3 - Waterfalls
We had arranged our departure from Kazbegi for the third day. Before we left this beautiful part of the world we wanted to see one last sight though: The waterfall at Gveleti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our driver from the day before drove us up towards the Russian border for about half an hour, before letting us hop out into the sun. After some back and forth (employing the usual amount of waving and pointing), we understood where he wanted us to go and we stalked off into the greenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_112753.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_112753_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The fellowship&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_113901.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_113901_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We quickly found the fast-flowing stream and then followed it up-hill. At that point, I definitely began to notice the ascents and descents of the previous days: My legs began to feel like rubber and it’s almost a miracle I didn’t faceplant straight into the stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_114044.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_114044_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we found the waterfall. The stream fell from a rocky ledge several meters up in the air. The water was then collected in a shallow basin before running down the gorge into the valley. Where we stood, a cool spray was flying everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_114307.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_114307_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The promised waterfall&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_114720.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_114720_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The view from up there wasn&#39;t so bad, either.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having relaxed at the waterfall for a bit, we climbed down the path and walked back to the waiting car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having seen this sight, we decided that it was time we drove back to Tbilisi. I recall sleeping through most of the drive back, but I did get out of the car once we stopped at this fancy monument:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_131417.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_131417_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Russian-Georgian Friendship Monument...hehe, yeah, I know!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-in-tbilisi&quot;&gt;Back in Tbilisi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Tbilisi, I checked back into the same excellent hostel I had stayed at before. I then spent another four days in Tbilsi, enjoying the usual dinners and drinks with the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150606_203754.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150606_203754_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Is that a dead fish, nailed to a painting? No, that would be absurd: It&#39;s obviously held in place by a screw!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One memory I will always cherish: We took a cab to a student-y bar near Rustaveli Square and had one hell of an evening. Chacha and beer flowed freely there. I vaguely recall randomly pointing at people, yelling “You there, you look interesting. Sit down!” To my great surprise, they tended to follow instructions rather well. That way I got to meet a singer, an event manager, the owner of the bar and a software developer from the Crimean who was very glad about finally having access to the Russian labor market. It was a long, long night…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150604_003219.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150604_003219_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A student bar in Tbilisi (early evening)&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I had to say my goodbyes to the others, who moved on to explore other parts of Georgia. Instead, I elected to book a ticket for the night train to Yerevan.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/12/kazbegi_iii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/12/kazbegi_iii/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
