<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Escaping Sloth</title>
    <description>...very slowly</description>
    <link>http://escapingsloth.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://escapingsloth.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Bahrain - Visa woes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, look: A text editor! What would one do with that? Why, write tall tales of course! Stories to amaze and entrance the readers, tales of distant lands, perilous journeys and wondrous people. Adventures and anecdotes of giants and midgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But actually I’m writing this in a well-airconditioned coffee shop. On Koh Samet, which is about as exotic as Berlin Mitte. Warmer though, with a lot more beaches. People are smiling, food is excellent. You see coconuts and palm trees everywhere. Okay, maybe it’s a bit more exotic after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just spent some time looking through my photographs of this trip (~4000 so far). It’s staggering how this travel-thing distorts one’s perception of time: It feels as if many of those pictures were taken several years ago when they’re only a few months old. That’s what happens in the absence of a routine. Or when you’re memory is, like, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was I talking about? Oh, right: I’m in Thailand. How in god’s name did I get here?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;georgia-to-bahrain&quot;&gt;Georgia to Bahrain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Twas a warm, sunny morning in May in Tbilisi, capital of the heartwarmingly hard-drinking Georgians…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera pans over a low-slung town nestled into a valley framed by a steep hill on one side. The sun lights up the roofs and the cobbled roads that lead up the hill towards the castle that looms over it. Just below the castle stands a big building with huge windows. The camera zooms in one one of the windows and spies our intrepid protagonist, who lazily rolls out of bed. He yawns, lifts his arms and stretches, his joints crackling like a bag of crisps under a hydraulic press. Slowly he trots into the bathroom to emerge a bit later looking exactly the same but smelling a lot better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, you recognized me? Excellent. It was indeed me getting up before heading off to the airport, to fly out to Bahrain. As the title gives away, that didn’t work so swimmingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with money, the root of all evil. After getting up I went to the hostel’s front desk to ask how much money I owed them, and then stumbled down the hill to get breakfast and cash. My remaining cash paid for the breakfast and afterwards I found an ATM. It took my card and then went all “Nope! Not today!” as would any other ATM I could find. I had booked a few flights earlier that week, so it was conceivable that the card was just empty. Fair enough. Weirdly, the same happened with my debit card, which I knew for sure had money on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhat concerned I walked back to the hostel. There, I managed to sweet-talk the staff into letting me pay my debts via online transfer instead. I also booked one more night, which I then immediately cancelled, somewhat to the surprise of the hostel staff. They did however refund me on the spot, giving me just enough money for the taxi to the airport. Grinning proudly, I got into the cab and drove to Tbilisi airport and handed over the last of my cash to the cab driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I breezed through check-in and security and then sat at the gate, excited to finally go to Bahrain. Eventually, this Indian couple sat down across from me and I overheard this exchange:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: Do you have the cash for the visa by the way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Him: Of course I have the cash for the visa! What idiot would fly to Bahrain without cash for the visa?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: Well, obviously nobody would be daft enough to reach Bahrain without cash for the visa, haha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They may not have said those exact words, but that’s what I remember hearing. Yes. Cash. Visa. The cash. For the visa. in Bahrain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the Bahrain visa would cost about 60 USD on arrival, payable immediately at immigration. See the problem? In my experience, immigration officials are usually not the most relaxed of people. If I turned out to be unable to pay for the visa, they might ask me to book a flight out on the spot (no, thank you) or have me sort it out from a border police cell (lovely, but no thank you). So I had a moment of panic at Tbilisi airport and then messaged my friend Andrew, who had graciously agreed to my one-person host-a-hobo programme. He promised to take a look but obviously couldn’t promise anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I spent a three-hour flight to Dubai thinking about immigration, borders and cells. At Dubai airport I called up my bank in Germany to ask why my debit card would not work. The result of a 10-minute, 20-Euro phone call? It didn’t work because it doesn’t work in that part of the world. Alright then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The connecting flight to Manama (Bahrain) took another 45 minutes which I spent thinking that I was really way too pretty to spend a night in jail. After a tense flight, we finally landed in Manama. Stepping out onto the runway felt…well, hot! Sure, I knew the place was in the desert. I just never really thought about the implications. The 200m walk to the terminal was enough to leave me wondering if maybe global warming is a bad thing after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After turning my phone back on (wouldn’t want to crash that plane, would we?), I received a text from Andrew instructing me to contact a service desk at the airport. Luckily, it turned out to be just in front of immigration. A nice lady handed me an envelope with money from Andrew. Lovely, fresh, crisp money! Money, the solution to all my problems!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly flush with cash I walked through immigration smiling and was met on the other side by Andrew and his girlfriend Angie. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arnes-insights&quot;&gt;Arne’s insights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;immigration-restrictions-suck&quot;&gt;Immigration restrictions suck.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we all knew that one already. As of right now I’ve spent 300+ Euro for visa fees. I’m lucky enough to have European passports which are easy to travel on. And yet, you still have to deal with visa and immigration rules. This takes time, effort and money. In my mind it’s a waste of all three but there is no way around it if you want to travel anywhere outside of Europe. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deserts-can-be-hot&quot;&gt;Deserts can be hot.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all of them are. Those in the middle east tend to be. This really shouldn’t surprise anybody but I wasn’t prepared for the sheer physical sensation of being grilled in the open air. Also, I’m quite clearly not built for that kind of climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;money-is-nice&quot;&gt;Money is nice.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traveling without access to cash (even temporarily) is an unnverving experience. I felt incredibly ill-prepared and exposed. Not a nice feeling at all. Before this particular anecdote I had been carrying around a cash reserve in US dollars for tough spots like this. Stupidly, I had at some point run out of cash and decided to exchange my dollars for Georgian Lari because the closest ATM was further away than the currency exchange. So when I needed the cash reserve I had already spent it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual tragedy here was that I walked past a Krispy Kreme doughnut shop at Dubai airport and had no cash…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/11/21/bahrain/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/11/21/bahrain/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travel - A Luxury</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m traveling from the sleepy town of Ella (Sri Lanka) to the city of Cebu (Philippines). Here’s how that works out. Spoiler: I spend about 52 hours in transit. Don’t do that, it’s retarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-walk&quot;&gt;The walk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around six o’clock in the evening my friends walk me to Ella train station.  Spirits are high, as we were just beginning to recover from the coconut cider drunk the night before. We pass the waiting time making fun of a particularly low-nippled stray dog running around the station. When I ask an attendant where the 3rd-class carriage carriage will stop, he mentions it might be a sleeper carriage, with beds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-train&quot;&gt;The train&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not. This becomes quite clear when the train finally arrives, but is also gleefully pointed out by my friends. We part ways on good terms anyway, and I walk out into the starry night, hop down onto the tracks and climb up into the carriage. Third class is barebones but…largely barebones, really. I sprawl out over two seats, which happens automatically if you’re wider than 30cm. The train is pretty empty at this stage. I use the first of twelve hours to craft an insightful and well-received essay on my situation. Then I plug in my headphones and start napping. I wake up as a heavy-set local squeezes in next to me. Heavy-set and twitchy: He’ll spend the next 10 hours fidgeting. I can’t sleep properly anyway. Instead, I spend the night somewhere between wakefulness and dreams. My perception of time just stops, until I notice the sky brightening. We reach Colombo at six in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bus&quot;&gt;The bus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Colombo station I find myself some Samosas for breakfast, which I eat waiting for the airport bus. I try to stare down a crow which is overtly curios about my samosa. The crow is not impressed. A few meters down the road a local guy is blowing chunks with abandon. Into a trash can - Sri Lankans are a considerate bunch. The crow and its friends are visibly excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus ride is long, but uneventful. I doze off a few times, before we reach the airport. I end up walking a kilometer to the terminal and reach it sweat-soaked around 9 in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-airport&quot;&gt;The first airport&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colombo airport is quiet and relaxed. Through the big windows I can see the tropical garden outside the terminal. Since my flight is not leaving until 4 o’clock, I can’t check in yet and end up sitting in the departure hall. My friends are all still asleep, so I have nobody to complain to. Instead, I buy chocolate. When I check in, I save 50 Euro on baggage, since the staff accepts my only bag as a carry-on. Joke’s on them, as it’s vastly overweight and held together by straining - and alarmingly frayed - compression straps. You don’t want to be anywhere near them when they eventually snap. Even more miraculously the security guys let me keep my scissors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-flight&quot;&gt;The first flight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get a window seat on our Airbus 330 and settle in. Even after flying my entire life I can’t get over how inspiring it is: I’m being hurled into the air faster than any bird, in a house made of metal, powered by continuous explosions of liquefied dinosaurs. But sure, keep reading your Financial Times, you philistine! 
Once in the air, I do fall asleep though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wake up half-way through the flight. Outside, night is falling and we’re flying right into it. The view is mesmerizing: the stars loom up over us in a black sky. Beneath them clusters of lights trace coastlines, which separate the lights which are stars from those that are ships on the black seas. It feels as if we could be among the stars if we just banked a little to the left. After a while I wipe my nose-print off the window and doze off again. We reach Kuala Lumpur at 22:00h.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-second-airport&quot;&gt;The second airport&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kuala Lumpur International Airport No. 2 (KLIA2) is vast, modern and bright. There are plenty of people around, but nobody is yelling. Shouldn’t there be yelling? This is all very confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my connecting flight to Manila only leaves at 08:20h the next morning, I have booked 12 hours in a sleeping capsule, so I have to go through immigration, even though the place is right in the terminal (“capsule by container”, KLIA2 - go look it up, I’ll wait!). I check in, take a few pictures and go hunt for dinner. The airport is more of a mall anyway, with the occasional flight arriving or departing. I end up eating junk and then book a flight out of the Philippines, which I apparently need to get a visa. I turn in around midnight local time but lie awake for almost an hour because my body clock is two hours behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get ripped out of deep sleep by my alarm after what feels like a painfully short nap. It’s 05:30h. Four and a half hours of sleep. Three thirty in the morning, by my inner clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I check out and trudge back through the airport in a state of angry, confused stupor. It’s packed with people. There are too many people here. We need a new plague. Whatever became of SARS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The walk to the gate is so long I’m beginning to wonder where the security check is. What is that hassle even good for? What if a county decided to just trust people not to be idiots and …nothing happened? What then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this airport the process is quick and efficient though. It pleases me. I’m considerably less pleased when I find out that there is no coffee available after security. This seems doubly unfair as the departure hall had two Starbucks and various other sources for that hot, black magic that keeps me moving. I refuse to eat noodles-in-a-cup for breakfast (I’m an adult) and settle for two fudge brownies (…I can do what I want!). At the gate the boarding process is fast and I’m on the plane in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-second-flight&quot;&gt;The second flight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another window seat. Fog and clouds outside. Sleep-deprived me passes out as soon as we pass through the clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pass over some insanely beautiful islands and reefs, before we land. Oddly, I see no major urban areas during our decent. Turns out, we didn’t land in Manila. Ooops! Due to bad weather we landed in the province. In Clarkfield. Now we’re refueling, to fly to Manila. Hopefully. Pleasantly little panic aboard about the delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope, one hour later we’re still standing on the airfield. I relent and order coffee. It’s amazing to see how relaxed people are about the whole thing. No whining, no complaints. Conversation and laughter instead. If I think of this happening in Europe…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, we’re taking off! After 13 minutes in the air and a generous loop over the sprawling cityscape of Manila we land at the right airport. Non-sarcastic applause fills the cabin. I stand amazed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-third-airport&quot;&gt;The third airport&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I arrived three hours late, I rush through immigration and to transfers to catch my connecting flight. Wikivoyage has Manila as one of the world’s worst airports, but what I see looks relatively orderly and efficient. A quick jog brings me to the gate just in time for the announcement that this flight is delayed by about two hours. The intended plane has failed to show up. I’m concerned over how little concern I see in the faces of other passengers: Is that normal? Will we get a similarly deadpan eulogy?
About an hour later a plane does show up at the gate just as I return from a food-run. I board the plane filled with a sense of doom and two beef-and-cheese panini.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-third-flight&quot;&gt;The third flight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isle seat. Bumpy take-off. Language hard, brain much tired. Head ouch. Are we there yet? I buy a can of beer for…several rup-…ring-…moneys. Finally the plane touches down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-fourth-airport&quot;&gt;The fourth airport&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The airport is alright. Outside it’s raining. I stand in line for a taxi and then get in a taxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-taxi&quot;&gt;The taxi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few attempts the driver finds the hostel. The city looks dark and rainy. I pay about 4 Euro for 13km and mutter something that rhymes with “clucking bell” as I stumble out of the taxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-hostel&quot;&gt;The hostel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lobby is full of blond-curled Australian surfer-dudes whose offer to join them I regrettably decline. Better save that experience for tomorrow. I grab my complimentary beer and find my dorm. 52 hours, door to door. About 4,5 hours of proper sleep, a few naps. Otherwise propelled onwards by coffee, beer and junk food. Travel, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/09/16/Travel-a-luxury/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/09/16/Travel-a-luxury/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yerevan II - The city</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So here’s the deal: I’m in Sri Lanka. My last article was in Armenia. That’s way behind, and I find it harder and harder to pretend I’m bothered by my own tardiness. Yes, I’m very forgiving that way. I’ve also gotten a bit tired of the overall style of this site: Went here, went there, did this, did that. Since I’m largely writing this for my own benefit (sorry) and to aid my memory, this doesn’t really do much for me: I already have that sort of information in my pictures (and Google’s GPS data…). At the same time I actually do enjoy writing about this journey in general. So maybe it’s time to try out a different writing style, a different method? Move away from itineraries to moments and impressions? From here on it’s going to be heavy-handed prose and pretty pictures all the way…maybe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-impressions&quot;&gt;First Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m bad with first impressions. By that I mean: I tend to get a bad first impression places and people. One of the main reasons is that I’m a certifiable retard in terms of scheduling my travels. As a result, I often arrive in new places at night, which I deal with badly. There is something about setting foot into a new city after dark that feels like stepping out into the dark jungle. By that point I’m usually tired (and grumpy), which isn’t really the mindset for exploration or adventure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By some one-in-a-million stroke of luck, my arrival in Yerevan happened in the early morning hours. On a sunny day, no less! Somehow, that made all the difference and I was quite excited to have a look at the city. So was my companion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_062206.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_062206_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After disembarking at Yerevan central, we stepped out into the sun and grabbed a taxi to my hostel. The driver took us through the city centre, which was entirely quiet due to the early morning hours. Quiet, and totally not what I had expected Yerevan to be like. Somehow, my image of Armenia had been that of an impoverished, agrarian nation. To put it bluntly, I had expected Yerevan to be a poorer, downtrodden version of Tbilisi. I was wrong. The city we saw was grand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_092645.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_092645_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_092650.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_092650_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One reason for the elegant cityscape we found ourselves in was that the Soviets “re-designed” the city in the 1960s. The result was a modern, open and airy plan for the city. On top of that, everywhere we looked, the city was well-cared for: No trash, no litter, no graffiti. The city gave of a surprisingly westernized vibe: Even off the main drag we saw various boutique stores, nice coffee shops and restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_095950.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_095950_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that day I found myself exploring the Cascades, a huge complex of art installations in the north of the city centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_100004.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_100004_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amongst other statues, the Cascades are also home to one of my favorite sculptures, a huge black lion fashioned from tire parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_100408.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_100408_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The way the sculpture captures all the traits of a predator gives you an almost physical sensation of menace&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having climbed all the stairs to the top of the Cascades, I was rewarded by this fantastic view of the city&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_100503.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_100503_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Barely visible through the haze you can see Mt. Arahat&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150608_100944.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150608_100944_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end I probably sat up top for almost an hour, slowly roasting away in the hot afternoon sun. Whenever I thought I was done, I noticed something new in the panorama before me. I couldn’t help but notice how beautiful a city Yerevan really is. It’s almost ridiculous how surprised I was by that. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/16/yerevan_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/16/yerevan_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yerevan I - Night Train</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My journey to Armenia started with a trip to the central train station in Tbilisi. For foreigners, that’s apparently the only place where they can buy train tickets. So I took a sweaty subway to the central station and walked up to the counter. The lady there looked as if she had smiled maybe once in her life and found the experience wanting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, she also understood some English so I approached the topic with all the minimalist eloquence developed during this trip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Ticket. Yerevan. Tomorrow? Bileti?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: What time? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Time? *pointing at the clock*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: *writes 10pm on a sheet of paper*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: How much money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: *holding up my wallet*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: *writes down 80 GEL and 100 GEL*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Class one and class two?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: *nods*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Yerevan. Tomorrow. Class one bileti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: Passport?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had left my passport in the hostel. Showing her a scan of my passport on my phone also elicited several headshakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Reserve bileti?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Money now. Reserve Bileti. Passport two hours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patiently massaging my temples I said a cheerful goodbye (and mumbled a few other things not fit for publication) and walked back to the subway to get my passport. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I blame myself. But I also kind of blame the Soviets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, after this trip I probably won’t be able to form coherent sentences anymore…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening of the following day, I arrived at the central station with plenty of time to spare. I was told to await the train on platform 3 and went to sit outside and enjoy the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150607_194005.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150607_194005_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Why is every place I go always deserted?&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About ten minutes before the planned departure there was no train in sight. Getting nervous, I started paying attention to the announcements on the platform. Most of it was unintelligible, but I thought I heard something like “Yerevan” and “four” in the same sentence. The only other person on platform 3 was a girl with a backpack. Of course she was a German on her way to Yerevan. Since neither of us was sure about the announcements we walked back to the service desk and were, once again, told to go to platform 3. We did, only to hear the same announcement as before. So we went back to the desk to really, really make sure. No, no, platform 3 was right. In the end, we ignored them and went to platform 4, where we just barely managed to jump on before the train pulled out of the station. We parted ways, since she had been frugal and gotten the 2nd-class ticket while I had splurged on the fancy 1st-class luxury sleeper cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150607_202135.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150607_202135_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;1st class: Two instead of four bunks per cabin&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we drove out of Tbilisi, a thunderstorm started and lightning flashed over the dark villages and Georgia’s beautiful rolling countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was standing outside my cabin and taking in the view, I was offered a bottle of wine by the guy from the cabin next door. He turned out to be a German photographer from my hometown, who was travelling around the Caucasus for both work and pleasure. Since we got along quite well, we decided to head to the dining car and have a few beers. A few beers turned into many beers, until suddenly we were ushered out of the dining car. It turned out that we had stopped at the border. Consequently, all toilets had been locked. So had the train doors. For some of us, this caused some distress. A few beers, some wine, some water even. 
It was only after having our passports checked at the Georgian side of the border that we were allowed to leave the train at the Armenian border station and use the facilities there. In return, the Armenians took close to 90 minutes to check our passports. Eventually we started moving again. I fell on my bunk and into restless, dreamless sleep as we rolled into Armenia.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/14/yerevan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/14/yerevan/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kazbegi III - Last Day in the Mountains</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One advantage of having my writing lag behind is that I get to consider episodes of my trip in hindsight.  A pattern I keep noticing is how some weeks are infinitely more eventful than others. This is the third article on Kazbegi (a trip that lasted all of the 3,5 days). Yet I know that other periods of several weeks will barely warrant more than one article. The obvious lesson is that a trip of several months is not just one exciting adventure after another. I suppose it could be, if I really wanted it to be, but who has the energy? Instead, I find that enjoying some downtime can be much more educational than frantic sightseeing. Stay in one place for a bit, have some tea, observe what is happening around you. Heck, maybe use the time to write down how you got there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aren’t these story-in-a-story things fun? So artistic, much wow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3---waterfalls&quot;&gt;Day 3 - Waterfalls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had arranged our departure from Kazbegi for the third day. Before we left this beautiful part of the world we wanted to see one last sight though: The waterfall at Gveleti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our driver from the day before drove us up towards the Russian border for about half an hour, before letting us hop out into the sun. After some back and forth (employing the usual amount of waving and pointing), we understood where he wanted us to go and we stalked off into the greenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_112753.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_112753_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The fellowship&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_113901.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_113901_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We quickly found the fast-flowing stream and then followed it up-hill. At that point, I definitely began to notice the ascents and descents of the previous days: My legs began to feel like rubber and it’s almost a miracle I didn’t faceplant straight into the stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_114044.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_114044_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we found the waterfall. The stream fell from a rocky ledge several meters up in the air. The water was then collected in a shallow basin before running down the gorge into the valley. Where we stood, a cool spray was flying everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_114307.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_114307_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The promised waterfall&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_114720.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_114720_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The view from up there wasn&#39;t so bad, either.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having relaxed at the waterfall for a bit, we climbed down the path and walked back to the waiting car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having seen this sight, we decided that it was time we drove back to Tbilisi. I recall sleeping through most of the drive back, but I did get out of the car once we stopped at this fancy monument:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_131417.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_131417_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Russian-Georgian Friendship Monument...hehe, yeah, I know!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-in-tbilisi&quot;&gt;Back in Tbilisi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Tbilisi, I checked back into the same excellent hostel I had stayed at before. I then spent another four days in Tbilsi, enjoying the usual dinners and drinks with the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150606_203754.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150606_203754_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Is that a dead fish, nailed to a painting? No, that would be absurd: It&#39;s obviously held in place by a screw!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One memory I will always cherish: We took a cab to a student-y bar near Rustaveli Square and had one hell of an evening. Chacha and beer flowed freely there. I vaguely recall randomly pointing at people, yelling “You there, you look interesting. Sit down!” To my great surprise, they tended to follow instructions rather well. That way I got to meet a singer, an event manager, the owner of the bar and a software developer from the Crimean who was very glad about finally having access to the Russian labor market. It was a long, long night…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150604_003219.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150604_003219_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A student bar in Tbilisi (early evening)&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I had to say my goodbyes to the others, who moved on to explore other parts of Georgia. Instead, I elected to book a ticket for the night train to Yerevan.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/12/kazbegi_iii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/12/kazbegi_iii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kazbegi II - Mountain Goats, Nuns and Snow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in Muscat, Oman, for two days now and have done next to nothing. Outside it’s around 43°C with 60-70% humidity. Apparently that sort of weather makes me drowsy, so I have done embarassingly little here and haven’t really seen anything either. For some random reason that makes me feel…guilty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s midnight and I’m sitting in the bath, listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RXiRpiOcWWI&quot;&gt;Beirut - Port of Call&lt;/a&gt; on repeat and sipping a Holsten Non-Alcoholic Malt Beverage Apple Flavour, which I mistook for non-alcoholic beer. Might as well get on with it then. Should we? The last article ended with a description of moonshine chacha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2---lazy-mornings-and-steep-ascents&quot;&gt;Day 2 - Lazy mornings and steep ascents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning my mouth tasted like death and felt as if a hamster had slept on my tongue. I got up with agonizing slowness, trying not to wake the pain hiding behind my temples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a thick slurry of Indian instant coffee and boiling water (ratio 1:1) and a light breakfast I almost managed to sit upright without swaying back and forth. Outside the sun was shining angrily and the sky was a hateful clear blue. Our accommodation was whisper-quiet, so I figured that the others were still in bed and, hopefully, just sleeping. Groaning, I decided to make use of the time and step outside to take care of my boots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While sitting there, groggily brushing away, our host turned up with an elderly man in tow. This man called himself the “Georgian Michael Schuhmacher” and was apparently the best driver we could get in this town. He explained the available tours in a passionate presentation. The audience - consisting only of myself, and just barely - nodded patiently. He would repeat the same pitch to all of the others during the next two days, and be disregarded every time. A pity, really, because his white Lada Niva had “adventure” written all over it. If you don’t know what a Niva is, just picture a Kalashnikov with wheels. About as comfortable a ride, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early afternoon the others began to trot around the house in the same, zombie-like state of tupor I had experienced earlier. Their livers were clearly used to more punishment though, since they began looking pretty spry just an hour later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quickly we decided on doing the hike up to Gergeti Trinity Church, which sat on top of a steep hill towering over Stepantsminda. So Rene, Manu and myself stepped out into the sunshine (Anthea had decided to relax a little longer) and started walking towards the hill. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_133733.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_133733_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Naazi Guest House, excellent branding&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, the hike would take around three hours, if we were to follow the looping serpentine sneaking around the hill. Or - amazing choice, really! No, really! - we could just walk to the foot of the hill and then walk…upwards for about 500 meters in elevation. The ascent turned out to be a painful mixture of panting, quiet cursing, louder cursing and burning quads. The view from up there was pretty special though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_141334.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_141334_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Stepantsminda from above&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_142328.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_142328_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Near the top&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About half-way up I must have stopped cursing because I couldn’t afford to waste the oxygen. Luckily, by the time I reached the top and found Manu smirking down at me, I had caught my breath again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_143102.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_143102_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A true mountain goat!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The church was built in the 14th century and looked wonderfully rustic. While it was not permitted to take pictures inside the church, the building itself and the fantastic scenery were enough to keep us occupied for a long time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_144817.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_144817_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Gergeti Trinity Church&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_144825.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_144825_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reasonably recovered from the ascent, we decided to take the same route down again. At that point, the weather began to change and the sky turned completely overcast. A bit worried, we hurried down the steep hillside (why am I always the only one falling on his ass in those moments?!). Just as we reached the town limit, another group of hikers (a family including little kids and the elderly) walked towards us and up the hill. That very moment it began to rain. By the time we reached our accommodation it rained in earnest. I wonder whatever happend to that little group. I’m sure they made it. Probably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed the evening with a decent dinner in town. I can’t recall if anybody ordered chacha that night. I reckon we might have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3---truso-valley-and-juta&quot;&gt;Day 3 - Truso Valley and Juta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we managed to get moving a bit earlier. With the help of our host we had actually found a much cheaper driver who turned up with a 8-seater Delica. That particular model seemed almost impossibly common in Stepantsminda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had planned on doing two tours on that day: Truso valley in the morning and a small mountain town called Juta in the afternoon. As it happened, our driver and his wife also ran a B&amp;amp;B. Since our original place did not have any vacancies for the coming night, we would stay at our driver’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sorting out our place for the night we hopped in the Delica and drove south along the river for about an hour before turning past some ancient-looking roadworks into a narrow valley. The Delica ambled over a precariously narrow pass right next to the muddy stream about 20m below us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the gorge opened up into a wide, green valley. We got out of the car and admired the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_114831.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_114831_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Entrance to Truso Valley&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_115128.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_115128_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amidst the greenery we found patches of unmolten snow, which obviously led to snowballs being thrown in unsuspecting faces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_120251.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_120251_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_120540.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_120540_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got back to the car, our driver drove further into the valley. Much of the road seemed flooded by meltwater, which was running into the stream. We stopped again at a tiny…village?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_123102.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_123102_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Ruins.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_124244.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_124244_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;And yet, there were people living there.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_123854.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_123854_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;One of my favourite shots of that trip.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_125848.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_125848_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking further into the valley we stumbled upon what turned out to be a nunnery. The nuns welcoming us were incredibly friendly and offered us a snack, which we took with another group of (German) tourists. The nunnery turned out to be very new, so the nuns proudly showed us around the building. This being Georgia they had a Magnum bottle of Whisky on their dinner table. Two of the younger nuns were explaining how and when the nunnery was built, while fiddling with their iPhones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_130322.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_130322_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The nunnery&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we stood there, taking in the views and washing down the hard cheese with coffee, this guy rode up on a horse. Dressed in army fatiques, carrying an army backpack and sporting some indecipherable rank insignia. Like  a scene from a movie, he rode up from the valley, passed us silently before stopping in front of one of the nuns. They exchanged a few words before he rode off towards the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_131147.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_131147_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Georgian Lucky Luke&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this somewhat bizarre encounter we walked back to the car. Our next destination was to be the town of Juta, higher up in the mountains. On the way there we drove through several smaller valleys which looked distinctly different from the somewhat winter-y Truso valley we had just left: The roads were lined with blooming trees and small gardens were almost bursting with various greenery growing through fences and hedges. Eventually, the road got steeper and steeper, as we entered another gorge. This time, the road led us at least 50m above the rapids down below. The road didn’t have much of a shoulder, so we all kept glancing back and forth between our driver and the sheer drop. There is something enjoyable about the detached amusement you feel in those moments. I mean, surely nothing is going to happen, right? Heh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our driver proved himself unflappable and delivered us to the small village. The first thing we noticed was the stream thundering down the middle of the town. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_154207.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_154207_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a round of coffees at the local cafe, we decided to climb up on top of one the hills surrounding the Juta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_162423.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_162423_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_161936.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_161936_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while of aimless wandering we found a passable trail. We decided to look at that snow you see in the distance up close:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_165059.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_165059_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end we got to within about 500 meters of it before deciding to turn around and head back. So we walked all the way back into town were we enjoyed a round of drinks before looking around for our driver. As these things go, everybody alwas sleeps on the way back. As did we, exhausted by a fair amount of hiking and that clear mountain air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening, the four of us gathered at our driver’s house were we enjoyed a fantastic home-cooked meal of traditional Georgian dishes. After a few drinks we all headed off to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/10/kazbegi_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/10/kazbegi_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kazbegi I - Mountains, Rivers and Rivers of Chacha</title>
        <description>&lt;div align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;color:gray&quot;&gt;
&quot;Oh don&#39;t give me none more of that Old Janx Spirit &lt;br /&gt;

No, don&#39;t you give me none more of that Old Janx Spirit &lt;br /&gt;

For my head will fly, my tongue will lie, my eyes will fry and I may die&lt;br /&gt;

Won&#39;t you pour me one more of that sinful Old Janx Spirit&quot; &lt;br /&gt;

-- Douglas Adams, The Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One warm evening in Tbilisi I had met two Kiwis, Anthea and Manu, on the roof terrace of our hostel. Over a few drinks we had started talking about travel plans. They intended to drive up to Kazbegi, a mountaineous region in the north, near the Russian border. Sure, why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/map_001_georgia_tbil_step.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/map_001_georgia_tbil_step.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days later, an old Mercedes arrived at the hostel. Our group consisted of Anthea and Manu (from NZ), Rene (AUS) and myself. Our driver had agreed to take us to the town of Stepantsminda for a total of 150 Lari (~50 EUR), a drive which would last about 3-4 hours. For the first third of the trip we rode through greater Tbilisi. Remember what I said about rats? Then again, the outskirts of most cities aren’t exactly scenic.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After passing the Zhinvali Reservoir, things started getting a lot more hilly. And sheep-y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_125747.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_125747_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A flock of some thousand sheep, according to the shepard. Show-off!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we reached an actual mountain road and began to climb up the serpentine. Even though most stretches of the road were not all that steep, the old Mercedes sounded like parts might come flying out the bonnet at any moment. Our driver just cruised down after every peak to compensate, so we were pleasantly slow both up- and downhill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_143457.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_143457_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, our driver was okay with us stopping for snacks and photographs. Since taking pictures from a moving car didn’t work so well (even at our slow speeds), we made use of that opportunity and admired the stunning scenery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_152154.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_152154_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Our Kiwi friends got weirdly excited at this sight.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_152540.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_152540_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;These guys nonchalantly stepped between us and the flock. Nice doggy! Peaceful doggy!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we followed a fast-flowing, muddy river through a valley until we reached the town of Stepantsminda. There, Anthea and Manu found their pre-booked apartment right next to the main square. Rene and I decided to try to get beds there, too, which worked out just fine. Hooray for not being prepared!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_155425.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_155425_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The house opposite of our accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our place was very neat and cozy. Our host had shown us the house and answered some of our questions. Then he reached into a kitchen shelf and pulled out a bottle of chacha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, yes: Chacha. Chacha is the Georgian poison of choice. It’s a clear spirit and a brandy in the widest sense, because it’s supposedly made from grapes. Or from whatever is handy and roughly grape-shaped. That could be anything, really: After a few glasses the finer points of distilling high-octane drinks will start getting lost somewhere between your eyeballs and your brain. Whether that’s due to your corneas dissolving in methanol (bad) or your neocortex drowning in ethanol (just as bad, but more fun) depends on the source: In Georgia, non-commercial moonshine is legal. It seems to range anywhere from 45% to 60% and was almost certainly distilled by somebody still in possession of their corneas. Then there are also award-winning commercial chachas made by trained professionals. In the small villages you might as well try and order a unicorn though, because your odds of getting it are roughly similar. Instead, people tend to fill their moonshine into the nice, official bottles. It doesn’t really make much of a difference either: Both the nice stuff and the moonshine give you the same note of “WhatAAARGGH!” and make your eyes water in appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, two shots of that and then off to explore the town!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_165955.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_165955_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Manu driving.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to walk to the foot of a steep mountain where we were supposed to find a church. We missed that by a wide margin but found some beautiful scenery instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_170625.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_170625_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Powerlines everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_173156.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_173156_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Heroic mountaineers!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found ourselves standing at the foot of said mountain ridge (pictured above, right behind us). Since it was still early and we were full of energy, we stopped and discussed what to do next. As we looked up the fairly steep slope, we started wondering if we could do a quick walk to maybe the half-way mark. From the distance, it definitely looked like an easy way up. I distinctly remember saying that aloud, and the others agreeing with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, where I come from, we don’t have mountains. Or hills. It’s so flat an area that standing on tip-toes will allow you to see for miles. But sure, that thing - in my expert opinion! - looked perfectly okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_180057.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_180057_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_181402.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_181402_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_181100.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_181100_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was slightly above this point that Manu and I encountered an almost vertical section consisting of loose and shifting rocks. While it would have been possible to continue, there wasn’t much to break our falls should we slip. Given our utter lack of equipment we figured this was good enough for the first day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “climb” back down was a haphazard affair of careful steps and a half-intentional slide on my hands and feet. Great fun, and nobody got hurt - surprisingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_183156.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_183156_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Slowly, slowly...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_184705.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_184705_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Looking down on clouds&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there we headed back into town, hoping to rustle up something edible. Our host had warned us that the quality of the local restaurants was mixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_185353.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_185353_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Bit of lens flare. I should really keep my phone clean.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This turned out to be true for the place we found: The waiter clearly hated his job, and us, for making him do it. The food wasn’t really to our liking. Instead we turned to the drinks menu. What was the name of that brandy again? Right: Chacha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s what we kept ordering with masochistic glee. Initially, we were brought shot glasses. Then small sherry glasses. In the end, our ‘shots’ kept arriving in the form of half-full water glasses. I recall a waitress asking “Are you sure?” as we ordered one of the last rounds…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around that time, that we figured that our behaviour  might end up harming the reputation of our respective countries. That seemed horribly inconsiderate, so we agreed that we would all pretend to be Australians. Why hurt the image of three when you could limit the harm to one, which didn’t have that much to lose to begin with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, three of us decided to call it a night and headed to bed. One however decided to have a few more drinks at some local’s grandparent’s place. That night, another colourful tale was added to the lore of Aussie travelers. I will spare you the details, but should you ever find yourself in Stepantsminda, be sure to ask the locals about their impression of Aussies!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/08/kazbegi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/08/kazbegi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tbilisi II - Visa-troubles and David Gareja</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The articles here are still almost a month behind my actual itinerary. Normally I would deal with the mounting feeling of guilt by taking a nap and then using the boost of energy to clean the kitchen or look up cat videos on Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the nap is out of the question: It’s impossible to find a sleeping position in which my lobstered skin doesn’t cause me to suffer dreams of hellfire, father-of-the-year King Stannis or the Vietnam war. Turns out, the colour of your skin can cause lots of problems. Who knew?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the absence of decent excuses I’m now sitting in the living room, not-sipping my not-coffee (because Ramadan). As its rich, smokey flavour not-fills my mouth, I’m thinking that I might as well get on with the writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Tbilisi I ended up spending little time on sightseeing, but rather more on socializing. My theory is that any person troubled by shyness or lack of friends should grab a bag, book a ticket and find themselves some nice hostels to stay in. Hostels are full of people with the strangest background and experiences! Most of them tend to actively look for other people to hang out with. That relative abundance of social interaction also puts any fears of blunders or awkwardness in perspective: So what, you’ll never see those people again - unless you want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, that’s what the choice between hotels and hostels comes down to: Would you rather talk to waiters and room service or other travelers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_001046.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_001046_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;airport-no&quot;&gt;Airport? No.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between the meals and nights out, I managed to clarify the situation regarding my visa for Iran. Clarify that I wasn’t going to get one, that is. My initial plan had been to fly into Teheran, spend two weeks roaming around Iran and then flying out to Bahrain. This actually sounded like a really good plan because of Iran’s Visa-on-arrival service, which allows citizens of some countries to just pick up a visa at the airport. Being lazy but cautious I decided to ask about that at the embass before booking my flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first attempt, I walked to the embassy (for about 90 minutes). Unfortunately, the place had closed down 10 minutes before I reached it. The opening hours listed on the website were out of date, apparently. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150526_123904.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150526_123904_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Vake Park, which I found along the way&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second attempt, I reached the embassy early and was admitted in, together with a couple from Poland. It was their second visit to the embassy, and the looks on their faces didn’t exactly inspire confidence. Sure enough, we were met by a almost-certainly-competent embassy official. I could elaborate on the specifics, but I fear that it might jeopardize my chances of getting a visa in the future. Suffice to say that he eloquently answered our initial question in one sentence: “… … … …airport? … … … no.” He really stuck to his guns and used the same sentence to answer all of our follow-up questions, too. 
Instead, he helpfully directed us towards a visa service agency, which would apply for a regular visa on our behalf, for around 200 USD. That would take around 2 weeks. For me, this meant I simply was not going to go to Iran: If I had to wait for two weeks to get a visa, I would only have around 5 days to spend in Iran before meeting my friend in Bahrain. 200 USD (visa) + ~200 USD (flight) / 5 days = 80 USD/day just to get into the country. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I had met other travelers (tourists!) who had gotten into Iran on those airport visas very recently, no problem. Plus, all Iranian government websites stated the Visa-on-Arrival was still an option. So technically, I could have just booked my ticket and hoped for the best. However, this meant running the risk of being rejected at the airport and then being forced to book a pricy flight out on the spot. I decided to trust the charming man from the embassy and leave my Iran visit for another journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;david-gareja&quot;&gt;David Gareja&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that sorted, I decided to explore the Tbilisi area some more. Luckily, I had met some interesting people at the hostel before (Hi, Rene!) and we decided to do a day-trip to the David Gareja monastery right on the Georgian-Azerbaijani border. The orthodox monastery was founded in the 6th century and consists of dozens of chapels, caves and buildings. Today, the area is the object of a border dispute between Georgia and Azerbaijan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We picked a tour operator near Liberty Square and were directed to a waiting car. It must have been a slow day, because it was only the two of us, an Italian guy and an Austrian lady, and the driver. He would drive us to the monastery, we would complete a short hike there and then be driven back. Luckily, our driver was very accommodating of our tourist-y desire to take pictures of…everything and stopped frequently along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_122615.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_122615_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Endless landscapes&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_125258.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_125258_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Endless sheep&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monastery itself turned out to be a fairly low-key affair: It is still operating (monks are still monking) and thus much of it is off-limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_132417.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_132417_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Caves dug into the side of Mount Gareja&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_132625.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_132625_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The chapel&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_133331.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_133331_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Inside the chapel&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the monastery behind, we started our hike up the cliff towards the Azerbaijani border. The temperature must have hovered around 35°C and the path was baked solid by the sun. The path was also quite steep, so after a short while we were all sweat-soaked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_135138.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_135138_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Rene and Marco figuring out the route from an A4 map provided by our driver&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Is that humming in your head the sign of an oncoming headache? You haven’t drunk enough water, clearly. And no aspirin on you. Yep, definitely a headache. One of those pulsing ones. Ka-CHOCK….Ka-CHOCK. Awesome.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few hundred meters of steep ascent we reached the top of the ridge. There, sitting on a huge rock, we found two Azerbaijani soldiers on watch, who called us in on their radio. Interestingly enough, they did not check our passports or require any documents. And thus we sat foot into Azerbaijan. The view from up there was stunning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_141130.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_141130_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The north of Azerbaijan actually looks...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_141250.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_141250_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;...a lot like the south of Georgia&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then followed a footpath along the ridge and found several small caves with wallpaintings and inscriptions. All of these were outlying parts of the monastery and still used as places of worship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_142018.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_142018_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Caves along the south slope of Mount Gareja&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_142106.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_142106_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Another cave&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_142528.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_142528_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;And another cave&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we made our way up to the peak of the ridge, where we checked back in with two Georgian soldiers sitting in the shade of a chapel there. We ended up spending half an hour just admiring the landscape and trying to snap a few good shots of the enormous birds of prey that circled around us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_145448.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_145448_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_145910.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_145910_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A bird!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, we climbed down the other side of the ridge, back towards the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_151705.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_151705_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Down the north slope of Mount Gareja&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back, we had a lunch-stop in the town of Udabno. As these things go, the only restaurant there was operated by our driver’s parents. Their entire community had been relocated to this area after their hometown in Svaneti had been devastated by a rockslide. The Soviets had begun building a completely new town for them, when the USSR collapsed and the money ran out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_160822.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_160822_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Udabno&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick lunch there, we all slept through the entire drive back to Tbilisi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1300 words! On a sunday, no less! Next time: Another episode of “Wanna come?” - “Sure, why not?” with mountains, sheep and chacha - nectar of the gods and terror of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/06/tbilisi_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/06/tbilisi_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tbilisi I - Arrival and doing not much</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, yes: the writing. The writing which I promised to do regularly. &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; writing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the above three sentences in an agonizing fifteen minutes, I got up and fetched myself a cup of coffee. Then I groaned to myself a little and pulled my own hair for a bit. But now I’m good. Excited to continue the tale!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left off - I remember distantly - when I took a coach from Batumi to Tbilisi. Metro, the coach company I had used so frequently in Turkey, offered a comfortable 5-hour trip to Tbilisi. Being the lazy sort I had a relaxed breakfast in Batumi first, and then got on the coach in the early afternoon. We drove up north along the coast for about two hours before turning east and driving into the country, towards the capital. I’ll spare you the details, but here is the summary: Georgia is beautiful. Really, really beautiful. That’s about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the outskirts of Tbilisi in the late afternoon. Remember what I wrote about Batumi looking pleasantly post-apocalyptic? The outer districts of Tbilisi looked worse. Within half an hour we went from “Oh, pretty hills!” to “Oh, a rat!” to “Oh, a guy…barbecueing a rat”. This surprised me, since I had heard very positive things about Tbilisi in general. Luckily, my concerns were unfounded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got off the coach near the city centre and found myself standing in the middle of a neat-looking high street (Rustaveli Avenue), which also leads to the parliament and the Georgian National Museum.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_195121.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_195121_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;On Rustaveli Avenue&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived, the entire road was blocked for traffic, as they were preparing for a parade: People were in the process of erecting stages and assembling stands. Bands were practicing and every available space was covered in billboards and posters. Despite the commotion I managed to find a cafe with wifi and find myself a suitable hostel. Then I shouldered my way back through the crowd and towards the southern part of town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_195532.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_195532_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Liberty Square, at the southern end of Rustaveli Avenue&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There, right at the foot of a massive hill and under the remains of Narikala Fortress I found the excellent Envoy Hostel. On top of all other amenities, it had a fantastic roof terrace!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_201831.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_201831_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View from the hostel roof terrace&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dark, I ventured down the hill and found myself something to eat. Next, I followed a bridge into a park on the other side of the river, and spent some time reading there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_203552.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_203552_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The park. That subtle, understated building in the background? The presidential palace.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, I called it an early night and headed back across the river and to bed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_214627.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_214627_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Shiny bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I heard from the hostel staff that I had actually managed to arrive just in time for Georgian independence day (May 26th). Curious, I headed out towards liberty square and had a look at the little military parade organized there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150526_112531.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150526_112531_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150526_112644.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150526_112644_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the whole affair wasn’t as action-packed as I had hoped, I decided to ignore the festivities and get coffee instead. That’s pretty much what I did on my second day in Tbilisi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150527_164627.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150527_164627_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Came up to me, looked at me, sat down on me.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite honestly, I didn’t feel like hardcore sight-seeing when I was in Tbilisi. So I just enjoyed wandering around town and having a look at various districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150528_105524.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150528_105524_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View of Narikala Fortress from the foot of the hill&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my hostel was very close to the fortress, I took a detour up there (using the cable car of course…what am I, a farmer?). While the fortress consisted of nothing more than its walls, I enjoyed climbing up to the parapet and taking in the view of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150528_112215.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150528_112215_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View of the castle from the northern side.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150528_113221.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150528_113221_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View down into town. That brownish thing is a river, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would end up staying in the Tbilisi area for around 5-6 days before heading north with a few new-found friends. All in all, I found the city pretty, but not overly exotic. For my personal productivity that was excellent news, but not necessarily the material for riveting stories. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phew, that’s a whole lot of writing right there! A good day’s work! I’ll take a break now. Next time, I’ll explain why I didn’t end up going to Iran and tell you how we crossed into Azerbaijan without passports!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/05/tbilisi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/05/tbilisi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Batumi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The third country of my trip was Georgia. I crossed the border at Sarpi and took a minibus from there to Batumi. The whole ride lasted about half an hour and cost me a single Lari (about 0.40 Euro). As we drove up the coast, I enjoyed the view of the empty beaches and the hilly countryside. Much of the scenery reminded me of a slightly more summer-y Poland. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun broke through the morning haze eventually and the streets become more and more lively as we reached Batumi. The city is a famous holiday destination and especially popular with tourists from Poland and the Ukraine. As we drove into the city centre, I noticed the fairly typical shape tourism has given Batumi: The outskirts looked pleasantly post-apocalyptic, the way former soviet-territories do. Rusty cars, about-to-collapse buildings and entire neighbourhoods which looked like they were held together only by duct tape and stubborn optimism. Or at least a shared confidence that things were not likely to get &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; worse in the immediate future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as we neared the city’s port, the influence of tourist money became very visible: Newer buildings, well-maintained facades and roads, lots of hotels and restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150523_085951.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150523_085951_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The port&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got off the bus there and grabbed an early coffee at a cafe on the promenade. There, I also tried my first Adjarian Khachapuri. This entire country seems to survive on various kinds of Khachapuri (cheesy dough baked goods). Case in point: Beggars will approach you repeating “Khachapuri, Khachapuri”. The Adjarian is baked dough in an open boat shape and has a raw egg on top of the feta-like cheese. Yes, most dishes here are very hearty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_103128.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_103128_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Main square&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I found myself a decent hostel (for 6 EUR/night) and took a nap which lasted for most of the day. My afternoon exploration was cut short by the onset of torrential rain, so I stayed in. In the evening, another hostel-guest from Poland and I went out to grab dinner, before calling it an early night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_104842.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_104842_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The obligatory seaside shot&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning the rain had stopped and I took a long walk around town and along the promenade. Since tourist season here does not start before July, most places were very empty and I struggled to find a place for breakfast. While I got increasingly frustrated at people telling me they didn’t serve coffee, I really appreciated the fact that most people seemed to speak English willingly. It’s nice to be denied in english!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the promenade you get plenty of hotels and casinos, many of them either new or still in the process of construction. And then you get this thing, which apparently belongs to the university: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_142143.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_142143_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Yeah, that building in the distance has a built-in ferris wheel. Does yours not have that?&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, circling back to the harbor, I came across this fine example of sturdy Cold War engineering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_142451.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_142451_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A semi-submersible...semi-submersed.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Batumi is marked by these strong contrasts: In front of the hotels and casinos you find plenty of Bentleys and Ferraris, other parts of town are just casually rotting to pieces. Besides this absurdity, Batumi did not really hold much of interest. To me, it seemed like a typical tourist town - at that point, minus the tourists - who would come there to swim, drink, eat and gamble. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_193649.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_193649_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The old part of town&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_194249.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_194249_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Another square and a fountain with lots of boobs&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, I decided that I was going to leave Batumi the next day. I ended up going out for dinner with my Polish aquaintance and enjoying a relaxing beer on the promenade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_202456.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_202456_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;I really need to stop posting these...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I got up nice and early and walked to the coach station on the other side of town. There, I got on a coach to Tlbl…Tblbl…the capital.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/02/batumi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/02/batumi/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
