<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Escaping Sloth</title>
    <description>...very slowly</description>
    <link>http://rkwrd.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rkwrd.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Another travel site?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as I had settled in on Thessaloniki&amp;rsquo;s lustrous promenade, my peace was disturbed by a scary thought. Staring into the sunset over the bay and puffing on my celebratory cigar I was startled by the question &amp;ldquo;What if my friends forget about me?&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before my departure some of my friends had indeed asked for regular status updates on my trip and/or whether my head was still attached to my shoulders (Day 1: yes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleary keeping my friends informed one by one seems like a lot of repetition. It&amp;rsquo;s likely that I would eventually start neglecting that task and lose touch. I can easily remedy this by putting regular updates online at a central location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I don&amp;rsquo;t really like or trust Facebook anymore, so putting all my stuff on there didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly appeal to me.
The obvious consequence then is a website, something I had discussed with some of my friends as well.
Here is the problem though: Since I am now traveling, my site would be a travel site. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t like travel sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst preparing for my trip I had skimmed through many travel-related sites. Quite simply too many of them were shit. 
Most of them seem to consist of listicles (a topic worthy of a rant of its own. Spoiler: I don&amp;rsquo;t like them.), &amp;ldquo;me at the beach&amp;rdquo; type pictures and rather heavy-handed prose.
I&amp;rsquo;m positive that&amp;rsquo;s not the kind of writing I would want to spend time on. Partially because of my drastic aversion to listicles, partially since I&amp;rsquo;m way too pale to be photographed at the beach. Lastly, I&amp;rsquo;m not under the delusion that I&amp;rsquo;m any kind of Hemingway.
So what is this site going to be then? 
Hopefully not a travel site!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I enjoy traveling, this undertaking was never meant to be about the travel itself. Instead, I wanted to have the freedom and energy to immerse myself in topics I find interesting. I could have gone  the formal-education route and lined up for another degree, tuition fees and a set curriculum. Instead I decided to pursue those interests on my own. That way I can spend the money saved at locations which are all a) sunnier, b) cheaper and c) friendlier than my birthplace. And if that&amp;rsquo;s the idea, why limit myself to one location? There, that&amp;rsquo;s how it accidentally turned into a trip.
So ideally, this site will be mainly be growing on articles on the topics I&amp;rsquo;m researching (and of course various vitriolic rants).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despair not, ye of little faith, I will surely write the occasional bit on my whereabouts (and yes, the status of my neck). Prepare for pictures of beaches, wine-glasses and my horribly sun-burned mug. Hell, I might even take a shot at some destination-related articles with a bit of substance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since writing here is also a desperate attempt to build some sort of self-discipline, please feel free to give me a friendly nudge between the eyes if I&amp;rsquo;m getting too lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s start this experiment then, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 21:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://rkwrd.github.io//2015/03/18/another-travel-blog/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rkwrd.github.io//2015/03/18/another-travel-blog/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So long, suckers!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;What better words to start a personal blog?&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://rkwrd.github.io//2015/02/22/so-long-suckers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rkwrd.github.io//2015/02/22/so-long-suckers/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>