<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Escaping Sloth</title>
    <description>...very slowly</description>
    <link>http://escapingsloth.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://escapingsloth.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Istanbul, again</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Him: “So what’s that tattoo say?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: “Well, it used to say ‘Curt’, my ex’s name.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Him: “And now?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: “Now it says…something similar. Still reminds me of him, too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Overheard in a hostel lounge)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahhh, Istanbul! Beating heart of empires past! A city built, cultivated, pillaged, burnt and then rebuilt. And then pillaged and burnt again. An immense melting pot with millenia-long history, steeped in an air of timelessness. Full of cats, too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached Istanbul after a 7-hour overnight bus ride. While the coaches are comfortable enough, sleeping is almost impossible because they stop often. Lights are turned on and announcements are made. People shuffle on or off the bus. People who seriously need to learn to shut the hell up. The journey was a fairly disorientating experience of drifting between wakefulness and sleep. At some point somebody shook me awake, repeating “Istanbul, Istanbul!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I took the hint and stumbled off the bus out into a grey-ish dawn, clutching my backpack and travel blanket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 008:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Get a travel blanket! Mine is almost full-sized but very thin, so it’s compact. It’s nice to have something to keep you warm or keep the light out of your eyes. Whichever bed I go to sleep in, once I spread out&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;blanket, it becomes&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;bed. Rolled up in a ziploc-bag it compresses a lot and stays dry, too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Istanbul is home to around 14 million people, it has at least four large coach stations. Helpfully, the coach driver had woken me at the one closest to the area I was going to stay in, called Sultanahmet. At this hour however, the massive coach station was deserted. The sun was not up yet, so the entire site was grey buildings, grey tarmac and grey skies. I shouldered my backpack and just walked around for a few minutes to see where exactly I had to go. It turned out that the station was around 11-12 subway stops away from where I wanted to go. Since the metro seemed like the easiest mode of transport anyway, I went looking for the metro station. Just like your typical bloody tourist would, I ended up wandering all over the coach station, mistakenly walking into at least one storage building and one underground garage. I finally found the metro station (cleverly hidden right in the middle of the coach station). From there, it was a relatively straight forward trip east towards Sultanahmet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150419_181125_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sultanahmet, the east-most part of the city’s European half, is its oldest and most famous district. It contains the Hagia Sophia, the Blue Mosque, the ancient Hippodrome, the Topkapi Palace and several museums. It is the most tourist-y part of town with many hotels and hostels. It is also where I found &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; hostel, which I immediately identified as such because they had kittens!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think that cats are alright. Sure, I took a few pictures. But it’s not like I’m a crazy cat person with dozens of pictures of kittens on their phone. Just a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150424_230757_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150419_071918_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150419_223358_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, one more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150420_153635_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there such a thing as a “cat habit”? You know, like a “coke habit”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed in Istanbul for five or six days (no, I really can’t tell). Since I had been to the city before, I had gotten most of the big sights out of the way already. So this time around I spend most days just walking around and exploring the more lived-in districts. Ironically, I took no pictures there, so here are some more common views instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150420_181632_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150420_181328_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150421_185657_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On most days this meant 6-hour walks. On two days, the weather was actually so terrible that I barely left the hostel, except for food/coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150422_125934_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeup, that’s sleet. From the thunderstorm which nearly flooded Gülhane Park in a torrential downpour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the hostel I also spent time with a group of other travelers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An Australian solicitor (Hi, David!)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Another Aussie and his Kiwi friend who were in town for ANZAC day&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A couple from Boston&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A data analyst from London (Hi, Paul!)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also used the occasion to visit the famous Topkapi palace, which I hadn’t seen during my last trip. The palace is a mindbogglingly ornate affair located at the northern tip of Sultanahmet. It served as residence of the Ottoman sultans 15th-19th century. Today, it’s a UNESCO site with lots of visitors and almost as many selfie-sticks. Seriously, people: You have arms, right? What the hell is the world coming to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150422_172556_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150422_172644_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150422_173056_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150422_175536_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember being thoroughly impressed by two exhibits in the palace:
Firstly, the scrolls and calligraphy in the privies. The amount of detail in the carvings above pales in comparison with the granularity and precision shown in the religious manuscripts. Unfortunately I did not take any pictures of them, but their effect is startling: You tend to get lost in the levels of detail. Every pattern is made up of smaller, more intricate patterns, which in turn contain their own symmetries and rules. Taking pictures of these with a cellphone camera seemed a bit pointless…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the religious artifacts in the Chamber of Sacred Relics. It’s not every day that you get to see Moses’ very own staff! You’d think that even by conservative estimates of biodegradation, that thing would be gone by now. But no, there it is! They also have Abraham’s saucepan™. I had been told of this unique item before, still I felt incredibly privileged to find myself in the company of such distinguished cookware. I didn’t take pictures of those, you’ll have to go see them yourselves. Or google it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I also found myself in a Turkish heavy metal bar. I know, but the band did play some great covers of Led Zeppelin, Megadeth and Anthrax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Istanbul is obviously a colourful city with a rich history. Exploring its facets as a tourist is an amazing experience and I’m sure I will come back here. At the same time, the second trip here showed me some of the more mundane, less exciting aspects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer number of people and extent of the city feel suffocating at times. The districts feel like they are just going on and on and on. For most people, living here seems a trade-off: Either you sacrifice a sizable share of your income to rent a centrally-located apartment, or you spend hours of your life commuting through traffic the consistency of jam mixed with bunker fuel. Two examples: One, even on the busiest highways around the city you find men selling bottled water and pretzels while standing right between the lanes. That sounds risky, but there really is no danger to them, since traffic barely moves at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two, when I eventually took a coach to Safranbolü, 90 minutes of the six-hour ride were spent just on getting out of Istanbul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This being the capital, most things tend to be just a little more expensive than in other parts of the country. Food, drink, fares, you name it. Both in Izmir and in Ankara I spoke to locals who had at some points in there lives moved to Istanbul. They all told me that they had moved back for a higher quality of life and standard of living. Counterpoint: I also met plenty of people in Istanbul who had moved there and had no plans of moving away again, because, you know, it’s Istanbul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While those realizations were sobering, they did reassure me that coming back and taking a look behind all those important sights was worthwhile: I only noticed those things because I spent more time here and had the leisure to observe in peace. If you only come to Istanbul for a few days, by all means take in all those magnificent buildings and museums, they are worth your time. But then make time to come here again, and use it to meandre around the city. Have coffee somewhere and have a look around. Go to the less pretty parts of town and soak up all the glances which say “The hell are you doing here?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days however, I happened to look at a world map in the hostel. And then at a calendar. I got angsty, so I packed my bag, did some hasty research and took a tram to the coach station. Eastwards! Actually, the coach station was west, which turned out to be a stupid mistake, as you’ll see…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/28/istanbul/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/28/istanbul/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Izmir, again</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I left Greece with the confidence that I had gained deep and meaningful insights into the psyche of its culture, history and people. Unfortunately, I can’t exactly remember any of them right now, so let’s just move on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bodrum&quot;&gt;Bodrum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s also what I did, leaving Kos on a completely unspectacular little boat on a somewhat overcast day. It took that boat almost an hour to reach the Turkish coast and the city of Bodrum. I spent that time on deck, with a beer in my hand and the wind in my hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow it had completely slipped my mind that Turkey is not part of the Schengen Agreement, so the passport control at the pier took me by surprise. Then again, German citizens get in without a visa or anything. Beautiful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a related note: Next time you go through passport control, pay close attention to the officer at the counter. The instant you hand them your passport, they will be completely puzzled for a second. I can only assume that the following thought process takes place: “Huh, what am I supposed to do with this? …Oh, right. I work for the border patrol, I’m supposed to check those things.”
Every. Single. Time. The more often I observe this phenomenon, the funnier it gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleared to enter the country I had a quick look around the port area and the center of Bodrum. Then I hastily walked towards the coach station. Looking at the crowds of early-bird tourists I felt no urgent need to stay in Bodrum any longer than I had to. So instead, I took a coach to Izmir straight away. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it hypocritical that the sight of tourists makes me run for the hills, given that I’m clearly a tourist myself? There, I said it: I’m a tourist. Not going to waste time trying to polish that turd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride from Bodrum to Izmir took about 4 hours on a nice, new coach which was effectively empty. Once we left Bodrum, I was instantly reminded why I had wanted to go back to Turkey: Holy hell, the Turkish Riviera is beautiful! I sat on this airconditioned, wifi-enabled gem of a coach and watched the sun set over a ragged coastline, sloping hills and a mountain highway. For most of that drive I struggled to keep my mouth closed and my nose from leaving prints on the windows. The fields and woods outside were showing incredible hues of green. Every single tree and bush seemed to be blooming. Meadows and hillsides shone in the last rays of sunlight and looked almost unnaturally &lt;em&gt;green&lt;/em&gt;. So &lt;em&gt;green&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;izmir&quot;&gt;Izmir&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached Izmir around 11pm. The last time I had been here I had seen the coach station, a hotel and the airport. Then it was just a layover on the way to Istanbul, but this time I wanted to explore the city, too. From what I saw, it certainly offered many, many shades of beige.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coach operater (Metro) offers free shuttle buses from the often remote coach stations to the city center. Hooray for shiny coaches! Since I had looked up a hostel beforehand, I got the driver to let me out of the shuttle at Basmane Square:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: &lt;em&gt;points and grunts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driver: &lt;em&gt;grunts questioningly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: &lt;em&gt;grunts affirmatively&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driver: &lt;em&gt;opens door&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: &lt;em&gt;grunts gratefully&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had a look around, I actually remembered the square from my last stay. Then I walked north towards the hostel, along the giant Kültürpark and into a part of town which is basically just one giant high street. From there I took a sideroad and ended up at the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Izmir is Turkey’s 3rd largest city (after Istanbul and Ankara) with a population of around 4 million and about 4000 years of history. Unfortunately a combination of earthquakes, petty wars and the occasional kitchen fire getting out of hand left the city without many historical sights. On the other hand, Izmir is a very modern and open city with a fairly young population. Quality of life there seemed pretty high: The city is smaller and cheaper than Istanbul, while being just as worldly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next four days I would stay in Izmir, take long walks around the city and study at coffee shops. I would also, for once, not look at ancient stuff, since there wasn’t any. I stayed at that first hostel which I had booked online - chosen due to its good reviews. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using those booking sites has been a mixed experience: Recently I’ve grown more and more frustrated with them. There is a plethora of sites such as booking.com, hostels.com, hostelworld.com and hostelbookers.com. All of them have review mechanisms and rankings for hostels. Yet, for every well-rated hostel that deserved its laurels, I’ve stayed at one which simply did not. Another big drawback is that booking a hostel via one of those sites locks in the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 007:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Booking sites obviously charge a commission, which we supposedly pay for convenience and validation through reviews. Yet if the convenience makes my travel plan less flexible, and the reviews are not reliable, what exactly am I paying for? Here is what I recommend instead:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look up a few suitable places online.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upon arrival, take a look at those hostels and the neighbourhood.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Walk in through the door, ask about vacancies and have them show you some of their rooms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask them about the price per night.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask: “Could I pay [75% of that]?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store your bag and go spend the money you just saved on coffee!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Izmir, my exploits mainly consisted of walking around the city and chugging liters of coffee at coffee shops on the promenade. Neither of those lends itself to terribly impressive pictures, so here are few generic ones instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150416_192251_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The promenade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150416_114732_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
I like that people in Turkey actually take care of the stray cats and dogs. Looking at you, Greece!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150416_115507_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
This left me giggling for at least five minutes. Mainly because of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5nRzh4CJTZs&quot;&gt;this clip from the show Community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, even at mediocre hostels you meet interesting people. Case in point: I spend a day with a delightful couple from Australia and two students from the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150418_194815_1_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days, I got restless in Izmir. Looking at a map I began to hear Istanbul calling, and that call just didn’t feel like it could be denied. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/26/izmir/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/26/izmir/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My personal Grexit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since Kos was the last destination in Greece, I should probably wrap up my experience there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-pre-season-for-a-reason&quot;&gt;It’s pre-season for a reason&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, I was there at the wrong time. Well, technically every Greek person assured me that normally the weather isn’t this bad this time of year. The effect was the same though: I remember being cold more often than being warm. I also used my rainjacket way more than my sunscreen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, being there before all the tourists was a blessing. Especially on the islands many locals told us various horror-stories about the numbers of tourists that would descend on the small towns like drunk, sunburned and tattooed locusts. If that’s not your thing - it certainly isn’t mine - than you really want to go to the islands outside of main season. Given my experience with the weather, I would probably prefer to go post-season rather than pre-season. That way, the weather might be a bit more predictable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nobody-told-me-they-hated-me&quot;&gt;Nobody told me they hated me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, at least not to my face. Coming from Germany, I had some mild reservations about going to Greece. “Sorry your economy is in the toilet, but isn’t it lovely how cheap everything is?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow this never came up. I didn’t even see any riots in Athens, which was a bit of a letdown, really. No burning flags or Merkel effigies either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had several conversations with locals about the whole topic (mostly young people). The consensus there seemed to be that the whole Euro-kerfuffle was a thing of politics, and politics were always fucked up. You know, the elites oppressing the little people like you and I. But you and I, we get along just fine, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand that was reassuring to hear. On the other hand, I could not help but wonder if the fact that I sat right across from them may have moderated their positions a bit. Maybe they they secretly harbored more negative opinions? After all, I couldn’t really blame them for being angry about the economic situation. One way or another, people were consistently friendly, so I have no complaints there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;everybody-here-should-be-fat&quot;&gt;Everybody here should be fat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right at the start of my trip, in Thessaloniki, I asked the hostel staff to recommend a restaurant. “You like meat?” they asked back. Those words warmed my heart. Why yes, I do! And meat likes me! Meat and I are made for each other!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a meat perspective, Greece was all I could have asked it to be. Grilled, fried, cooked, you name it. Meat of course does not make anyone fat. Virtually anything else served here does. The sheer variety of pies, puff pastries and sugary desserts would be enough to give a heart attack a bad case of the beetus (sic). Yet, you rarely see overweight people. Certainly none of the towering hamplanets you tend to get in some Anglosaxon countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One explanation must be that most of Greece is built on hills. So whereever you go, you’re either working your way up an incline or doing your best not to fall down one. The other explanation might lie in portion control. Most foreigners clearly sucked at that: On one occasion, two Americans and I devoured a huge serving of juicy, sugary baclava right in the bakery. The digusted look the owner gave us had “You animals!” written all over it. I think we may have obliterated what was meant to be a family serving…each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The locals seem to pace themselves a bit better: Most restaurants offer decent servings but nothing excessive. Many of the locals tend to consume various greenery with their meat. Maybe that’s their secret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;damn-its-a-beautiful-country&quot;&gt;Damn, it’s a beautiful country&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even ignoring all other benefits Greece has to offer, the nature alone would compel me to go again. I didn’t see a single part (excluding Patisia, Athens) that wasn’t beautiful in some way. You know what I’m talking about, you saw the pictures! Hills, mountains, rivers, cliffs, fields, and of course the sea. Oh, the sea! If nothing else, go there for the sea!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/21/my-personal-grexit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/21/my-personal-grexit/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kos</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;grumpy-mornings&quot;&gt;Grumpy mornings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last leg of my journey through Greece I took a ferry from Santorini to the island of Kos. Kos is actually so close to the Turkish coast that most people tend to assume the island is part of Turkey. It is also what you might call a tourist shithole. But since it was pre-season still, I resolved to try my luck before escaping to Turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I ended up taking a ferry from Santorini close to one o’clock in the morning. As I had chosen the cheapest ticket, I did not get a cabin like a civilized person would. Instead I boarded the ferry (yes, shiny blue ferry!) with a handful of bleary-eyed tourists and began looking for a cushioned, flat surface. The ferry had come all the way from Athens and stopped at several islands. Consequently, all the good spots were already taken. I resigned myself to a short stretch of couch I extended with a heavy high-backed chair. Voila!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fleece rolled up as a pillow, rainjacket as a blanket and earplugs to give me peace and quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 005:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Earplugs! Unlike most of the other lessons, this is one I actually learned a while back. You can’t travel without earplugs. Maybe you think you can, because you’re an exceptionally heavy sleeper. But some day you’ll sleep in a dorm with a Romanian truck driver. Or on a boat with a broken muffler. Or there is a noisy civil war going on. In any of those cases, earplugs will keep you from rising grumpy.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rose &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; grumpy. In part, because the entire night Greek action movies were blaring from a nearby TV and the occasial explosion must have reached my ear. Mostly though, because I knew we would arrive around 04:30h. Somehow knowing that I get to sleep very little makes it impossible for me to get any sleep whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all I was not at my best as a grabbed my possessions and trudged down the stairs to the ferry’s gangway…at 04:30h. I remember standing inside the neon-lit belly of the ferry and viciously chewing on a piece of gym. Amidst the cars stood other passengers, few of them looked well-rested. Most of them must have felt just as exhausted as I did, but I was tired and therefor pissed off, so I glared at them angrily anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon a klaxon rang out and the loading gate was lowered with an unnecessary amount of noise. Stupid klaxon, stupid loading gate. Looking out, Kos didn’t seem like anything special. Stupid Kos. Then again, I only saw the outlines of some buildings and a few yellow-ish streetlights. For a moment I was wondering: Why do I do this again?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, my arrival protocol consists of sitting down for a cup of coffee and taking a moment to gather my wits. At 04:30h in the morning this wasn’t really an option and my wits felt pretty far gone anyway. Since I didn’t think I’d be able to check into any rooms, I decided to go for a walk around the port instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grumpiness nonwithstanding, I began to wonder if I was onto something as I noticed the massive ancient stonewalls surrounding part of the port. Intrigued I took some detours and found myself striding through a silent park and through gates in the walls. The air was cool and rich with the smell of blooming trees and bushes. Just as I reached the other side of the port, the horizon lit up. I found myself staring at the sun rising over the Turkish coast in the distance. For half an hour I just stood there, watching as the sunlight washed over the harbor, the marina and the small cafes and restaurants on the promenade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_060416_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_061419_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_061936_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Right, THIS is why I’m doing this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly a lot less grumpy, I wandered off towards the city centre, along the beach. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_064703_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_065408_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
This, right here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considerably reassured about the purpose of my travels I found a place renting out apartments and sat down on the stairs overlooking the still street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, a stately-looking lady opened the door and invited me in. Through a mixture of my roguish charme, my pityfully exhausted appearance and the fact that it was still pre-season, I managed to haggle the price down to half. And thus I got two nights in a double for 20 euros. After dumping my stuff I went for a walk and got breakfast. Then I took a long, luxurious nap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lazy-days&quot;&gt;Lazy days&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I basically continued that nap, with minor interruptions, for two more days. Whenever I accidentally woke from my slumber - pesky biorythm! - I would go for a walk. The town looked about as empty as my brain felt, so I mostly stuck to the equally deserted beach. I passed the time wandering along the waterline and skipping flat stones over the waves. This mindless process of “See stone” -&amp;gt; “Grab stone” -&amp;gt; “Throw stone” -&amp;gt; “Repeat” proved almost meditative. Time begins to slow and eventually breaks down around you when you’re looking for that perfect stone and that perfect pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point I foolishly attempted to streamline the logistics by gathering a big pile of suitable stones and then chucking them all in quick succession. Of course that’s a hugely efficient and Germanic thing to do. It also totally defeats the purpose of the exercise and almost left me with a dislocated shoulder. After that experience I ended up throwing with my weaker, left arm, which must have looked every bit as spastic as you would think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 006:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The secret to good skipping lies in both the stone and the throwing movement. You want a stone which is smooth and flat-ish. A certain amount of rounded bevel is necessary for it to skip upon contact with the waves, so shards of ceramic or flint don’t work. I find that a slightly oblong shape of about 8-10cm provides better leverage for my fingers, resulting in better spin and thus more jumps. For the throw, I prefer a looping sideways pitch with a neutral grip. Haha, did you suckers really just spend 3 minutes reading about a guy chucking rocks in the sea?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recall taking a long walk through Kos’ impressive marina. The entire thing was a charming mixture of clear blue water and…well, lots of boats. I don’t really know anything about boats. Most of them where white, relatively shiny and somewhere between “somewhat large” and “definitely very large indeed”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_095450_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150413_095444_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Do you think this thing would be fast?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking decidedly out of place I resolved to walk around very purposefully. I also spent some serious time devising witty answers in case anybody asked me which one of the boats was mine. “Oh, just browsing, really. You got anything you’d recommend for whaling?”
Unfortunately, I must have walked so purposefully that people were just too intimidated to stop and ask me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not ashamed to admit that the days in Kos were anything but productive (though I did manage to watch a series of videos on relational algebra). I’m lazy, so sue me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two days I began to feel that particular itch in my bones, telling me to move on. So I took a ferry from Kos over to Bodrum, Turkey. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/20/kos/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/20/kos/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stranded, part III - Look at that water! Look at it!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;eastersaturday&quot;&gt;Easter…Saturday?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day after all the sparks and stuff was pretty low-key. I recall spending most of the day either reading, eating or napping. Judging from my photographs of that day, I must have spent a good share of the day with a cat sleeping on my chest. A recurring theme: I’m writing these lines with a 6-week old kitten sleeping snuggled in my fleece jacket. Don’t believe me? Joke’s on you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150420_153626_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we wanted to go see the fireworks. A guy working at the hostel had gotten us all excited about it. He used the words “homemade bombs” and “loud as hell”, so of course we wanted to go. He had even shown us a few videos from his hometown, which really did look like the world was coming to an end in a hurricane of colourful lights and explosions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the evening we gathered the group from the night before (plus a few additions) and sauntered over to the cliff to watch the sunset. It did indeed set, and it was magnificent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I remember - I really need to start writing these articles in a more timely fashion - we went out for a drink afterwards. At midnight - I think - we went up to the biggest church in Fira to see the ceremony. A crowd was already waiting, holding unlit candles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a procession exited the curch and sang a song or two, they began lighting candles from a candle brought from the church. No ordinary flame this, but a descendant of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holy_Fire&quot;&gt;Holy Fire&lt;/a&gt;. Yep, brought from the grave of Jesus Christ by the orthodox patriarch himself. A miracle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pilgrims and clergy claim that the Holy Fire does not burn them.” (So quoted on Wikipedia) 
That’s just asking for it, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I digress. The flame was handed out to the crowd accompanied by cheering, hugging and some more singing. Then the fireworks began: Teenagers began throwing firecrackers into the church yard. Amplified by the building, one loud BANG after another rang out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that was it. For a moment we were left wondering when the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; fireworks would start. No, that was it. Even without the high expectations after the night before this would have been a let-down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this trip I’ve indiscriminately taken pictures of almost everything. Not of this ceremony though, which should tell you something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shaking our heads - and in two cases clutching our holy candles - we headed back towards the bars, eventually ending the night in an Irish pub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;easter-sunday&quot;&gt;Easter Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning the common room was quiet. Most of our group had ended the evening rather late and were still out of commission. The few survivors - the dauntless Finn and his Spanish friend - suggested heading for Oia. We walked around for a spell and I used the opportunity to re-shoot all the rainy pictures I had taken when I was there with my friend Holger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_124956_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_125904_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow we figured it might be fun to take a small boat to  the island of Thirasia which was visible in the distance (previous picture, island on the upper right). So we began to look for a path down to the small port. The path we found consisted of a long series of looping, serpentine stairs. Sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This descent was a bit more hurried though, as we saw a small boat approaching the port from the direction of Thirasia. This being a public holiday, we figured that missing that particular boat could well mean not getting another chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_130851_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_131058_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from one local, we were the only passengers as the small boat set off and zipped across the waves to Thirasia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_131346_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arrival, Thirasia looked like it had been left there by somebody and then forgotten. The port was somewhat charming with its sleepy looks, but empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had lunch in a restaurant right on the beach. The place was somewhat minimalist (little furniture, fewer guests), and the owner had the dirtiest hands I have ever seen on a human being. He turned out to be incredibly friendly (I think he was - we couldn’t really find a language we shared) and the Easter lamb that was served was delicious. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_135832_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Exhibit A: Before roast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_135836_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Exhibit B: After roast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a generous meal and an even more generous helping of various desserts, our host offered to drive us to town. In many ways it seems to be true that the further you get off the mainstream destinations, the more helpful and friendly people become. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a scenic drive to the centre of the island our host bid us farewell in the middle of what he called “the capital”. Of the 200 people living on that island, we saw maybe six. So we spent around half an hour milling about town until we got bored and decided to hike back to the harbor to catch the boat back to Oia. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended up seeing more donkeys than we saw people. Even finding something to drink turned out to be impossible, since the few people we saw insisted their restaurants were closed, and the donkeys had no suggestions either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_145414_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Properly roasted by the sun we arrived back at the harbor. The lure of that azure-blue water was just impossible to resist, so Jarno and I decided to go for a quick swim. Just to give you an impression:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150412_162035_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The water here must have been around 2-2.5m deep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we made our way back to the pier, where we boarded the boat together with a group of French hikers, most of them quite middle-aged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we reached the port on Oia, this fact would become a bit embarrassing. The group of what should have been grey panthers began to attack the stairs with the dexterity of mountain goats, quickly overtaking us. In our defense: It was really hot, the stairs were steep and…yeah, there is no excuse, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed the phenomenal view from a cafe over drinks before heading back to Fira. There, we met up with the rest of our group and had a delightful dinner of even more lamb, followed by a few relaxed beers. Around midnight I said my goodbyes before taking a bus to the ferry terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My extended stay on Santorini came to an end as the ferry (once again one of the shiny ones!) docked at the pier just shy of one o’clock. When the storm first screwed up my travel plans, I had been a bit annoyed. Seeing the Easter celebrations and spending the weekend with an amazing group of people changed my attitude considerably. That’s the good thing about poor plans: They can only get better!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/18/easter2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/18/easter2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stranded, part II - The Easter Bunny is an arsonist!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;These orthodox Greeks have their own Easter which apparently takes place a week after, well, normal Easter. Since I was going to be stuck on the island until Sunday night, I tried to see as much of the celebrations as possible. In practice, that meant three parts, starting with lots of fire on Good Friday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my donkey-themed excursion, the afternoon found me reading - being useless - in the hostel. The charming Finnish gentleman I had met there pointed out that the locals were famous for their Good Friday celebration in the village of Pyrgos. From Google Image Search I knew that this festivity consisted of them decorating all the roofs with candles right after dark. A procession would then head down from the church on the peak of the hill down into town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pyrgos was around 6km from our hostel. Of course we would have loved to walk, but with sundown approaching quickly, we’d have to take a cab. Bad luck. The Norwegian we had befriended at the hostel agreed to join us, leaving one seat in the taxi free. In the interest of saving money, we also shanghai’ed two Canadian backpackers (“Oy, there’s going to be fire on a hill. You should come!”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approaching Pyrgos, we immediately saw the hilltop sticking out of the landscape. Since the sun was still up and there weren’t too many people around, we decided to walk up to the peak to take a look. As most organically grown Greek towns, the area consisted of houses built on top of and into each other with tiny, narrow walkways and stairs leading through this maze. The closer we got to the peak, the more urgently we were reminded of the storm which whistled around the walls and corners of the tiny houses. Eventually we ascended a stairway and found ourselves on the flat roof right next to the main church. Here, the gusts were so strong that we had trouble standing or walking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking that maybe, just maybe the wind wasn’t strong enough were we stood, we climbed up to the flat roof of the church on the top of the hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a few pictures of the sunset but they turned out blurry, since I simply could not stand still in that wind. My Finnish friend did a little better, so I’ll just post his pictures instead (thanks, Jarno!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/P4100112_scaled.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/P4100107_scaled.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_193452_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From up there, we also noticed the lights that had been placed on every wall, every roof and every pillar in town. Not candles, as we had imagined, but tin cans filled with wood shavings and candle wax. Keep this in mind, this will get important in a minute!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sundown we headed back down into town to grab a cup of coffee and observe the procession from the comfort of a bar or restaurant. After finishing a jug of rakomelo (a hot drink made from raki and honey) we got a bit impatient and began to head back up the hill. Still, there weren’t many lights in sight, but a crowd was gathering around the church. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One by one, the lights were lit by local youngster armed with propane torches. The wind, however, had not lessened a bit. If anything, it was stronger than before. Remember those wood shavings in the cans? Soaked in candlewax? The ones set on fire by the local teenagers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gusts ripped the burning wood from the cans and sent them flying through the darkness, turning the night into a storm of sparks and light. Dozens, if not hundreds of those cans were lit and with each light, more sparks were sent flying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The glowing wood was blown from the roofs down the narrow walkways and stairs. Since the wind sent them flying so fast, the sparks didn’t touch anything for long enough to pose an actual danger to anyone. They sure enough made for an amazing sight though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes, I braved the storm for long enough to climb back up on the roof of the main church. The experience up there was fantastic: The church bells rang out next to me, barely audible of the deafening roar of the wind. I looked down into the town with more and more spots of light appearing in the darkness below every minute. And over all of this, showers of sparks blew past me like massive waves, engulfing the church and the spot I was standing in. It was like standing in the middle of a firestorm. I remember grinning like a maniac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dutifully, I attempted to take a few pictures, but I don’t think they really reflect the sheer intensity of those moments up on that church roof:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_205155_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_205211_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I decided to climb down from there. The wind threatened to throw me on my face, off the roof or both. Instead I joined the others in front of the church and we headed back down through the town. Not before taking a few more pictures near the top though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/P4100110_scaled.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_210602_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/P4100094_scaled.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/P4100109_scaled.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards we navigated the labyrinth of passages and stairs. We also had the decidedly weird experience of walking right through a choir of priests and the congregration. As in: right between the priest and the singing congregation. “Excuse me - so sorry - my bad!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we reached the foot of the hill. As we looked back, we saw the very image that countless photographers had captured before us: Pyrgos, on the hill, as a sea of shimmering lights in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_213237_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took us a while to pull ourselves away from this sight. We weaseled our way through what had become dense traffic at the foot of the hill and called a cab. After finding our cab and being stuck in traffic for the better part of 20 minutes, we finally managed to drive back to Fira, the brightly lit hill left behind us.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/16/easter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/16/easter/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stranded, part I - Hiking down Donkey Turd Avenue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So picture this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your friend has left the island and you’re settled in in your hostel, awaiting your ferry’s departure the next day. But then you hear whispers in the common room about ferries getting canceled due to the storm, so you go out and check. A look down from the main road seems to support that rumor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_084952_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as the first heavy drops fall you reach the travel agency, and yes, ferry traffic has been cancelled. Outside, stray dogs and cats run for shelter. Probably for the best not to be on a boat right now. The ticket gets moved to the next ferry, which leaves on Sunday night. If the storm has calmed by then, which it might. Or might not. You know how islands are, says the friendly lady with a shrug. Since there is not much you can do you  flick up your collar and step outside and get drenched on the way to the bakery next door. Armed with coffee and a sandwich you half-walk, half-run back to the hostel. Since plenty of other people are just as stranded as you are, most of the guests are sitting in the common room. So you settle in for the day and get to know the others, which include a guy from Finland and a girl from Norway. So far so good. So you end up spending the day watching Taken 3 and Wild Card and being generally useless, while outside the palms are whipped back and forth by gusts of wind. Sunset happens without anyone noticing, because the sky was pretty dark to begin with. After a day holed up in the hostel you sneak off to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, lo and behold, the skies have cleared. The wind is still coming in powerful gusts, but the sky is mostly blue. So you decide to be less useless than you were yesterday and set out to explore the cliff-side of Fira. 220 meter above the sea, the cold wind sucks all the warmth right out of your clothes. This part of the town is pretty, but devoid of substance: Bars for tourists. Souvenir stores for tourists. Restaurants for tourists. Without tourists, the area is mostly empty. The view however, is stunning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/PANO_20150410_114642_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting there, staring down into the water, you notice a path leading all the way down to the sea and the old port. So you try to find a way to the beginning of that path, which isn’t easy because whoever planned this city had no plan at all. What you absolutely don’t do is climb over lower walls or gates when you get frustrated. No sir, not even when nobody’s looking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually you find the start of the path down. Right at the start you pass a man brushing the sidewalk in front of of his store. He’s build a neat pile of manure. Where did he get that from, you wonder? Suddenly you are distracted by a conversation between a local man and a tourist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tourist: &quot;So are you from around here?&quot;
Local: &quot;No, I&#39;m from Pireas.&quot;
Tourist: &quot;Pyras?&quot;
Local: &quot;No, Pireas.&quot;
Tourist: &quot;Ohhh...you mean PEE-RAY-US!&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nestled between the cliffs, the path is somewhat protected from the cold winds and you can feel the heat radiating from the cobbles under your feet. You smell the sun on the stones, the salt of the sea and, again, manure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_121258_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The avenue in question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You turn onto the start of a serpentine stretch of shallow stairs, and suddenly you understand where all that manure comes from: Donkeys. Not horses, because that would be stupid. No, donkeys. Apparently there is a class of people who are too lazy to walk but too outdoors-y to take the cable car. For those people the locals have two or three dozen donkeys shuttling tourists up and down the stairs. And covering those stairs in donkey poop in the process, evidently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150410_121335_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
One of the furry culprits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course you wouldn’t be caught dead on one of those four-legged mobility scooters, you’ll walk. So you pass the group of donkeys currently being loaded with a few tourists. You see one of the donkeys strutting off towards a wall at a casual pace. The British teenager riding it begins to scream in panic. In slow-motion she begins to tip out of the saddle, suddenly hanging on with one hand and one leg only. For an instant, the other donkeys seem to shake their collective heads in disgust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving a respectful distance between yourself and the donkeys you walk around that group and hike down the stairs. Further down, the wind picks up and throws more and more dust in your face. Most of that dust is dried donkey turds, actually, but there isn’t a whole lot you can do about it. The entire stairway is covered in it, after all. Onwards and downwards. After nine serpentine loops you see the old port down there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You pass a sign “Donkey Terminal”, followed by a row of two dozen donkeys, patiently waiting for the next group of tourists going up the stairs. After that, you’re in the old port. One or two restaurants are open for business, but most of the harbour seems to be empty ruins with occasional bits of maritime engineering strewn around and left for good: An anchor winch here, part of a rudder there, some damaged rowboards pulled up on the dock. Everything is sun-baked and covered in salt. Some glass-bottom boats are hidden from the storm behind a pier. Leaning against the sudden gusts, you carefully climb up the stairs to the pier wall and follow it until its very end, marked by a light tower and a bench. You sit down and pull up your collar against the stiff wind, then you look out over the bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day, the clear, blue water looked so inviting. Today, it shows a very different face: Waves surge violently and crash into the pier, filling the air with a salty mist. Out in the bay, the squall grabs the crests off the waves and rips the spray up in the air in hazy shapes. Close to the volcano in the middle of the bay seabirds struggle to stay in the air as angry gusts throw them this way and that. The sun shines on it all. And you just sit there, on your bench, and smile at this phenomenal display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting completely lost in the view for an hour you get up and slowly make your way back to the stairs. You scoff at the next group of tourists which is just getting on their respective donkeys and start taking the steps, two at a time. After two of the serpentine loops you begin to feel that welcome sense of going somewhere. After three, your breath comes quickly and you start feeling rather warm in your jacket. How many of those loops were there again? Oh, that’s right: Nine. Two loops later you notice that the weird dimensions of the steps mean you’re stressing one leg more than the other. You begin to alternate the pace. Maybe that will make it less exhausting. Five loops done and you’re breathing through your mouth. You can definitely feel your legs now. Can’t really slow down though, because then the donkeys might overtake you. How would that look? Loop six is a short one, thank god. You feel sweat soaking your shirt and your pulse hammering in your neck as you ascend the last few stairs and lean on a low wall to catch your breath. Way, way down below the donkey caravan is crawling up, leaving another unmistakable trail on the stairs you just conquered. Who the hell needs donkeys anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/13/hiking-down-donkey-turd-avenue/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/13/hiking-down-donkey-turd-avenue/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cyclades, part II</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;santorini&quot;&gt;Santorini&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached our hostel in Fira, the biggest city on the island, after dark and checked in. Afterwards we went for a short walk around the city centre. Despite it being pre-season, the main roads were already teeming with tourists. Most of them from China, it seemed, and mostly congregating in front of the numerous Chinese restaurants. As we eventually found out from a Albanian hostel clerk, groups of Chinese tourists travel to Santorini during the more affordable pre- and post-season and annoy the locals through extreme stinginess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick bite to eat we headed back to the hostel. Upon closer inspection, the rooms and especially the bathrooms turned out to be very…rustic. Wait, no: rusty. And somewhat grimy, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kamari-beach-and-ancient-thera&quot;&gt;Kamari Beach and Ancient Thera&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we got up and headed for the bus station to take a bus to Kamari beach in the southeast of the island. After a short ride through scenic, if sleepy parts of the island we arrived in Kamari and wandered towards the beach. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150407_101603_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The beach - in case you hadn’t guessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we tried to find breakfast however, we found almost nothing: It really felt like the town was only just about waking from hibernation. Wherever we looked, shop owners were slowly beginning to polish signs, paint walls and posts and prune trees and bushes. There were plenty of cafes and bars of course, but none of them were open for business yet. Instead, we grabbed some pies from a bakery and had a relaxed lunch on the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we sat there, looking at the waves, I couldn’t help but steal a glance or two at the people getting to work around us: They began working, but there was no rush whatsoever. They had coffee and tee, they chatted. There was a lot of yawning and lazy stretching going on. The whole atmosphere was not one of having to do stuff, but rather one of another day taking its course, the work unfolding on its own. I enjoyed watching this kind of effortlessness taking place, which stands in such a stark contrast, to say, the German attitude towards work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After wrapping up these profound sociological musings, we headed towards the mountains fencing in Kamari in the southwest. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150407_122013_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
What is it with you and cliffs, Holger?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had initially thought we’d just hike the way up to the ancient ruins on top. And we started doing just that, in the mid-day heat and without a complaint. But then Holger spied a car about to pass us. We decided that, while of course we were hardcore, we weren’t donkeys, so we’d take the ride offered to us, thank you very much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up at the top we goofed around on the cliffs for a spell,  before climbing up to the ruins of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_Thera&quot;&gt;Ancient Thera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150407_130153_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150407_134019_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150407_135538_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having taken the easy way out on the ascent, we figured that we could easily do the descent on our own. But then Holger spied a car…well, you can see where this is going. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down at the beach we went for a quick swim, observed by an audience of Chinese tourists. That clear, blue water looked so warm and inviting! While it wasn’t exactly warm, the hot sand and sunshine took the edge off the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in town we grabbed a quick dinner before picking up a few beers and heading back for the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150407_162900_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150407_165155_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Relaxing after a hard day’s work. And yes, those rocks were all warmed up by the sun. I felt like a lizard. A lizard with a beer and a smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards we took a bus back to Fira, had a pretty unspectacular dinner and a few more beers with said Albanian hostel clerk. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;oia-pronounced-ia&quot;&gt;Oia (pronounced [ˈi.a])&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we decided to take a bus to Oia, the scenic town in Santorini’s northeast. If you get a postcard from the island, this is the town that’s going to be on there. It perches on the cliff overlooking the horseshoe-shape of the island and the vulcano in its middle. The town looks strangely organic as the white houses are built into the rock at random levels and seem to flow into one another. Narrow stairwells and footpaths connect the buildings. Everything is either white, or a light shade of blue. In bright sunlight the town would be blinding. Just as well: It was rainy and overcast as we got there. We walked around the buildings, most of which were either hotels, restaurants, art galleries or jewellery stores. Where the locals live (or if there are any locals to begin with) I couldn’t say. Deserted as it was, the town seemed like a nice destination, but I’d hate to be caught there in the middle of tourist season. I’d imagine the crowds there to be suffocating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We managed to take a few interesting pictures before the rain forced us inside, into a cafe. Spoiler: I would come back here a few days later, in bright sunshine. I’ll post the pictures in a later article. You’ll be jelly, trust me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Fira I moved my stuff to another, less grimy hostel where I would stay for the next days. Holger and I lounged around the lobby for an hour or two, before he took a bus which would take him to the airport, from which he’d fly back to Athens.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/12/cyclades_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/12/cyclades_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cyclades, part I</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: This is where the really nice pictures of beaches and islands start. If you already hear the old hobo demon whispering in your ear you should tread lightly. I’m looking at you, Sofia!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leaving-athens&quot;&gt;Leaving Athens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday 05/04/2015, Holger and I left Athens to do some relaxed island-hopping in the Cyclades. Named after its round shape, this group of islands is what people imagine when they hear “Greece”. Clear turcoise water, We had decided to make the best use of Holger’s limited vacation time by visiting two islands: Milos (not very touristy) and Santorini (very, very touristy). The best of both worlds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So on said Sunday we agreed to meet up at Athen’s ferry terminal (yes, yes: it’s technically in Pireas, but you really can’t tell it’s a different city). Since I dislike being late or missing flights, boats or coaches, I arrived at the port way too early. So after finding the correct gate, I had plenty of time to sprawl out in the shade and watch a number of ferries enter the port, dock, offload, load and depart. Sure, airports have that atmosphere of travel and adventure, but they often feel so rushed. Ships, now that’s a different matter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, before I get too philosophical: Ships. We took one of those. For around 50 euros per person you are allowed to get on one of the shiny ones. Hence we got on a shiny, blue catamaran one which would carry us to the island of Milos in around 4 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ferry was quite neat and well-equipped but we spent most of the trip on deck, looking at the fantastically blue water or the islands we passed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150405_120653_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Your intrepid protagonists!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;milos&quot;&gt;Milos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached Milos in the late afternoon and found our hotel pretty much immediately. Truth of the matter is that the town of Adamantas is rather small. We saw several hotels, hostels and rooms for rent, but it was clear that tourist season was yet to start. That might also be the reason why we managed to get a room with two beds for 10 euro per person and night. As we reached the place indicated on the booking confirmation, this guy walked up to us, ushered us into this spacious room on the ground floor and I gave him 20 euros. Simple. The room seemed perfectly suitable, so we just dropped off our luggage and headed into town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150405_183952_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Even the clouds look amazing here! I’m currently using this shot as a wallpaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150405_184303_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Meeting the locals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a hearty meal in an almost completely empty restaurant and a few shots of raki, we wandered around the deserted town until after dark. Amongst other things, we came upon the island’s mining museum. Turns out that Milos actually earns more revenue from mining rare earths and obsidian than from tourism. That at least explains the relatively low-key tourism infrastructure in the town. I was left wondering who in their right minds would mine for obsidian though. I knew that they were historically used as blades and arrow points, because these stones tend to have sharp, glass-like edges. Amusingly enough, that seems to be one modern application, too: Obsidian is used for experimental &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Obsidian#Current_use&quot;&gt;scalpel blades&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150405_193154_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Sunset on Milos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we got up early (Hahaha…no. No, we didn’t) and decided to do a quick hike along the northern-most cliffs before leaving the island with a ferry in the afternoon. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150406_111507_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Walking along the coastline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150406_112219_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Up on the cliff. Near the edge. Thanks for the shock, Holger!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as we sat down on the beach behind the cliff, it started drizzling. Glancing up the ominuous-looking clouds above us we decided to leg it and scuttle back to the hotel before we got properly drenched. This turned out to be one of the better decisions we made, because just as we got close to the hostel, it started raining in earnest. We waited for the rain to die down, grabbed our bags, left the key in the door (apparently that’s how you do it on Milos) and headed for the ferry terminal. The ferry arrived on Greek time (50 minutes late).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at a map of the islands and thinking of the first leg of our journey, we figured that our trip to Santorini would also be about 4 hours long. Nope. Paying only 20 euros for a ticket, we got the less shiny ship this time. 7 hours on a ferry which was as deserted as the town of Adamantas had been (for similar reasons, I gather). At first both of us passed out on the sofas in the ferry’s bar area. The warmth and the gentle rocking of the waves just put us right to sleep. Fast forward a few hours, we were rather confused that we were still at sea. According to our GPS we were moving…slowly. Should have shelled out for the shiny ship!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the wind had picked up significantly and the ship was lurching up and down a lot. The crew apparently had some problems with the heating: It heated well enough, but you couldn’t turn it off. Something smelled vaguely burned. The heat, the smell and the rocking motions caused some queasiness amongst the passengers. At some point I chose to step outside, too. For the view, of course! Observe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150406_182907_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Some island. Could be Ios, I think. It’s late here as I’m writing this. Can you tell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150406_185900_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Suck my…Kielwasser?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150406_194259_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
I’m an artist!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much, much later than anticipated, we arrived at Santorini and slipped inside the horseshoe-shaped island towards the port. In the setting sun the view of the towns up top on the cliffs was spectacular: We had both read that most of Santorini’s urban area perched on those cliffs but we hadn’t anticipated just how HIGH those things were. As these sights unfolded before us in dusk, I have no nice pictures to show for it (my smartphone camera can’t handle lack of light too well). But trust me, there will be plenty of awe-inspiring pictures in a later post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We docked at Santorini’s new port and let ourselves be talked into paying an outrageous sum to be transported from the tourist information to our hostel. It was late, there were no visible buses or cabs, but I’m still too ashamed to mention how much we paid for the 8km car ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 004:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Tourist informations can be great. Some of those places have been incredibly helpful. In some cases they are little more than travel agencies shuffling people to hotels and getting commissions on bookings and transport fares. The guy in Santorini tried to justify the outrageous prices by saying we would also receive a map of the island. The same basic map you get for free at every hostel. Screw that. We should have just called a cab and waited for a bit. Don’t get talked into paying for a service you don’t need. Even when it comes with a fucking map.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Santorini really deserves its own post, since Holger and I stayed there for 2 days together, after which I stayed for another 4, which was not planned but very lucky anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/08/cyclades/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/08/cyclades/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Athens</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;at-least-its-warmwait-no-its-not&quot;&gt;At least it’s warm…wait, no, it’s not&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left Trikala soaking wet but excited to finally see Athens. At the coach station I bid farewell to my Canadian travel companion and stepped aboard the coach for a well-deserved nap. The road to Athens was sneaking up over hills and mountain passes. The view from up there, I have to assume, must be stunning on a clear day. Alas, all I saw was grey: The same fog that had shrouded Meteora was now hanging over the mountain roads. Just as well, at least I didn’t miss anything once I went - you guessed it - to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roughly halfway through the 5-hour drive I was woken by the bus driver turning up the radio. I’m sure the lyrics of Greek pop music are deep and meaningful and all that. And those music videos with very tan men and women looking all serious and longing while being surprisingly underdressed? Rich in symbolism and artistic depth! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invigorated by the catchy tunes I was able to observe the vistas along the North Euboean Gulf:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150325_162449.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also observed an oncoming column of battle tanks, transported on heavy trucks. It’s a pity I didn’t manage to snap a good picture, because tanks are decidedly awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, my enjoyment of Greek pop music was cut short: Since I had booked an AirBnB apartment in the northern part of Athens, the bus driver agreed to let me out close to that Area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good news: Short walk to the apartment. Bad news: Turns out I had screwed up my booking, as I learned from the following text exchange: “Alright, I’m in front of the apartment.” - “You arrive tomorrow, no?” - “Yes. Yes, I will see you tomorrow.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This left me without a roof over my head, standing in a part of the city which a realtor might describe as “quirky, multicultural and lively”. I managed to find a cafe with wifi (and with a lot of coming and going in the backrooms). From there I booked a hostel. Apparently you can get passable hostels for 8 euro per night. Anything cheaper than that, you’ll have to provide your own cockroaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the evening walking around Patisia. The evening was rainy, but marked by that special tranquility and peace that only lots of police in full-on riot gear bring about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I moved into the AirBnB apartment, all 18sqm of it. It was…economical. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson 003:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;My impression is that AirBnB in Greece just isn’t worth it. The main argument for AirBnB would be the privacy of having a flat to yourself. That’s not what you get under 20 euros per night though. Instead, you’ll have a sofa in somebody’s living room. So if you’re going to share the space with others anyway, hostels provide a much cheaper and more flexible option.
My favorites so far have been Little Big House (Thessaloniki) and Quinta (Athens), both of which charge around 15 euro per night. Small, friendly hostels. On a totally unrelated note, both of them offer free, unlimited coffee. Free. Unlimited. Coffee.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next 3-4 days exploring the area and taking in the many facets of this colourful district. As far as I’m concerned it should be burned, and the scorched earth then salted generously, but that’s just me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired to seek out other parts of the city, I also ventured into the city centre (a 15-minute walk) and had a look at Syntagma square and some of the more touristy areas. Mostly though I stayed indoors to escape the frequent rain. I got a lot of reading done, but there was no denying that I felt a bit cheated. Come on, Greece, get your act together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finally-lobstered&quot;&gt;Finally lobstered&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once my booking ran out, I checked out and hiked over to the aforementioned Hotel Quinta. ‘Twas a crisp, sunny morning and I found the place in a district much closer to the city centre. Located just 5 minutes walking distance from the foot of Lycavitus Hill, the entire neighbourhood is full of small, student-y cafes and bars. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the somewhat dreary AirBnB the hostel was an amazing surprise: I wandered around a lovingly graffiti-d block twice before I found the entrance in an alley. After ringing the doorbell I was led into a beautiful house with sky-high ceilings and decorations that were so ornate that they almost felt a bit ironic. Just to give you an impression:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150330_133713.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The lobby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150331_110800.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The upstairs hallway:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_161457.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
And the hostel dog (a million dog-years old and clinging to her furry life)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed here for a week. During the first day, I went for a long walk in the city centre with another German guy I met at the hostel. Wandering around the ruins of the Ancient Agora and the Roman Agora we enjoyed the view of the Acropolis hill and the remnamts of the Parthenon up top. This decidedly touristy area is full of enterprising young businessmen (or annoying, shit-peddling cutthroats, depending on just how badly you want that guaranteed-to-be-original Rolex for 20 quid).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150330_144715.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150330_145422.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Wooden dicks, because reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150330_163743.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Library near the university&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, I got up early and climbed up Lycavitus Hill. The hill is the highest point in the city and located smack in the middle of it. Having read about the view from up there, I grabbed a cup of coffee and started climbing the steep, steep roads up to the foot of the hill. From there, a circling path winds around the hill and through a light forest. I took a short break on one of the lower peaks to enjoy the view:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150331_101544.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After catching my breath, I continued upwards to the highest point of the hill, which is - of course - adorned by a cafe. I passed through the cafe, empty at that hour, and reached the peak which is marked by a chapel and a huge Greek flag. The view from up there was stunning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150331_103629.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I met up with my Canadian co-traveller and we went to see Acropolis Hill and the amazing ruins of the Parthenon. Standing there is every bit as impressive as the pictures would lead you to believe. That’s why I’ll refer you to Google Image Search once again, they have better quality shots. But here, have a picture of my sunburn instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150402_091313.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, maybe one or two pictures of the Acropolis, if you insist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150401_123618.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150401_130133.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150401_124335.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I was properly burned. What would a trip be without 2nd-degree burns? Fun fact: Sunscreen is a shameless racket in this country. 150ml of SPF 50 set me back 14 euros in Athens. On the islands, I would later see bottles of 200ml for 24 euros. So if any of you are interested in import/export, you should consider shipping sunscreen here. The margins would be worth it, I’m sure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next 2-3 days exploring the city centre and catching up on my reading. This included the Acropolis Museum and the National Archeological Museum. Both museums are definitely worth seeing. The Acropolis Museum holds most of the findings from Acropolis Hill (the parts not stolen by Brits at least…) so many of the objects on display are statues and fresks from the Parthenon or the Erechtheion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_133216.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_132903.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one section displayed a little-known fact about most antique ruins and statues: They were brightly painted! While we like to imagine ancient Greeks striding through cities of white marble, the truth of the matter is that most buildings - especially religious ones - were  decorated with paint, mostly made with mineral pigments which did not survive until today. The same goes for statues, which had painted clothes and skin. The Acropolis Museum had several examples of what these statues may have looked like and the effect is quite different from the serene-looking white images we tend to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_184623.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Mycenean acropolis is conspicuous for its mighty Cyclopean walls that led Homer to name it “well-walled” in the Illiad.” That doesn’t sound like a ringing endorsement, it sounds like old Homer’s version of “the walls were alright.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Archeological Museum was vast, but at the time of our visit, almost completely deserted. It held exhibitions of Cycladic art and jewellery (including Agamemnon’s Death Mask, though archeologists seem to think that it might not have been his bling after all), Egyptian…stuff (I confess I skipped that one, so I don’t know what exactly was on display there), the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antikythera_mechanism&quot;&gt;Antikythera mechanism&lt;/a&gt; and truckloads of statues from various epochs of Greek art. Some of my favourites included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_191645.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
The effect of Emperor Octavian’s empty eyes staring down on you is quite startling…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_192244.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_190358.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://rkwrd.github.io/pics/IMG_20150404_193653.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
Yes, I laughed :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-out&quot;&gt;Going out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason I like to stay in hostels (or to avoid them like the plaque, depending on the mood I’m in) is the social aspect: You meet people so goddamn easily. The words “Hi” and “Any plans for tonight?” are usually enough to suddenly be surrounded by people. Of course I had read about this before, but I was sceptical of all those tall tales. Nope, turns out, it’s all true. Not that surprising, really, when you think about it: Lots of young people, no local friends, all looking for company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when a friendly guy from Spain told me he was meeting a friend who lived in Athens and asked me to join him, my answer was a resounding “No, thank you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight I’m quite glad I changed my mind to “Eh, why not?” quite quickly, because I eventually found myself bar-hopping with a crowd of 10-12 travellers and locals, wandering all over the centre of Athens. The evening was a lot of fun, especially talking to the local guys and girls. Overall, three aspects of the experience stood out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, drinks in Athens are not cheap. 5-6 euros for a beer seems fairly normal. Maybe that’s the reason you don’t see many truly drunk people. It’s just too expensive to get drunk. (Some might argue that being half-drunk is a waste of money, of course…) The entire experience is very relaxed. No aggression, no tension, just people having a few drinks with friends. Beautiful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, Athenians dress up properly before going out. Properly-properly. We didn’t, though. I dare say we stood out a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, a group that large will have an amazing mix of cultures and languages (“I’m from Morocco, sorry, I don’t speak English…”) but some things are the same everywhere (“…but I’ve worked for Daimler in Stuttgart for 4 years, so we can speak German if you like!”). Back at the hostel we counted that between us 6 alone, we spoke 15 different languages. Globalisation may have its ugly sides, but meeting people from all over the world is definitely not one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leaving-athens&quot;&gt;Leaving Athens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I met up with my friend Holger, who had come to Greece for a few days. After some relaxed sightseeing, we prepared to take a ferry to the islands and see Milos and Santorini!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/05/athens/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/04/05/athens/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
