<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Escaping Sloth</title>
    <description>...very slowly</description>
    <link>http://escapingsloth.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://escapingsloth.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Yerevan I - Night Train</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My journey to Armenia started with a trip to the central train station in Tbilisi. For foreigners, that’s apparently the only place where they can buy train tickets. So I took a sweaty subway to the central station and walked up to the counter. The lady there looked as if she had smiled maybe once in her life and found the experience wanting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, she also understood some English so I approached the topic with all the minimalist eloquence developed during this trip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Ticket. Yerevan. Tomorrow? Bileti?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: What time? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Time? *pointing at the clock*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: *writes 10pm on a sheet of paper*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: How much money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: *holding up my wallet*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: *writes down 80 GEL and 100 GEL*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Class one and class two?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: *nods*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Yerevan. Tomorrow. Class one bileti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her: Passport?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had left my passport in the hostel. Showing her a scan of my passport on my phone also elicited several headshakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me: Reserve bileti?
Her: No.
Me: Money now. Reserve Bileti. Passport two hours?
Her: No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patiently massaging my temples I said a cheerful goodbye (and mumbled a few other things not fit for publication) and walked back to the subway to get my passport. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I blame myself. But I also kind of blame the Soviets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, after this trip I probably won’t be able to form coherent sentences anymore…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening of the following day, I arrived at the central station with plenty of time to spare. I was told to await the train on platform 3 and went to sit outside and enjoy the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150607_194005.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150607_194005_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Why is every place I go always deserted?&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About ten minutes before the planned departure there was no train in sight. Getting nervous, I started paying attention to the announcements on the platform. Most of it was unintelligible, but I thought I heard something like “Yerevan” and “four” in the same sentence. The only other person on platform 3 was a girl with a backpack. Of course she was a German on her way to Yerevan. Since neither of us was sure about the announcements we walked back to the service desk and were, once again, told to go to platform 3. We did, only to hear the same announcement as before. So we went back to the desk to really, really make sure. No, no, platform 3 was right. In the end, we ignored them and went to platform 4, where we just barely managed to jump on before the train pulled out of the station. We parted ways, since she had been frugal and gotten the 2nd-class ticket while I had splurged on the fancy 1st-class luxury sleeper cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150607_202135.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150607_202135_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;1st class: Two instead of four bunks per cabin&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we drove out of Tbilisi, a thunderstorm started and lightning flashed over the dark villages and Georgia’s beautiful rolling countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was standing outside my cabin and taking in the view, I was offered a bottle of wine by the guy from the cabin next door. He turned out to be a German photographer from my hometown, who was travelling around the Caucasus for both work and pleasure. Since we got along quite well, we decided to head to the dining car and have a few beers. A few beers turned into many beers, until suddenly we were ushered out of the dining car. It turned out that we had stopped at the border. Consequently, all toilets had been locked. So had the train doors. For some of us, this caused some distress. A few beers, some wine, some water even. 
It was only after having our passports checked at the Georgian side of the border that we were allowed to leave the train at the Armenian border station and use the facilities there. In return, the Armenians took close to 90 minutes to check our passports. Eventually we started moving again. I fell on my bunk and into restless, dreamless sleep as we rolled into Armenia.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/14/yerevan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/14/yerevan/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kazbegi III - Last Day in the Mountains</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One advantage of having my writing lag behind is that I get to consider episodes of my trip in hindsight.  A pattern I keep noticing is how some weeks are infinitely more eventful than others. This is the third article on Kazbegi (a trip that lasted all of the 3,5 days). Yet I know that other periods of several weeks will barely warrant more than one article. The obvious lesson is that a trip of several months is not just one exciting adventure after another. I suppose it could be, if I really wanted it to be, but who has the energy? Instead, I find that enjoying some downtime can be much more educational than frantic sightseeing. Stay in one place for a bit, have some tea, observe what is happening around you. Heck, maybe use the time to write down how you got there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aren’t these story-in-a-story things fun? So artistic, much wow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3---waterfalls&quot;&gt;Day 3 - Waterfalls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had arranged our departure from Kazbegi for the third day. Before we left this beautiful part of the world we wanted to see one last sight though: The waterfall at Gveleti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our driver from the day before drove us up towards the Russian border for about half an hour, before letting us hop out into the sun. After some back and forth (employing the usual amount of waving and pointing), we understood where he wanted us to go and we stalked off into the greenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_112753.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_112753_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The fellowship&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_113901.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_113901_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We quickly found the fast-flowing stream and then followed it up-hill. At that point, I definitely began to notice the ascents and descents of the previous days: My legs began to feel like rubber and it’s almost a miracle I didn’t faceplant straight into the stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_114044.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_114044_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we found the waterfall. The stream fell from a rocky ledge several meters up in the air. The water was then collected in a shallow basin before running down the gorge into the valley. Where we stood, a cool spray was flying everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_114307.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_114307_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The promised waterfall&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_114720.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_114720_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The view from up there wasn&#39;t so bad, either.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having relaxed at the waterfall for a bit, we climbed down the path and walked back to the waiting car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having seen this sight, we decided that it was time we drove back to Tbilisi. I recall sleeping through most of the drive back, but I did get out of the car once we stopped at this fancy monument:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150603_131417.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150603_131417_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Russian-Georgian Friendship Monument...hehe, yeah, I know!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-in-tbilisi&quot;&gt;Back in Tbilisi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Tbilisi, I checked back into the same excellent hostel I had stayed at before. I then spent another four days in Tbilsi, enjoying the usual dinners and drinks with the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150606_203754.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150606_203754_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Is that a dead fish, nailed to a painting? No, that would be absurd: It&#39;s obviously held in place by a screw!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One memory I will always cherish: We took a cab to a student-y bar near Rustaveli Square and had one hell of an evening. Chacha and beer flowed freely there. I vaguely recall randomly pointing at people, yelling “You there, you look interesting. Sit down!” To my great surprise, they tended to follow instructions rather well. That way I got to meet a singer, an event manager, the owner of the bar and a software developer from the Crimean who was very glad about finally having access to the Russian labor market. It was a long, long night…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150604_003219.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150604_003219_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A student bar in Tbilisi (early evening)&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I had to say my goodbyes to the others, who moved on to explore other parts of Georgia. Instead, I elected to book a ticket for the night train to Yerevan.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/12/kazbegi_iii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/12/kazbegi_iii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kazbegi II - Mountain Goats, Nuns and Snow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in Muscat, Oman, for two days now and have done next to nothing. Outside it’s around 43°C with 60-70% humidity. Apparently that sort of weather makes me drowsy, so I have done embarassingly little here and haven’t really seen anything either. For some random reason that makes me feel…guilty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s midnight and I’m sitting in the bath, listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RXiRpiOcWWI&quot;&gt;Beirut - Port of Call&lt;/a&gt; on repeat and sipping a Holsten Non-Alcoholic Malt Beverage Apple Flavour, which I mistook for non-alcoholic beer. Might as well get on with it then. Should we? The last article ended with a description of moonshine chacha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2---lazy-mornings-and-steep-ascents&quot;&gt;Day 2 - Lazy mornings and steep ascents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning my mouth tasted like death and felt as if a hamster had slept on my tongue. I got up with agonizing slowness, trying not to wake the pain hiding behind my temples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a thick slurry of Indian instant coffee and boiling water (ratio 1:1) and a light breakfast I almost managed to sit upright without swaying back and forth. Outside the sun was shining angrily and the sky was a hateful clear blue. Our accommodation was whisper-quiet, so I figured that the others were still in bed and, hopefully, just sleeping. Groaning, I decided to make use of the time and step outside to take care of my boots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While sitting there, groggily brushing away, our host turned up with an elderly man in tow. This man called himself the “Georgian Michael Schuhmacher” and was apparently the best driver we could get in this town. He explained the available tours in a passionate presentation. The audience - consisting only of myself, and just barely - nodded patiently. He would repeat the same pitch to all of the others during the next two days, and be disregarded every time. A pity, really, because his white Lada Niva had “adventure” written all over it. If you don’t know what a Niva is, just picture a Kalashnikov with wheels. About as comfortable a ride, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early afternoon the others began to trot around the house in the same, zombie-like state of tupor I had experienced earlier. Their livers were clearly used to more punishment though, since they began looking pretty spry just an hour later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quickly we decided on doing the hike up to Gergeti Trinity Church, which sat on top of a steep hill towering over Stepantsminda. So Rene, Manu and myself stepped out into the sunshine (Anthea had decided to relax a little longer) and started walking towards the hill. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_133733.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_133733_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Naazi Guest House, excellent branding&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, the hike would take around three hours, if we were to follow the looping serpentine sneaking around the hill. Or - amazing choice, really! No, really! - we could just walk to the foot of the hill and then walk…upwards for about 500 meters in elevation. The ascent turned out to be a painful mixture of panting, quiet cursing, louder cursing and burning quads. The view from up there was pretty special though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_141334.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_141334_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Stepantsminda from above&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_142328.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_142328_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Near the top&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About half-way up I must have stopped cursing because I couldn’t afford to waste the oxygen. Luckily, by the time I reached the top and found Manu smirking down at me, I had caught my breath again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_143102.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_143102_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A true mountain goat!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The church was built in the 14th century and looked wonderfully rustic. While it was not permitted to take pictures inside the church, the building itself and the fantastic scenery were enough to keep us occupied for a long time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_144817.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_144817_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Gergeti Trinity Church&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150601_144825.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150601_144825_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reasonably recovered from the ascent, we decided to take the same route down again. At that point, the weather began to change and the sky turned completely overcast. A bit worried, we hurried down the steep hillside (why am I always the only one falling on his ass in those moments?!). Just as we reached the town limit, another group of hikers (a family including little kids and the elderly) walked towards us and up the hill. That very moment it began to rain. By the time we reached our accommodation it rained in earnest. I wonder whatever happend to that little group. I’m sure they made it. Probably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed the evening with a decent dinner in town. I can’t recall if anybody ordered chacha that night. I reckon we might have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3---truso-valley-and-juta&quot;&gt;Day 3 - Truso Valley and Juta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we managed to get moving a bit earlier. With the help of our host we had actually found a much cheaper driver who turned up with a 8-seater Delica. That particular model seemed almost impossibly common in Stepantsminda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had planned on doing two tours on that day: Truso valley in the morning and a small mountain town called Juta in the afternoon. As it happened, our driver and his wife also ran a B&amp;amp;B. Since our original place did not have any vacancies for the coming night, we would stay at our driver’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sorting out our place for the night we hopped in the Delica and drove south along the river for about an hour before turning past some ancient-looking roadworks into a narrow valley. The Delica ambled over a precariously narrow pass right next to the muddy stream about 20m below us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the gorge opened up into a wide, green valley. We got out of the car and admired the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_114831.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_114831_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Entrance to Truso Valley&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_115128.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_115128_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amidst the greenery we found patches of unmolten snow, which obviously led to snowballs being thrown in unsuspecting faces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_120251.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_120251_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_120540.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_120540_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got back to the car, our driver drove further into the valley. Much of the road seemed flooded by meltwater, which was running into the stream. We stopped again at a tiny…village?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_123102.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_123102_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Ruins.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_124244.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_124244_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;And yet, there were people living there.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_123854.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_123854_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;One of my favourite shots of that trip.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_125848.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_125848_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking further into the valley we stumbled upon what turned out to be a nunnery. The nuns welcoming us were incredibly friendly and offered us a snack, which we took with another group of (German) tourists. The nunnery turned out to be very new, so the nuns proudly showed us around the building. This being Georgia they had a Magnum bottle of Whisky on their dinner table. Two of the younger nuns were explaining how and when the nunnery was built, while fiddling with their iPhones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_130322.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_130322_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The nunnery&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we stood there, taking in the views and washing down the hard cheese with coffee, this guy rode up on a horse. Dressed in army fatiques, carrying an army backpack and sporting some indecipherable rank insignia. Like  a scene from a movie, he rode up from the valley, passed us silently before stopping in front of one of the nuns. They exchanged a few words before he rode off towards the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_131147.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_131147_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Georgian Lucky Luke&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this somewhat bizarre encounter we walked back to the car. Our next destination was to be the town of Juta, higher up in the mountains. On the way there we drove through several smaller valleys which looked distinctly different from the somewhat winter-y Truso valley we had just left: The roads were lined with blooming trees and small gardens were almost bursting with various greenery growing through fences and hedges. Eventually, the road got steeper and steeper, as we entered another gorge. This time, the road led us at least 50m above the rapids down below. The road didn’t have much of a shoulder, so we all kept glancing back and forth between our driver and the sheer drop. There is something enjoyable about the detached amusement you feel in those moments. I mean, surely nothing is going to happen, right? Heh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our driver proved himself unflappable and delivered us to the small village. The first thing we noticed was the stream thundering down the middle of the town. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_154207.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_154207_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a round of coffees at the local cafe, we decided to climb up on top of one the hills surrounding the Juta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_162423.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_162423_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_161936.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_161936_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while of aimless wandering we found a passable trail. We decided to look at that snow you see in the distance up close:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150602_165059.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150602_165059_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end we got to within about 500 meters of it before deciding to turn around and head back. So we walked all the way back into town were we enjoyed a round of drinks before looking around for our driver. As these things go, everybody alwas sleeps on the way back. As did we, exhausted by a fair amount of hiking and that clear mountain air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening, the four of us gathered at our driver’s house were we enjoyed a fantastic home-cooked meal of traditional Georgian dishes. After a few drinks we all headed off to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/10/kazbegi_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/10/kazbegi_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kazbegi I - Mountains, Rivers and Rivers of Chacha</title>
        <description>&lt;div align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;color:gray&quot;&gt;
&quot;Oh don&#39;t give me none more of that Old Janx Spirit &lt;br /&gt;

No, don&#39;t you give me none more of that Old Janx Spirit &lt;br /&gt;

For my head will fly, my tongue will lie, my eyes will fry and I may die&lt;br /&gt;

Won&#39;t you pour me one more of that sinful Old Janx Spirit&quot; &lt;br /&gt;

-- Douglas Adams, The Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One warm evening in Tbilisi I had met two Kiwis, Anthea and Manu, on the roof terrace of our hostel. Over a few drinks we had started talking about travel plans. They intended to drive up to Kazbegi, a mountaineous region in the north, near the Russian border. Sure, why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/map_001_georgia_tbil_step.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/map_001_georgia_tbil_step.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days later, an old Mercedes arrived at the hostel. Our group consisted of Anthea and Manu (from NZ), Rene (AUS) and myself. Our driver had agreed to take us to the town of Stepantsminda for a total of 150 Lari (~50 EUR), a drive which would last about 3-4 hours. For the first third of the trip we rode through greater Tbilisi. Remember what I said about rats? Then again, the outskirts of most cities aren’t exactly scenic.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After passing the Zhinvali Reservoir, things started getting a lot more hilly. And sheep-y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_125747.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_125747_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A flock of some thousand sheep, according to the shepard. Show-off!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we reached an actual mountain road and began to climb up the serpentine. Even though most stretches of the road were not all that steep, the old Mercedes sounded like parts might come flying out the bonnet at any moment. Our driver just cruised down after every peak to compensate, so we were pleasantly slow both up- and downhill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_143457.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_143457_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, our driver was okay with us stopping for snacks and photographs. Since taking pictures from a moving car didn’t work so well (even at our slow speeds), we made use of that opportunity and admired the stunning scenery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_152154.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_152154_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Our Kiwi friends got weirdly excited at this sight.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_152540.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_152540_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;These guys nonchalantly stepped between us and the flock. Nice doggy! Peaceful doggy!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we followed a fast-flowing, muddy river through a valley until we reached the town of Stepantsminda. There, Anthea and Manu found their pre-booked apartment right next to the main square. Rene and I decided to try to get beds there, too, which worked out just fine. Hooray for not being prepared!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_155425.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_155425_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The house opposite of our accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our place was very neat and cozy. Our host had shown us the house and answered some of our questions. Then he reached into a kitchen shelf and pulled out a bottle of chacha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, yes: Chacha. Chacha is the Georgian poison of choice. It’s a clear spirit and a brandy in the widest sense, because it’s supposedly made from grapes. Or from whatever is handy and roughly grape-shaped. That could be anything, really: After a few glasses the finer points of distilling high-octane drinks will start getting lost somewhere between your eyeballs and your brain. Whether that’s due to your corneas dissolving in methanol (bad) or your neocortex drowning in ethanol (just as bad, but more fun) depends on the source: In Georgia, non-commercial moonshine is legal. It seems to range anywhere from 45% to 60% and was almost certainly distilled by somebody still in possession of their corneas. Then there are also award-winning commercial chachas made by trained professionals. In the small villages you might as well try and order a unicorn though, because your odds of getting it are roughly similar. Instead, people tend to fill their moonshine into the nice, official bottles. It doesn’t really make much of a difference either: Both the nice stuff and the moonshine give you the same note of “WhatAAARGGH!” and make your eyes water in appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, two shots of that and then off to explore the town!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_165955.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_165955_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Manu driving.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to walk to the foot of a steep mountain where we were supposed to find a church. We missed that by a wide margin but found some beautiful scenery instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_170625.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_170625_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Powerlines everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_173156.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_173156_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Heroic mountaineers!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found ourselves standing at the foot of said mountain ridge (pictured above, right behind us). Since it was still early and we were full of energy, we stopped and discussed what to do next. As we looked up the fairly steep slope, we started wondering if we could do a quick walk to maybe the half-way mark. From the distance, it definitely looked like an easy way up. I distinctly remember saying that aloud, and the others agreeing with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, where I come from, we don’t have mountains. Or hills. It’s so flat an area that standing on tip-toes will allow you to see for miles. But sure, that thing - in my expert opinion! - looked perfectly okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_180057.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_180057_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_181402.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_181402_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_181100.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_181100_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was slightly above this point that Manu and I encountered an almost vertical section consisting of loose and shifting rocks. While it would have been possible to continue, there wasn’t much to break our falls should we slip. Given our utter lack of equipment we figured this was good enough for the first day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “climb” back down was a haphazard affair of careful steps and a half-intentional slide on my hands and feet. Great fun, and nobody got hurt - surprisingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_183156.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_183156_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Slowly, slowly...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_184705.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_184705_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Looking down on clouds&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there we headed back into town, hoping to rustle up something edible. Our host had warned us that the quality of the local restaurants was mixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_185353.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_185353_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Bit of lens flare. I should really keep my phone clean.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This turned out to be true for the place we found: The waiter clearly hated his job, and us, for making him do it. The food wasn’t really to our liking. Instead we turned to the drinks menu. What was the name of that brandy again? Right: Chacha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s what we kept ordering with masochistic glee. Initially, we were brought shot glasses. Then small sherry glasses. In the end, our ‘shots’ kept arriving in the form of half-full water glasses. I recall a waitress asking “Are you sure?” as we ordered one of the last rounds…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around that time, that we figured that our behaviour  might end up harming the reputation of our respective countries. That seemed horribly inconsiderate, so we agreed that we would all pretend to be Australians. Why hurt the image of three when you could limit the harm to one, which didn’t have that much to lose to begin with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, three of us decided to call it a night and headed to bed. One however decided to have a few more drinks at some local’s grandparent’s place. That night, another colourful tale was added to the lore of Aussie travelers. I will spare you the details, but should you ever find yourself in Stepantsminda, be sure to ask the locals about their impression of Aussies!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/08/kazbegi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/08/kazbegi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tbilisi II - Visa-troubles and David Gareja</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The articles here are still almost a month behind my actual itinerary. Normally I would deal with the mounting feeling of guilt by taking a nap and then using the boost of energy to clean the kitchen or look up cat videos on Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the nap is out of the question: It’s impossible to find a sleeping position in which my lobstered skin doesn’t cause me to suffer dreams of hellfire, father-of-the-year King Stannis or the Vietnam war. Turns out, the colour of your skin can cause lots of problems. Who knew?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the absence of decent excuses I’m now sitting in the living room, not-sipping my not-coffee (because Ramadan). As its rich, smokey flavour not-fills my mouth, I’m thinking that I might as well get on with the writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Tbilisi I ended up spending little time on sightseeing, but rather more on socializing. My theory is that any person troubled by shyness or lack of friends should grab a bag, book a ticket and find themselves some nice hostels to stay in. Hostels are full of people with the strangest background and experiences! Most of them tend to actively look for other people to hang out with. That relative abundance of social interaction also puts any fears of blunders or awkwardness in perspective: So what, you’ll never see those people again - unless you want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, that’s what the choice between hotels and hostels comes down to: Would you rather talk to waiters and room service or other travelers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150531_001046.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150531_001046_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;airport-no&quot;&gt;Airport? No.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between the meals and nights out, I managed to clarify the situation regarding my visa for Iran. Clarify that I wasn’t going to get one, that is. My initial plan had been to fly into Teheran, spend two weeks roaming around Iran and then flying out to Bahrain. This actually sounded like a really good plan because of Iran’s Visa-on-arrival service, which allows citizens of some countries to just pick up a visa at the airport. Being lazy but cautious I decided to ask about that at the embass before booking my flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first attempt, I walked to the embassy (for about 90 minutes). Unfortunately, the place had closed down 10 minutes before I reached it. The opening hours listed on the website were out of date, apparently. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150526_123904.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150526_123904_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Vake Park, which I found along the way&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second attempt, I reached the embassy early and was admitted in, together with a couple from Poland. It was their second visit to the embassy, and the looks on their faces didn’t exactly inspire confidence. Sure enough, we were met by a almost-certainly-competent embassy official. I could elaborate on the specifics, but I fear that it might jeopardize my chances of getting a visa in the future. Suffice to say that he eloquently answered our initial question in one sentence: “… … … …airport? … … … no.” He really stuck to his guns and used the same sentence to answer all of our follow-up questions, too. 
Instead, he helpfully directed us towards a visa service agency, which would apply for a regular visa on our behalf, for around 200 USD. That would take around 2 weeks. For me, this meant I simply was not going to go to Iran: If I had to wait for two weeks to get a visa, I would only have around 5 days to spend in Iran before meeting my friend in Bahrain. 200 USD (visa) + ~200 USD (flight) / 5 days = 80 USD/day just to get into the country. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I had met other travelers (tourists!) who had gotten into Iran on those airport visas very recently, no problem. Plus, all Iranian government websites stated the Visa-on-Arrival was still an option. So technically, I could have just booked my ticket and hoped for the best. However, this meant running the risk of being rejected at the airport and then being forced to book a pricy flight out on the spot. I decided to trust the charming man from the embassy and leave my Iran visit for another journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;david-gareja&quot;&gt;David Gareja&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that sorted, I decided to explore the Tbilisi area some more. Luckily, I had met some interesting people at the hostel before (Hi, Rene!) and we decided to do a day-trip to the David Gareja monastery right on the Georgian-Azerbaijani border. The orthodox monastery was founded in the 6th century and consists of dozens of chapels, caves and buildings. Today, the area is the object of a border dispute between Georgia and Azerbaijan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We picked a tour operator near Liberty Square and were directed to a waiting car. It must have been a slow day, because it was only the two of us, an Italian guy and an Austrian lady, and the driver. He would drive us to the monastery, we would complete a short hike there and then be driven back. Luckily, our driver was very accommodating of our tourist-y desire to take pictures of…everything and stopped frequently along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_122615.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_122615_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Endless landscapes&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_125258.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_125258_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Endless sheep&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monastery itself turned out to be a fairly low-key affair: It is still operating (monks are still monking) and thus much of it is off-limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_132417.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_132417_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Caves dug into the side of Mount Gareja&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_132625.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_132625_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The chapel&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_133331.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_133331_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Inside the chapel&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the monastery behind, we started our hike up the cliff towards the Azerbaijani border. The temperature must have hovered around 35°C and the path was baked solid by the sun. The path was also quite steep, so after a short while we were all sweat-soaked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_135138.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_135138_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Rene and Marco figuring out the route from an A4 map provided by our driver&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Is that humming in your head the sign of an oncoming headache? You haven’t drunk enough water, clearly. And no aspirin on you. Yep, definitely a headache. One of those pulsing ones. Ka-CHOCK….Ka-CHOCK. Awesome.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few hundred meters of steep ascent we reached the top of the ridge. There, sitting on a huge rock, we found two Azerbaijani soldiers on watch, who called us in on their radio. Interestingly enough, they did not check our passports or require any documents. And thus we sat foot into Azerbaijan. The view from up there was stunning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_141130.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_141130_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The north of Azerbaijan actually looks...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_141250.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_141250_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;...a lot like the south of Georgia&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then followed a footpath along the ridge and found several small caves with wallpaintings and inscriptions. All of these were outlying parts of the monastery and still used as places of worship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_142018.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_142018_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Caves along the south slope of Mount Gareja&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_142106.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_142106_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Another cave&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_142528.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_142528_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;And another cave&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we made our way up to the peak of the ridge, where we checked back in with two Georgian soldiers sitting in the shade of a chapel there. We ended up spending half an hour just admiring the landscape and trying to snap a few good shots of the enormous birds of prey that circled around us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_145448.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_145448_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_145910.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_145910_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A bird!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, we climbed down the other side of the ridge, back towards the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_151705.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_151705_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Down the north slope of Mount Gareja&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back, we had a lunch-stop in the town of Udabno. As these things go, the only restaurant there was operated by our driver’s parents. Their entire community had been relocated to this area after their hometown in Svaneti had been devastated by a rockslide. The Soviets had begun building a completely new town for them, when the USSR collapsed and the money ran out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150529_160822.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150529_160822_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Udabno&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick lunch there, we all slept through the entire drive back to Tbilisi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1300 words! On a sunday, no less! Next time: Another episode of “Wanna come?” - “Sure, why not?” with mountains, sheep and chacha - nectar of the gods and terror of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/06/tbilisi_ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/06/tbilisi_ii/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tbilisi I - Arrival and doing not much</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, yes: the writing. The writing which I promised to do regularly. &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; writing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the above three sentences in an agonizing fifteen minutes, I got up and fetched myself a cup of coffee. Then I groaned to myself a little and pulled my own hair for a bit. But now I’m good. Excited to continue the tale!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left off - I remember distantly - when I took a coach from Batumi to Tbilisi. Metro, the coach company I had used so frequently in Turkey, offered a comfortable 5-hour trip to Tbilisi. Being the lazy sort I had a relaxed breakfast in Batumi first, and then got on the coach in the early afternoon. We drove up north along the coast for about two hours before turning east and driving into the country, towards the capital. I’ll spare you the details, but here is the summary: Georgia is beautiful. Really, really beautiful. That’s about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the outskirts of Tbilisi in the late afternoon. Remember what I wrote about Batumi looking pleasantly post-apocalyptic? The outer districts of Tbilisi looked worse. Within half an hour we went from “Oh, pretty hills!” to “Oh, a rat!” to “Oh, a guy…barbecueing a rat”. This surprised me, since I had heard very positive things about Tbilisi in general. Luckily, my concerns were unfounded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got off the coach near the city centre and found myself standing in the middle of a neat-looking high street (Rustaveli Avenue), which also leads to the parliament and the Georgian National Museum.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_195121.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_195121_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;On Rustaveli Avenue&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived, the entire road was blocked for traffic, as they were preparing for a parade: People were in the process of erecting stages and assembling stands. Bands were practicing and every available space was covered in billboards and posters. Despite the commotion I managed to find a cafe with wifi and find myself a suitable hostel. Then I shouldered my way back through the crowd and towards the southern part of town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_195532.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_195532_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Liberty Square, at the southern end of Rustaveli Avenue&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There, right at the foot of a massive hill and under the remains of Narikala Fortress I found the excellent Envoy Hostel. On top of all other amenities, it had a fantastic roof terrace!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_201831.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_201831_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View from the hostel roof terrace&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dark, I ventured down the hill and found myself something to eat. Next, I followed a bridge into a park on the other side of the river, and spent some time reading there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_203552.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_203552_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The park. That subtle, understated building in the background? The presidential palace.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, I called it an early night and headed back across the river and to bed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150525_214627.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150525_214627_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Shiny bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I heard from the hostel staff that I had actually managed to arrive just in time for Georgian independence day (May 26th). Curious, I headed out towards liberty square and had a look at the little military parade organized there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150526_112531.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150526_112531_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150526_112644.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150526_112644_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the whole affair wasn’t as action-packed as I had hoped, I decided to ignore the festivities and get coffee instead. That’s pretty much what I did on my second day in Tbilisi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150527_164627.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150527_164627_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Came up to me, looked at me, sat down on me.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite honestly, I didn’t feel like hardcore sight-seeing when I was in Tbilisi. So I just enjoyed wandering around town and having a look at various districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150528_105524.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150528_105524_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View of Narikala Fortress from the foot of the hill&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my hostel was very close to the fortress, I took a detour up there (using the cable car of course…what am I, a farmer?). While the fortress consisted of nothing more than its walls, I enjoyed climbing up to the parapet and taking in the view of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150528_112215.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150528_112215_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View of the castle from the northern side.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150528_113221.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150528_113221_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;View down into town. That brownish thing is a river, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would end up staying in the Tbilisi area for around 5-6 days before heading north with a few new-found friends. All in all, I found the city pretty, but not overly exotic. For my personal productivity that was excellent news, but not necessarily the material for riveting stories. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phew, that’s a whole lot of writing right there! A good day’s work! I’ll take a break now. Next time, I’ll explain why I didn’t end up going to Iran and tell you how we crossed into Azerbaijan without passports!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/05/tbilisi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/05/tbilisi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Batumi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The third country of my trip was Georgia. I crossed the border at Sarpi and took a minibus from there to Batumi. The whole ride lasted about half an hour and cost me a single Lari (about 0.40 Euro). As we drove up the coast, I enjoyed the view of the empty beaches and the hilly countryside. Much of the scenery reminded me of a slightly more summer-y Poland. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun broke through the morning haze eventually and the streets become more and more lively as we reached Batumi. The city is a famous holiday destination and especially popular with tourists from Poland and the Ukraine. As we drove into the city centre, I noticed the fairly typical shape tourism has given Batumi: The outskirts looked pleasantly post-apocalyptic, the way former soviet-territories do. Rusty cars, about-to-collapse buildings and entire neighbourhoods which looked like they were held together only by duct tape and stubborn optimism. Or at least a shared confidence that things were not likely to get &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; worse in the immediate future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as we neared the city’s port, the influence of tourist money became very visible: Newer buildings, well-maintained facades and roads, lots of hotels and restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150523_085951.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150523_085951_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The port&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got off the bus there and grabbed an early coffee at a cafe on the promenade. There, I also tried my first Adjarian Khachapuri. This entire country seems to survive on various kinds of Khachapuri (cheesy dough baked goods). Case in point: Beggars will approach you repeating “Khachapuri, Khachapuri”. The Adjarian is baked dough in an open boat shape and has a raw egg on top of the feta-like cheese. Yes, most dishes here are very hearty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_103128.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_103128_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Main square&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I found myself a decent hostel (for 6 EUR/night) and took a nap which lasted for most of the day. My afternoon exploration was cut short by the onset of torrential rain, so I stayed in. In the evening, another hostel-guest from Poland and I went out to grab dinner, before calling it an early night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_104842.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_104842_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The obligatory seaside shot&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning the rain had stopped and I took a long walk around town and along the promenade. Since tourist season here does not start before July, most places were very empty and I struggled to find a place for breakfast. While I got increasingly frustrated at people telling me they didn’t serve coffee, I really appreciated the fact that most people seemed to speak English willingly. It’s nice to be denied in english!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the promenade you get plenty of hotels and casinos, many of them either new or still in the process of construction. And then you get this thing, which apparently belongs to the university: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_142143.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_142143_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Yeah, that building in the distance has a built-in ferris wheel. Does yours not have that?&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, circling back to the harbor, I came across this fine example of sturdy Cold War engineering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_142451.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_142451_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;A semi-submersible...semi-submersed.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Batumi is marked by these strong contrasts: In front of the hotels and casinos you find plenty of Bentleys and Ferraris, other parts of town are just casually rotting to pieces. Besides this absurdity, Batumi did not really hold much of interest. To me, it seemed like a typical tourist town - at that point, minus the tourists - who would come there to swim, drink, eat and gamble. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_193649.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_193649_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The old part of town&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_194249.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_194249_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Another square and a fountain with lots of boobs&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, I decided that I was going to leave Batumi the next day. I ended up going out for dinner with my Polish aquaintance and enjoying a relaxing beer on the promenade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150524_202456.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150524_202456_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;I really need to stop posting these...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I got up nice and early and walked to the coach station on the other side of town. There, I got on a coach to Tlbl…Tblbl…the capital.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/02/batumi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/06/02/batumi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>35 litres of stuff</title>
        <description>&lt;div align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;color:gray&quot;&gt;
  &quot;Oh, is that it?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
  -- She &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several times other travelers asked me where the rest of my stuff is. Many are surprised to find out that I only carry one medium-sized backpack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantages of traveling light have been analyzed in excrutiating detail on a great number of travel sites and forums. Let me save you the time and present the key principle of traveling light: &lt;strong&gt;Things are heavy and you don’t need most of them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most backpackers look like they are moving house for a year. I blame two faulty lines of thought:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) If you travel for longer, you need more everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) Foreign countries do not have shops, ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these hobo-hoarders go out and get themselves a nice 90-litre hiking pack. What goes well with that? Oh yeah, a second, smaller pack they can carry on their chest! That’s useful because it allows them to strap their sleeping bags on there, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, it must be nice to have everything you could possibly need with you. On the other hand, I don’t want to go &lt;em&gt;beep!-beep!-beep!&lt;/em&gt; while awkwardly reversing off a train because all that gear is too bulky for me to turn around. I have carried heavy equipment for extended periods, and I’m not a fan. The prospect of doing that for an entire year is incredibly off-putting to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided against it. After all, I was going to stay in civilization (or whatever passes for it) for most of the time. I knew I would be able to buy additional things as needed. This also meant that I would leave typical hiking-gear, like a hiking boots, tent and sleeping bag. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I understand that travelers of the female persuasion tend to carry more stuff. The social consensus seems to be that the whole smelly-but-somehow-handsome-in-a-rugged-way look is male-only. Lucky me!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would just bring the basics then. When I inspected my gear before leaving Samsun, I took this picture:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150522_112422.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150522_112422_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One pair of shorts, one pair of jeans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel towel and travel blanket&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swimming trunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First-aid kit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laptop and charger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Powerbank (thank you, Alex and Clément!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notebook (thank you, Sisi, Sofia and Martin!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sunglasses (the label says “Ray Bon”)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flashlight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Windbreaker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sweatshirt (wool)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sunscreen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 T-shirts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Belt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 pairs of woolen socks (two pairs hand-knitted by my mom!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Washbag&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 Boxers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assorted cables and adapters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vacuum compression bags (Eagle Creek)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Backpack (Assault pack II)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, of course, the clothes I was wearing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vacuum bags are incredibly useful: They are heavy-duty ziplock-bags with one-way valves on the lower end. You stick your clothes in there and then roll the bag to press out all the air. This way, my clothes shrink to less than half their volume. In addition, the bags keep them dry and protect them from that typical bag-smell. I’m absolutely amazed by these bags and I could kick myself for not getting them earlier. This compactness obviously doesn’t do anything about the weight, so my backpack is a bit heavier then it looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150522_113213.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150522_113213_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;All my clothes put into those two vacuum bags&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is all that stuff packed up nicy and tidy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150522_115332.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150522_115332_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s it: A moving household stuffed into a 35-litre backpack!
If I’m completely honest, even this bag could stand to lose a few items. I might still eliminate one or two t-shirts and the pair of jeans and replace the swimming trunks with a less bulky pair. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/29/traveling-light/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/29/traveling-light/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Samsun</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Outside, in the alley the rain is pouring down hard. Big, heavy drops drum on the pavement and glisten in the yellow light of the street lamps. For most of the afternoon the city smelled of hot dust and ozone.  At sunset the thunderstorm finally broke and I got back to the pension drenched. Now I’m sitting in the small lobby, sunk deep into the worn sofa-cushions. I sit by myself, surrounded by pillows, throws, thick carpets and a huge bookshelf. On top of the shelf, barely visible in the dim glow of the glass lamps, the owner has arranged decorative plates and glasses, and a few family photographs, too. Next to it, the wooden counter is dwarfed by the photographs and flags on the wall behind it. In the half-dark I can’t make out where the old clock is, but its solemn ticking fills the room. When I concentrate on the moments between its ticks, the place feels as if time itself has stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clock’s rythm contrasts with the continous pitter-patter outside, intermingled with the occasional distant rumbling of thunder. I hadn’t really noticed any of that until a few minutes ago, when I put down John Le Carré’s ‘Tinker, Taylor, Soldier, Spy’. Mentally coming back from Cold War espionage to the present, I also realized that the pension’s owner must have gotten up from his paperwork at the counter to attend to one of the rooms upstairs. There isn’t much to do though, since I am the only guest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No doubt that’s part of the reason why I am still in Samsun: The pension is neat and very quiet. The owner is a stately-looking man in his early 50s who uses the phrase “no problem!” almost exclusively and brings me coffee without me asking. That, too, is part of why I’m still in Samsun, a city in which there is nothing to do. A city which I intensely disliked when I arrived here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t slept much on the night bus from Göreme (I’m sure I mentioned that). When I arrived at Samsun coach station at 04:00h, I barely knew where I was. My mouth felt like a hamster had slept on my tongue. The station was devoid of people but I managed to find the metro lounge, which had a TV tuned to a sports channel. So I saw some of the run-up fights to Mayweather vs. Pacquiao.  I also noticed that somebody on the bus must have nicked the cookies I had kept in a plastic bag under my seat. Whoever you are, cookie-thief, I hope those chocolate chips bring you joy, and not diabetes. Just before the big fight started, a shuttle appeared out of the thick fog outside and took us the city centre. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I saw of the city looked dire as hell in the fog and under a light drizzle. I got off at the city centre and wandered around in search of caffeine, wifi and processed carbohydrates for almost an hour. It would only occur to me a few days later that I had arrived on a sunday morning, at 06:00h. This would have explained nicely why nothing was open and there were no people around at all. As it was, I felt very much betrayed by the universe. Finally I managed to find a bakery with wifi (yay!), puff pastries (yay!) and tea (…). From there, I looked up this one pension and then crossed the road to a Metro coach ticket office, on the off-chance that there was a way out of this hellhole on the same day. Since there wasn’t (probably - my Turkish isn’t so good), I marched off in the other direction and found the pension. The room I was offered was a double, for a price which made haggling feel pointless. I lugged my bag up to the fourth floor and collapsed on the bed. Outside, the sun rose behind hazy clouds, stores were opened and cars started. Windows were flung open, tea was brewed. Inside, I drifted off and slept the sleep of the all-but-dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150504_191404.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150504_191404_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;The promenade&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150505_142038.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150505_142038_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Fried egg on top of my beef-bacon pizza/pide? Don&#39;t mind if I do!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have been in Samsun for two weeks now, I will spare you all the details. The main points are these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After staying in so many places for relatively short periods (2-5 days), I wanted to take a break and stay somewhere for a bit longer. While hopping from town to town is great fun, it’s also a flood of new impressions which need to be processed at some point. I simply did not want to be one of those travelers who live by their itineraries. The kind that gets off a bus somewhere with glazed-over eyes and trembling hands. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, my other stays had been at hostels. That had turned out great in terms of the people I met and I’m actually amazed how easily groups formed between people from very different backgrounds. Yet, after I while I felt like I needed a break from people. Some time to shut up and think (or precisely not think). This was made all the more pressing, as I kept remembering all the things I had set out to do on this trip: Study, write, read, program. So far, I had done preciously little of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past two weeks, I started doing some of what I had planned, and Samsun turned out to be just the right place for it: Population of 1 million, but not too crowded. Affordable, yet modern. No major attractions meant: no major distractions. In Samsun I didn’t feel the least bit guilty about spending entire afternoons and evenings in cafes, just reading or writing. I knew I wasn’t missing out on anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150504_191736.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150504_191736_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Samsun&#39;s port&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I did things. I read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Joe Haldeman, The Forever War (I loved this one.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Terry Pratchett, The Nightwatch (Deeply philosophical satire, one of his best!)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;John Le Carré, Tinker, Tailor, Soldier, Spy (enjoyable)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kurt Vonnegut, Slaughterhouse 5 (not sure)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Orson Scott Card, Ender’s Game (not convinced)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also finally managed to commit Kipling’s “The Palace” to memory, though I struggled for ages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually I would read in the mornings and at night, and program in the afternoons. That way, I got some Python exercises out of the way and completed a script which manages the photographs included in these articles (more on that later). I also found out how shockingly simple it is to write a script to generate and guess Finnish Social Security Numbers. I started working on some simple pattern recognition for data analysis in Python. I hope to continue that in the coming weeks. Finally, I set up a virtualized Arch Linux system, which is a great thing to do if you ever need a system which feels like it’s been made of broken household appliances. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150506_130454.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150506_130454_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Not quite sure what this is...&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between the reading and the programming, I spent an unreasonable amount of money on coffee and don’t regret a thing. For breaks, I took plenty of long walks along the promenade and exercised fairly regularly. All in all, the past two weeks have felt refreshingly productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150509_170844.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150509_170844_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As enjoyable as my stay here has been, I’m beginning to feel restless. Luckily, a coach ticket to Batumi, Georgia (No, not that one. The other one.) is only ~20 EUR. I’ll leave at 23:00h and reach at 07:00h. Hooray for overnight coaches!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/19/samsun/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/19/samsun/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cappadocia, part III - Hiking and climbing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brace for a storm of landscape shots!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-valley&quot;&gt;The valley&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, Marc and I met Michal (from Poland) over breakfast. The three of us decided to go for a casual morning hike in one of the valleys (Kiliclar vadisi). The weather was gorgeous and the three of us picked a route which followed almost none of the suggested paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_103945.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_103945_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_104428.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_104428_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started out by walking past (and through) some of the deserted rock houses. Having inspected them in detail, we then walked up to one of the large ridges lining the valley:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_104710.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_104710_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_104714.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_104714_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_110803.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_110803_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the ridge, we climbed down into one of the smaller valleys, and for once followed a path for a while. Next, we tried to scale one of the opposite ridges, which took us over an hour. The white rock you see in the pictures is tufa, which is soft and porous at the best of times. Often enough, the rock itself was covered by layers of sand and dust, which looked just like the rockface itself. As we found out, it was utterly unsuited for even light climbing. So many times when we though we had finally found a decent route out of the valley, we had to track back after feeling our hands slip in the layers of white dust. On the plus-side, we ran into this magnificent little dinosaur!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_114608.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_114608_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Foreground: Turtle, Background: Marc and Michal&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several failed attempts, we finally found a way up on the rock, where we looked magnificent against the backdrop of the valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_115659.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_115659_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed over on the other side of the ridge and were suddenly looking down into the main valley. The fairy chimneys visible in the second picture are the same ones, Marc, Mohamed and I saw during our first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_122122.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_122122_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_122739.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_122739_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way down into the valley the three of us almost fell into a 6-8m deep chasm. No big deal though. Also, it turned out that there was a perfectly safe crossing just a few meters to the side. We just hadn’t seen it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_123554.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_123554_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the fairy chimneys have a very characteristic shape. I will leave it to you to figure out what exactly the two gentlemen were doing here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_124612.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_124612_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_124452.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_124452_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_124008.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_124008_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Just something to dispell those rumors that I&#39;m making up these stories while playing video games in my mother&#39;s basement&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-castle&quot;&gt;The castle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having seen the valley, we headed back to town in time for lunch. Marc and I were both scheduled to leave Göreme in the evening, but that would leave us the afternoon to do some more exploring. We decided on taking a minibus up to the castle which loomed over Pidgeon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_144623.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_144623_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_144837.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_144837_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The castle itself turned out to be a bit of a let-down: From outside, it looked like a bee-hive and I was excited to see what remnamts of its occupation could be found inside. The answer: None. There was nothing there but a path up to the top. The view from up there compensated us though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_144918.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_144918_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_151118.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_151118_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_151356.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_151356_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking back down, we decided that we wanted to see the valley we had been looking down on. That was clearly one of the best decisions of my trip so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153009.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153009_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153439.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153439_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One entire side of the valley was lined with rocky peaks, one giant line of them which started with the castle hill itself. All along the steep rockface was a maze of houses, windows, half-eroded stairwells and scary-looking ledges. &lt;strong&gt;It. Was. Awesome.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153523.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153523_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153528.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153528_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153533.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153533_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three of us set out to explore, climbing higher and higher into the rocks. We even managed to climb into several of the empty rock-houses and have a look around inside. It is difficult to convey in writing, but the whole thing felt like a giant playground and I’m not ashamed to admit I felt like a kid. Including the confident risk affinity of somebody who has no understanding of even basic mechanics but very elastic bones…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a whale of a time in those ruins. Nothing was off-limits, nothing was roped off. We were free to climb everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_153852.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_153852_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_162044.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_162044_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_162153.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_162153_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we found a way out of the valley. As we couldn’t find a bus back, we hitchhiked the short distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.escapingsloth.com/pics/fullsize/IMG_20150502_163230.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Image&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot;http://escapingsloth.com/pics/IMG_20150502_163230_scaled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in Göreme, I said my goodbyes to Marc and Michal and got on my coach to Samsun. Yes, the one I had complained about previously, that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sidenote:&lt;/strong&gt; If you go to Turkey, try to make time for Cappadocia. Just like Pammukale, it’s a unique landscape and certainly worth seeing. Next time I go there, I will definitely do one of those balloon tours which are largely accident free, but were booked out for the days we were there. I would also bring a proper camera to take some nicer pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/06/goreme_iii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://escapingsloth.com/2015/05/06/goreme_iii/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
